First time giving blood?
Yes.
They pay cash here.
And there's no limit to how
many times you give.
They even buy it in the jar.
Jared Nomak, we're ready for you.
In the past 12 months,
have you gotten a tattoo...
...or undergone any ear,
skin, or body piercings?
No.
Where did you get that scar on your chin?
Childhood accident.
You say you don't have any immediate
next of kin, is that right?
Not that I'm in contact with.
- Nobody to call in case of an emergency?
- No one.
- No family?
- I told you, no.
Are you telling me I can't be a donor?
It depends. We came up with some
unusual results on your blood test.
What? How? How unusual?
Let me explain.
Your blood has a very rare phenotype,
one we haven't encountered before.
What? What are you talking about?
- Who are you? No. No.
- Sit down, please.
What is this?
This is a good news-bad
news scenario, Jared.
Good news for us.
Bad news...
...for you.
Forget what you think you know.
Vampires exist.
My name is Blade.
I was born half human, half vampire.
They call me The Daywalker.
I have all their strengths,
none of their weaknesses...
...except for the thirst.
Twenty years ago, I met
a man that changed that.
Whistler.
He taught me how to hold
the thirst at bay.
Taught me the rules.
Gave me the weapons to hunt with:
Silver, garlic, sunlight.
Two years ago, he was attacked.
They took him, and turned him
into the thing I hate most.
I should have finished him off.
Now I'm hunting him.
I will find him.
And nothing will stand in my way.
Daywalker's here! Stop him!
Where is he?
Hey!
No, no.
Take me to him, and I'll
consider you a loose end.
Catch you later.
Old man.
Look at what they've done to you.
Let's go home.
Lock up your daughters, boys and girls,
the dark knight returns.
- Need a toke of the smokage there, B?
- Later.
Cut the lights.
You found him.
You didn't kill him.
Give me a hand.
I got a bad feeling about this, B.
Unh! Listen to his breathing.
He's already dying.
He's in pain. Why don't you
just put him out of his misery?
They had him on stasis
in a halfway house.
I'm giving him an accelerated
retro-viral detox.
Like a heroin addict.
- Agh!
- Make him go cold turkey in one night.
Shit ain't gonna work, man.
I say you kill the motherfucker right now.
Get out.
If there's anything left of you
in there, Whistler, listen up.
In the morning, those blinds
are going to open...
...whether you're cured or not.
Hey, man, I didn't mean to call him...
Listen to me, Blade.
- You're gonna have to finish me off.
- No.
Give me that damn gun.
Now walk away.
Stubborn son of a bitch.
How do you feel?
Like hammered shit.
How'd you find me?
Started out in Moscow, then Romania.
- They kept moving you around.
- How long was I gone?
- Months?
- Too long.
Years.
They'd torture me almost to death...
...and then let me heal in a vat of blood...
...so they could go at it again.
Sorry sons of bitches could have at least
fixed my goddamn leg while they were at it.
Where's my arc welder?
Whistler, nice to meet you, man.
I heard a lot about you.
I'm Josh. You can call me Scud, though.
Everybody does.
Tell me something, Skid.
No, man, it's Scud. Scud, like "stud."
- Scud.
- Whatever. What did you do in here?
The pimpmobile? Just a little
after-market modification.
- Nitrous oxide and shit like that.
- Oh, yeah.
You gave it a more aggressive
exhaust profile ramping.
Whole package will crank that
Betty up maybe 300 horsepower.
You'll burn the damned thing out
before your next oil change.
Where did you dig up
this shitbird, anyway?
What the fuck is your problem, Poppy?
My problem is I've been sucking
blood clots for two years.
I get out to find some jerkoff
fucking with my life's work.
We jeopardized our operation
to save your ass.
- "Our operation"?
- Yeah.
"Our operation"?
I built this operation, you ass-wipe.
Motion sensors. It's on three, gentlemen.
Human?
Uh, body temperature, 50.
I'd guess suckhead.
Fried. They're using magnesium flares.
They've got your security
system scoped out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, I don't trust you...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Cool outfit.
Guard lights.
We represent the ruling body
of the Vampire Nation.
They're offering you a truce.
They want to meet with you.
Scud.
Take off your mask.
My name is Asad. This is Nyssa.
You have been our most feared enemy.
But now there's something
else loose on the streets.
Something worse than you.
What's so funny?
They tell stories about Blade
as the bogeyman.
Frankly, I'm disappointed.
You hear that, B? She's disappointed.
He agreed to come along so easily.
Come on, B, show her. Pretty please?
Semtex.
Enough explosives to level a city block.
You still disappointed?
The guards look human, B.
They're probably familiars.
You sure about this?
What if I'm not?
The true power of the Vampire
Nation lies here.
Father?
Blade, this is Overlord Eli Damaskinos.
It has been said, "Be proud of your
enemy and enjoy his success."
In that regard, I should thank you.
- For what?
- Eliminating Deacon Frost.
You did us a favor. Karel Kounen.
- You're human.
- Barely. I'm a lawyer.
European Health Consortium.
As you may know,
vampirism is a horrible virus...
...carried in the saliva of predators.
In 72 hours, it spreads through
the human bloodstream...
...creating new parasitic organs.
Like cancer.
Cancer with a purpose.
Unfortunately, viruses evolve too.
We've encountered a new one.
We dubbed it the Reaper strain.
And like any good pathogen,
it appears to have found a carrier.
There, Jared Nomak.
Born a vampire, but an anomaly like you.
Unlike the rest of us, however...
...he feeds on not just humans,
but vampires as well.
- Looks like he was doing me a favor.
- You're missing the point.
Their vampire victims don't die.
They turn. They become carriers.
You've got to understand.
These things are like crack addicts.
They need to feed daily.
Nomak's been up for 72 hours.
By our estimates, there are
already a dozen Reapers.
There'll be hundreds
before the week is out.
Thousands within a matter of months.
Do the math.
Wait, let me get this right.
You want me to hunt them for you?
When they are finished with us,
who do you think they'll turn on next?
Your precious humans.
Not one of them will be left.
We spent two years training a small
tactical unit, the Bloodpack.
We want you to lead them.
Two years?
We've been training to hunt you.
- So, B-man, what do you think?
- Sounds like a plan.
What do you really think?
They're gonna fuck us
the first chance they get.
We ain't gonna do this, though, right?
We'll play along for now.
They'll take us in deeper
than we've ever been.
Get a chance to see
how their world really ticks.
I had enough of their world.
They're just shitting bricks because
they're no longer top of the food chain.
Damn, man, I'm really worried about him.
Look, I know he's your friend and all,
but I think you should watch him.
Nobody goes cold turkey
from the thirst in just one night.
Looking to get hooked up?
Maybe. What do you have?
No problem. Horse, Hawaiian ice.
Whatever you need.
Whatever I need.
I like that. What if I need you?
So, so sweet.
They are ready whenever
you are, Daywalker.
Blade, meet the Bloodpack.
Lighthammer, Verlaine...
...Priest, Snowman...
...Chupa and Reinhardt.
Hey, uh.
Me and the gang were wondering...
What was that?
Can you blush?
Here we go, Poppy.
Oh, I get it.
I see now.
You've been training
for two years to take me out.
And now here I am.
Ooh.
Ooh, so exciting, isn't it?
Okay, here's your chance.
Come on. Come on,
what are you waiting for?
Here I am, right here in front of you.
Adolf here gets the first shot.
Come on. What are you looking at her for?
You need permission?
Maybe you need a little bit of incentive.
Okay, I can help with that.
What's the matter? Missed that?
It's okay, I can do it again.
Come on. What, you need a manual?
- Kill the bastard!
- Do it! Come on!
Now you've got an explosive device
stuck to the back of your head.
Silver nitrate, rigged to go off
if anybody tampers with it.
I'll have the detonator with me.
And you, if you so much
as look at me wrong...
Whoo.
From now on, we work as a unit.
You'll be taking orders from me.
Any questions?
Good.
You want to catch the hunter,
you start with the prey.
We'll target all the night places
where vampires congregate.
Blood banks, safe houses,
the bigger, the better.
So, what's first?
The House of Pain.
Where's the entrance?
I don't see any signs, no vampire glyphs.
No, because of you,
we've had to rethink our habits...
...tighten our security.
Have a closer look.
Nice.
Thirty-eight, .45 and 9mm caliber.
All with foil capsules at the tip filled
with silver nitrate and garlic extract.
This hyper-velocity stake gun spits out
a silver stake at 6000 feet per second.
Since you suckers don't like sunlight...
...we've modified the gun's
entry light with a UV filter.
Pop it open, instant UV light.
- Filter's on, no problem.
- Yo, B, check this out.
It's got a pneumatic
syringe delivery system.
The vials are filled with
an anticoagulant called EDTA.
One punch with this blows
your target up like a balloon.
The cartridge ejects. Automatic reload.
Nice.
Let's go.
You won't pass for one of us. No way.
- Like I give a shit.
- No, he's right.
Why don't you post up
on the roof over there?
Cover our backs.
So the Bloodpack's calling
the shots now, huh?
Great.
Better curb that dog of yours
or we'll do it for you.
Keep pushing, asshole.
We're in.
You're about to enter our world.
You will see things, feeding.
Just remember why you're here.
I haven't forgotten.
What exactly are we looking for in here?
Anything that looks suspicious.
You gotta be kidding me.
What y'all get it ain't haunted, call it
I see some of y'all thirsty for it
Straight frontin' y'all winnin' come down
To the combat, dog, I'm a workaholic
My swag touches every enemy
Within my clutches
Black makin' that ruckus
And I'm puttin' that lean on all you suckas
Black! Your bone crushes
Every opponent suffers
Your tone hushes from punches
Don't you like percussion?
Don't lose yo life for nothin'
You don't wanna try to touch 'em
No competition, listen
This ain't open for discussion
Ha, you want it, want it
Come on, you want it
Ha, come on, you want it, want it
Ha, you want it, come on
Scud, do you read me?
- You reading me?
- Reading you loud and clear, B.
The whole place is a safe house.
Windows are painted black,
one access door.
- Two, or 300 suckheads in here.
- That sounds cool.
Hey, W, you got me?
W?
Tell me something, how's the weather
up there, sweetheart?
Walking on sunshine, toad boy.
Look at them.
Half of these bastards,
they're not even purebloods.
I tell you what.
Why don't we just fucking kill everyone?
Just to make sure.
God, it would be so easy.
He's got you.
Fuck you.
Daywalker.
Mother's milk.
I say we got about half an hour
till sunrise, Cinderella. Hurry up.
I spotted one, but lost him.
Be on the lookout.
Fuck.
Whistler, man, they're on the roof.
On the roof of my bus.
Shh.
Nomak.
Daywalker.
What am I to you?
Is the enemy of my enemy
my friend or my enemy?
Aah!
We're under attack!
There's three of them. Probably more.
Daylight.
Silver don't do shit.
Don't waste the bullets.
- Motherfucker.
- You hear me, Chupa?
Say "cheese."
Come on.
How about some daylight, motherfucker?
Fuck!
Listen to me. If you're under attack, use
your UV lights. They can't take the light.
Priest?
We're not dying here, man. Come on.
Priest is down.
Daylight's coming.
You're on your own, Blade.
You want me so bad, Blade?
Here I am.
Why kill me?
You and I, we have the same enemy.
We want the same thing.
We need the same thing, Blade.
What happened?
Why didn't you tell me these
things were immune...
- ...to silver and garlic?
- I didn't know.
If you did, would you have told me?
I think you know the truth
when you hear it.
Then why didn't he kill you?
- How long since he's been bitten?
- About 20 minutes.
- His skin is fucking burning.
- He's already starting to change.
Will someone just shut him the fuck up?
Hold on!
- Hold him, Chupa!
- Come on, man.
Just put him out of his fucking misery.
Don't you get it?
You can't finish him that way.
Hold him down. Hold him down, Chupa.
Move.
Back off!
If that was your Bloodpack
Sunday punch, we're in trouble.
This motherfucker left his post.
- He just disappeared.
- Where were you?
Ran into a little Reaper action myself.
Oh, yeah? How little?
We lost a man, Priest.
You want me to carve his
fucking name on your chest?
Let me show you.
Saw it moving in the alley
and followed it down.
Found it just like this.
I think they came through here.
It was trying to crawl back
in the culvert and caught his arm.
Been gnawing at it like a coyote.
Little boy blue.
It's already dying.
I need to examine it
as quickly as possible.
Okay, look for a lever. Let's open it.
They've made contact with the Reapers.
- Any casualties?
- One so far.
It was not Nyssa, I trust?
No.
This a dangerous game
you're playing, Damaskinos.
Blade is too volatile.
You won't be able to keep
manipulating him.
You worry too much.
I've been informed by our friend inside
that events are unfolding as scripted.
You've already lost one of your own.
How many more are you
willing to sacrifice?
- Every one.
- Even your own daughter?
Yes, even her.
Recognize this?
The blood bank. He's one of the guards.
So why is he dying? What's killing him?
Time.
His metabolism is burning too fast.
They need fresh blood every couple of hours
or they'll start feeding on themselves.
Nomak's different. He's the carrier.
It all started with him, it'll end with him.
- Open the mouth, Scud.
- Heh.
Open the mouth.
B, man, come on.
Sissy.
Ugh. Gah.
Only the tongue carries the virus.
It is injected through these barbs.
It has bifurcated masseter muscles.
Overdeveloped, allowing
for a much stronger bite.
Jaw structure remains the same.
But there's no mandible bone.
Squeeze that tooth, Scud.
Neurotoxin.
Probably paralyzes their
victim while they feed.
Garlic don't work.
Silver, that don't work.
- We gotta go with the sunlight, right?
- That's deadly to us too.
So let's see what else we can find.
These things are as different
from us as we are from you.
Look at that.
The heart is encased in bone.
- Only the side is vulnerable.
- Good luck getting a stake through that.
Pull a leg off a spider,
it keeps moving on its own...
...essentially trying to walk
without a body attached to it.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Hardwired, right?
What the fuck is that?
Brain's dead. Body's still trying to feed.
We got six hours before sunrise.
Be ready by then.
Hey, what happens at sunrise?
Blade, I'm talking to you.
What happens at sunrise?
We hunt.
- In broad daylight?
- You gotta be fucking joking.
You better get you
some sunscreen, buttercup.
Listen, shitkicker.
You're about one cunt hair
away from hillbilly heaven.
I love it when you talk dirty.
Sunlight's the only edge we've got.
- They'll be more vulnerable then.
- And so will we.
Let's be real about one thing.
I don't expect everybody
to make it back tomorrow.
Remember to protect
yourselves at all times.
What are you looking for?
Phosphor rods. If I can
suss out the light source...
...maybe I can make some sort of UV
flash-bang grenade or something.
It's been tried already.
Yeah, but you didn't have the Scudster
working on it then, did you?
- Blade.
- Mm.
- The way you talk to them, us.
- What is it?
We are together in this, remember?
Why do you hate us so much?
It's fate.
- It's in my blood.
- Well, it's in mine too.
I'm a pureblood. I was born a vampire.
You know the thirst better than any of us,
shooting that serum of yours.
The only difference between us is that I made
peace with what I am a long time ago.
- How long have you known Blade?
- Going on 20 years.
He doesn't talk about
the old days that much.
Blade doesn't talk about anything much.
You want to hear something funny?
Blade kind of looks at you
like a father figure.
Tell me something.
How'd you two hook up?
I was backpacking.
I met these two chicks, decided
to take them back to my, uh, tent...
- ...for a little Three's Company action.
- Pretty.
Next thing I know, Janet and Chrissy
start tearing chunks out of my stomach.
Blade shows up, saves my ass.
Everything else just
sort of fell into place.
- Let's try it.
- All right.
Maybe I fucked up.
Maybe you were right.
All right. Papa's got a brand new bag.
Let me ask one question.
How the hell are we gonna
find these Reapers?
We won't have to. They'll come to us.
- What is this shit?
- Pheromones.
Harvested from the Reapers'
adrenal glands.
They're gonna key to it.
They want us to spray on
some suckpuppy's nut juice?
First use your firearms
to drive them back.
Then toss your UV grenades.
Right. This is what we got
for the grand finale.
I hot-wired a couple of these
babies to a nitro-vacuum.
Just be real careful where you
pop your load, all right?
And you, you're not coming?
No. I'm a lover, not a fighter.
UVs have a 10-second delay.
Nyssa, just remember to take cover.
Hey, Blade, give me a hand.
You and Miss Muffet getting
a little cozy there?
I wouldn't worry about that if I was you.
Looks to me like you're
getting confused...
...as to which side of the line
you're standing on.
Those are real hollow words
coming from a man...
...who just spent two years
running with the enemy.
And what the hell is that
supposed to mean?
You know, Whistler,
there's an old saying:
"Keep your friends close,
but keep your enemies closer."
You might want to remember that.
Blade, we should split into three units.
We're trying to attract them,
not scare them off.
Yeah, well, some of us can't see
in the dark, you fucking nipplehead.
What am I supposed to do?
Bifocals, Grandpa, and try to keep up.
Let's do this.
Hey, hillbilly.
What the fuck you doing?
Ain't nobody here but you
and us, buttercup.
We lose a partner, and Blade loses one!
I'll leave you two lovebirds
some time to yourselves.
Verlaine?
I spotted a group in the east tunnel.
I'm prepping the bomb pack.
Nyssa.
Get out!
Right now.
No!
I'll attract them to me.
Do what I tell you. Move!
Ten...
...nine...
...eight...
...seven...
...six...
...five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
...one.
Piece of junk.
What the hell is this?
You trying to stink me to death, old man?
Wait!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
We gotta move.
We got a lot of company.
All units, regroup. Regroup!
Eat shit, you ugly motherfuckers!
There's nobody left!
Aah! Unh.
- Where's the bomb pack?
- Had to leave it down that tunnel.
Give me the rest of the pheromones.
Go down that tunnel. Go, go, go!
You obviously do not know
who you are fucking with!
By the way, Blade, did I happen
to mention the bomb lever is stuck?
Suck this!
Let's go!
You want a bite of me? Well, come on!
Come on, motherfucker!
Whistler.
Wait.
You will survive this...
...only to tell Blade...
...about this ring.
About the truth. The truth, old man.
Damaskinos...
Nyssa.
You've done a great job.
Not that great, I'd say.
What is it, my daughter?
They took them. All our weapons.
Even your sword.
Somebody's been keeping
tabs on us from inside.
Where are we?
Some kind of chamber deep in their lair.
They smashed up everything,
the workshop, all of it.
They've been lying to us from day one.
The Reaper strain didn't evolve.
It was designed.
- What?
- Designed. Nomak told me.
I saw him back in the sewers.
He let me live.
Did he?
How generous of him.
I brought you here to see
the fruits of our labor.
For years I've struggled to rid our kind
of any hereditary weaknesses.
And so recombining DNA was
simply the next logical step.
Nomak was the first. A failure.
But in time, there will be
a new pure race...
...begotten from my own flesh...
...immune to silver...
...soon even sunlight.
I got a question for you,
you lying son of a bitch.
You want to explain how Nomak
got ahold of this ring?
I would have thought that was
obvious at this point.
I gave it to him, of course.
A gift from father to son.
I thought he'd never leave.
The wolf has lain with the sheep
long enough.
Reinhardt, you can kiss your ass goodbye.
Oh, huh. I'm sorry, man.
B, you're wasting your time, man.
The bomb's a dud.
It was never supposed to explode.
It was just supposed
to make you feel in control.
You thought you had me
on a short leash, didn't you, jefe?
Much better.
See this?
I'm one of Damaskinos' familiars.
They needed my help to bring
you here to control Nomak.
The old fuck, he was always just bait.
I mean, look at him.
He's your only real weakness, man.
You may be fast, you may be strong
and all that other bullshit...
...but in the end, B,
you're just too human.
Well, you little shit.
- Heh.
- Unh.
You think they scoped out
my security system?
I let them in, asshole!
I practically handed them the keys.
You heard Cue Ball, right?
Pretty soon they're all
gonna be daywalkers, man.
When that happens,
I'd rather be a pet than cattle.
You got me, B?
- What do you think about that, man?
- Two things.
One, I've been onto you
since they turned you.
And two...
...it's not a dud.
Oh, great.
I was just starting to like him.
Take him down!
We're going to harvest your blood,
every drop of it.
Then bone marrow, organs, everything.
We'll find the missing key
to creating daywalkers.
Now, this might hurt a bit.
Nice.
I wonder...
...how many vampires
he's killed with this thing.
Not nearly enough, Fritz.
Keep talking, honky-tonk.
Just makes my sending you
to the next world all the sweeter.
Been there, done that.
Do your worst, chickenshit.
We'll settle up after.
What else should I find out?
I trusted you...
...with my men...
...with my will...
...with my life.
You, you sent us out there.
You sent me to die.
Our enemy saved my life twice,
and you have used us...
...your own children.
Make no mistake, Nyssa.
Those blood ties mean nothing to me...
...when measured against
the ascendancy of our race.
Who do you think God
really favors in the web?
The spider or the fly?
- Nomak.
- Hmm?
What about him?
He wants revenge...
...on the people who created him.
You may be right.
But fortunately for us,
he doesn't know this location.
Now...
...he does.
What the fuck?
Come on, kid. Don't you even
think about dying on me.
You didn't give up on me,
I won't give up on you.
Come on, Blade.
Blood.
Yeah.
Father!
He'll never enter here.
Go on, kid.
Go!
Go! Get him!
Get in there!
Hmm.
Well, like my daddy said right
before he killed my mom:
"Want anything done right,
you gotta do it yourself."
He also said...
Can you blush?
Hey, kid.
I reset the security code.
- We're locked in.
- Are you insane?!
- He'll kill us both.
- Yes.
Isn't it sad that you die
not by the hand of your enemy...
...but by that of your own children?
Father.
Nyssa.
Nomak!
Blade, it could end right here.
What do you think, huh?
After all, it looks like I've
finished my father's job.
It's strange.
It hurts...
It hurts no more.
It won't be long.
I can already feel it
burning inside of me.
I want to die while I'm still a vampire.
I want to see the sun.
Go to booth number three. Enjoy, man.
Are you sure, uh,
that the girls are live?
- Last time I checked.
- Thank you.
A couple of razor blades, just in case.
Oh, you didn't think I forgot
about you, did you?