Good God.
Matthew.
They say your whole life flashes
before your eyes when you die.
And it's true, even for a blind man.
I grew up in Hell's Kitchen.
The politicians and the real-estate
developers call it Clinton now.
But a neighborhood,
like everything else, has a soul.
And souls don't change with a name.
Come on, shrimp, hit me.
I'll give you a free shot.
- Hit him again.
- You fight like your dad.
Come on, hit me.
- My dad's gonna be champ.
- Your dad's a bum.
- Yeah, a bum.
- Come on. Hit me.
- Yeah, he's a punk, man.
- Can't fight.
- Sure can run, though.
- Pathetic.
My father was a boxer.
A sportswriter once wrote
that he fought like the devil...
...and the name stuck.
Jack "The Devil" Murdock
was a contender.
But that was a long time ago.
Come on, Dad. Get up.
- Who won?
- Colan.
Yeah?
- I beat him, you know.
- I know, Dad. TKO.
That's right, Matty, you remember.
- Hey, hey, what's that?
- Nothing.
I told you I didn't want you fighting.
I tried to walk away, like you said,
but they kept giving me shit.
Don't curse.
What kind of shit?
They said that you work for Fallon.
That you're one of his guys now.
Get over here. Sit down. Come on.
Think I'd be pulling double overtime at
the docks if I was working for Fallon?
What are you, nuts?
You don't hit nothing but books.
Get me?
You be a doctor or a lawyer.
Not like me.
- Dad...
- Matt, you can do it.
You can do anything if you're not afraid.
Now, you promise me.
I promise, Dad.
Hey, guys, pull that line all the way in.
Then bring the crane around front,
all right?
Hey, kid. What, are you trying
to get yourself killed?
I'm looking for my dad, Jack Murdock.
Seen him around?
Murdock? No, he ain't worked here
in months.
- Now, beat it, huh?
- Come on, move it.
- Jack, I don't want you to hurt me.
- I will.
Jack, come on.
I had other obligations.
- Dad?
- Okay, I got it.
Matt?
Matt!
Matty, I...
- I talked to the doctor, and--
- I'm blind. I know.
How could you know?
I heard you talking in his office.
I hear everything.
Something's happened to me, Dad.
I don't know what it is.
I'm sorry, Matty.
I'm so sorry.
We made each other a silent promise...
...to never give up.
To be fearless.
To stick up for the long shots like us.
We were two fighters
on the comeback trail.
I had lost my sight,
but I got something back in return.
My remaining four senses functioned
with superhuman sharpness.
But most amazing of all, my sense of
sound gave off a kind of radar sense.
High above the roar of the streets,
I trained my body and my senses.
An acute sense of touch
gave me both strength and balance...
...until the city itself
became my playground.
I was the boy without fear.
Murdock!
Hey, Murdock! Round two.
- What's up, freak?
- Look at him, man. Look at his eyes.
- Kick his ass.
- Go ahead, fight me. I dare you.
- Yeah, Murdock.
- I dare you.
Yeah, that's what I'm saying, man.
Kick his ass.
Come on, man, let's just go.
Okay.
Jack, it's been a while.
- I don't work for you no more, Fallon.
- Jack, you never stopped.
Did you really think
you won those fights on your own?
You're 42 years old.
Miller, Mack, Bendis.
They're all my fighters.
Just like you.
And now it's your turn to take a fall.
Think about your boy, Jack.
I'm sure you'll do the right thing.
Matty.
No, come on, Dad! Come on, Dad,
get up! You can do it, Dad. Come on!
Come on, Dad. Get up! Come on!
Let's go! Come on! Come on, Dad!
Get up!
Never give up, remember?
Yeah, yeah! Come on, Dad. All right!
Yeah!
You all right? Murdock, you all right?
Okay, let's fight.
Down! He's out. Fight's over.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the winner, by way of knockout...
...Jack "The Devil" Murdock!
This one was for you, Matty.
I waited outside of the Olympic
for my father.
In some ways, I'm still waiting.
Finish him off.
Dad!
I can't see you, Dad.
I can't see you.
No one cared much about the death
of a washed-up prizefighter.
Nobody but me.
I would keep my promise.
I would help those that others wouldn't.
I would seek justice.
One way or another.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are here today to seek truth.
To seek justice.
Mr. Quesada,
would you state for the court...
...the sequence of events leading up
to the night of June 30?
I stopped off at Josie's Bar after work.
I had a few drinks.
Angela was there.
She was closing up.
She asked me if I wanted
to stick around for some fun.
Anything that happened after that
was entirely consensual.
Are you aware that perjury is a crime,
Mr. Quesada?
Objection. My client's a respectable
member of the community.
- Miss Sutton has a history of drug--
- My client's not on trial.
- Her testimony is suspect--
- Nor is her testimony suspect.
Gentlemen, that's enough.
The truth is, Mr. Murdock,
is that Miss Sutton...
Miss Sutton enjoyed every minute of it.
Mr. Quesada, for your sake,
I hope justice is found here today...
...before justice finds you.
Matt? Matt, where you going?
We knew this was a risk going in.
Why? She's from the Kitchen?
She's not from the Upper East Side?
Yeah. Come on, man,
she has a history of drug abuse.
That was a long time ago.
I know, but juries don't like their victims
to be flawed. You know that.
- It's not right.
- Yeah?
Here's what I don't get.
How can a scumbag like Quesada
afford an attorney like Hirsh?
He can't.
The Kingpin's gotta be footing the bill.
- Come on, let's go get drunk.
- Not tonight.
I got work to do.
Line them up, Josie.
I'm ready to party tonight.
Got a lot of nerve coming in here
after what you did.
Didn't you hear? I'm innocent, baby.
Bikes behind the cage!
No burnout, you assholes!
- Right here.
- Hey.
- What's up?
- You gotta take that.
- Big neck, come on.
- I can't believe--
What was her name?
To the justice system, right?
Of course I beat it.
Kingpin's got my back, bro.
How you doing, sweetie?
- Boss?
- What's up?
- What's up with that?
- Is that guy for real?
Yeah, he's for real.
- What do you want?
- Justice.
Quesada!
Time to give the devil his due.
Oh, God. Oh, God!
- Hey. How you doing?
- Didn't you hear?
- I was acquitted.
- Not by me.
Who made you judge?
You did.
Go to hell...
...diablo.
Okay. But you'll beat me there.
Hey, that light
at the end of the tunnel?
- Guess what. That's not heaven.
- I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
- That's the C train.
- I'll kill you! Oh, God!
Hey, you can't go past there.
- Call Charlie.
- Right.
You're wasting your time, Urich.
There's nothing to see here.
Jose Quesada.
And the rest of Jose Quesada.
- Whole lot of nothing, huh?
- Keep running those stories...
...and we'll end up with copycat
vigilantes who'll get themselves killed.
Are you here to confirm that Daredevil
is responsible for this, detective?
Come on, Urich. Stop busting my--
There is no proof that your
so-called Daredevil was involved...
...nor that he even exists. Got it?
Got it.
Can one man make a difference?
There are days when I believe.
And others when I have lost all faith.
Matt, it's Heather. Are you there?
Of course you're not there.
You're never there.
At least, not for me.
Look, I didn't wanna do this
over the phone...
...but it's not like you've given me
any choice.
I mean, it's been three months now,
and I've never even seen your apartment.
Every time we sleep together,
I wake up in the morning alone.
I mean, Jesus, where do you go
at 3:00 in the morning?
I thought that if I waited,
if I was patient enough, you'd let me in.
That we'd take our relationship
to the next level.
Then I realized
that this is the next level.
Goodbye, Matt.
I hope you find what you're looking for.
Please don't hurt me!
Please don't shoot!
I didn't do anything wrong!
Sleep now.
"Eyewitnesses say Quesada
was singled out...
...by the demonic vigilante
known as the Daredevil."
- I don't know why you read that trash.
- There's gotta be something to it.
- Like the alligators in the sewers?
- There are alligators in the sewers.
- A friend in sanitation has seen them.
- Fine. Just drop it.
You should see this guy.
They got this picture.
- They have a picture?
- It's a drawing, an artist's rendering.
It's just-- It's grotesque.
I'd hate to see his therapy bills.
Speaking of bills...
...your client, Mr. Lee,
made his first payment.
- Great. You should be very happy.
- Yeah, it's fantastic. He paid in fluke.
Fluke is a fish, Matt.
Did you know that? I didn't.
Mr. Lee is a good man
and doesn't have much money...
...and he fishes on weekends.
I guess it's--
I salsa dance on weekends, but I don't
shake my ass to pay my phone bill.
Will you pass the honey, please?
We need better clients.
I'm tired of pro Bono cases.
What is your problem with our clients?
We have good, honorable clients.
What's your idea of better?
Define "better."
- What would be a better client?
- Better means rich and guilty, okay?
Law school taught us
to create a moral vacuum...
...so you can represent people
who aren't innocent.
- That was your best course, as I recall.
- You don't have a moral vacuum.
You are completely vacuum-less.
- What happened to your face?
- Nothing.
It's a small cut. I walked into a door.
Matt, every time you disappear, we can't
get ahold of you, you come in all cut up.
I'm in the Fight Club.
It's the first rule of Fight Club.
Don't talk about Fight Club.
So you're not in the Fight Club.
Didn't see the movie.
I'm sure it's a funny joke,
but I didn't see it.
Okay? All I'm saying is
I'm here for you as a friend.
I mean, I spent $3000
on that Seeing Eye dog.
I didn't ask for it.
I didn't want it.
Can I tell you something else?
Seeing Eye dogs bond for life.
Yours ran away. What does that tell you
about how emotionally available you are?
- What? What? Where? Where? Where?
- Front door. Not yet, soon.
Now.
Tell me.
- You want the truth?
- Absolutely.
She's hideous.
I don't know if it's a fungus
or some congenital birth defect...
...but as your attorney in this matter,
I advise you to take no further action.
- I'm sorry. Excuse me.
- Sure.
I was looking for some honey.
Could you help me out?
Right in front of you.
Well, could you be
a little bit more specific?
- What, are you--?
- Blind? Yeah.
- I am so sorry.
- That's okay.
- Friend of yours?
- You know, I've never seen him before.
Matt Murdock.
- Nice to meet you, Matt Murdock.
- Nice to meet you.
I didn't get your name.
I didn't give it.
Some people have no compassion
for the handicapped.
Apparently not.
- Where you going?
- I'm gonna file an appeal.
We have to be in court by noon.
- 12:00, Matt.
- I'll be there.
What do you want?
I just wanted to get your name.
I didn't want trouble.
Look...
...I don't like being followed. So don't.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a second. Take it easy.
I don't like being touched.
Why don't you tell me what you do like
and we'll start there?
Sure you're blind?
Sure you don't wanna
tell me your name?
- You're holding back.
- Yes.
Don't.
Does every guy have to go through this
to find out your name?
You should try asking for my number.
- Fight!
- Fight! Fight! Fight!
Stop hitting me.
Okay.
My name's Elektra Natchios.
Thanks. That's all I wanted to know.
I have to go.
Go? Wait a second. Hold on.
I don't wanna get my ass kicked again.
I just wanna know why you have to go.
My bodyguard is here.
Your bodyguard?
If you need a bodyguard,
I'm in serious trouble.
I thought I lost him at the coffee shop.
Dad can be a little overprotective.
Oh, Natchios. Right.
As in Nikolaos Natchios.
That's Dad.
How am I gonna find you?
You won't.
I'll find you.
- What's wrong, Wesley?
- Have you seen the papers today?
Somebody's been talking.
Somebody always does.
Wesley, did you know,
back in ancient times...
...they would cut the tongues
out of their bodyguards...
...their first day on the job?
You think that's horrible, don't you?
Because you don't like the physical stuff.
I do.
Wesley, handkerchief.
Your 11:00 is here.
Natchios, my dear old friend.
I'm getting out, Wilson.
I am out.
You think it's funny?
They're writing about the Kingpin.
They're going back to the beginning.
Well, I'm tired of looking
over my shoulder.
I wanna put all that behind me now.
I want you to buy me out.
I think you'll find
it's a very generous offer.
So, what do you say?
How's your daughter?
- I said I was sorry. What do you want?
- Details. You owe me that.
Her name's Elektra Natchios.
She sounds like a Mexican appetizer.
It's Greek, genius.
Her father's Nikolaos Natchios.
- The billionaire?
- Yeah, see. Yes, the billionaire.
As your attorney, I advise you
to marry her immediately.
I'll take it under consideration.
- What do we got?
- Oh, this one's a real winner.
Dante Jackson, ex-con from Queens...
...charged with the murder
of Lisa Tazio...
...your friendly neighborhood prostitute.
Bad news is Jackson was found...
...passed out in an alley
holding the murder weapon...
...and enough THC in his lungs
to get Staten Island high.
Jackson can't remember what
happened that night...
...or for that matter, most of the '90s.
- What's the good news?
- The fluke wasn't bad.
Can you let us in, please?
Mr. Jackson.
Who are you?
We're your attorneys...
...if you're innocent.
So are you?
Innocent?
Yeah.
Hell, yeah.
I believe you.
You do?
You got yourself a defense.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
I want you to create a paper trail.
One that can be traced to Natchios.
- Sir?
- The press want a Kingpin...
...so I'll give them a Kingpin.
Get me Bullseye.
Two out of three.
Bloody Irish piece of trash.
What do you think Jackson's
gonna pay us with? Chronic?
The guy's a three-time loser, he was
a block away with the murder weapon.
It makes the fact
that he's innocent interesting.
- How are you sure?
- Have I ever been wrong?
No, which is really starting to annoy me.
Hey, come on, I got a blind guy here.
Well, use the crosswalk, asshole.
I love this city.
Empty your pockets.
Raise your arms.
All right, so this is it. Okay, now what?
Take a look around.
Look, Matt, I know you got
this built-in bullshit detector...
...but this time it's on the blink.
Let's just say...
- ...Jackson is innocent.
- He is.
Why go through the trouble
of setting him up?
Why the big cover-up in the death
of a prostitute?
I don't know. I can't answer that.
I gotta find out more about Lisa Tazio.
Well, you know,
too bad we don't have a key.
Matt? Matt, where you going?
Give me your pen.
To leave a note?
- Here.
- That was my pen.
Must have been sick the day they
taught that. Is that real estate law?
- What do you see?
- What do I see?
I see high ceilings.
I see hardwood floors under carpet.
I see some good Feng Shui.
Think they rented this place yet?
What, she have a puppy?
- Ammonia.
- So what?
Over blood.
Something else.
Cordite.
Gunpowder.
She was shot here and dragged outside
to make it look like a random robbery.
Come on, Matt, there's nothing
over there. Let's go.
Write this down.
She wrote something here in a
ballpoint pen. The imprint is in the wood.
- M.
- O.
- Six.
- Eight.
I knew it. Her mother did it.
Now, can we please go
before we need attorneys too?
Susie is my son Larry's daughter
by his first marriage.
She eloped with this
semi-colored fella from London.
What's the word for that? Mulatto.
Just let's say he had
a little cream in his coffee.
But he did very well
for himself on the Internet.
But don't ask me how. No.
You know, they did get me a computer
for Christmas last year...
...but I refuse. I'm afraid
it's going to explode.
But who can afford to fly these days?
But then my sister Marjorie called and
said she had these frequent-flier miles...
...and she couldn't use them
because of her sciatic nerve.
So I said--
She's sleeping. Can I get you
anything before we land?
More peanuts, please.
I'm here at the Manhattan Courthouse
where accused killer Dante Jackson...
--accused of gunning down prostitute...
- As you can see...
- Dante Jackson.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury...
...I am not here to convince you
that Dante Jackson is a model citizen.
He has been in and out of prisons and
reform schools since 12 years of age.
But this is not a court of character,
however.
This is a court of law.
Isn't he facing the wrong way?
Don't worry. He's got them
right where he wants them.
Yeah.
And that is what it's been like
for Mr. Jackson.
Like trying to talk to a wall.
Does this defense come with
a two-drink minimum, Mr. Murdock?
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
I'm just trying to make a point.
You see, justice is blind,
but it can be heard.
And today, the truth will come out.
Thank you.
Here, right this way.
He's blind. He can't see anything.
Okay, here's the arm.
You got the arm there, Matt.
Just reach down. There you go.
I'm sorry.
Here we go. Right there.
You got it? Okay.
- What, you think too much?
- Yeah, it was a little much.
You always wanna do the chair thing,
and that's embarrassing.
People want sympathy.
It's not The Gong Show.
Officer Mackenzie, you were
the arriving officer at the scene, right?
That's correct.
Please, tell us what you observed.
I was a block away when I got the call
of shots being fired.
When I arrived on the scene,
Lisa Tazio's body...
...was lying dead on the steps
of her apartment.
I found Jackson passed out in the alley...
...still holding the murder weapon...
- What's wrong?
- ...Tazio's wallet in his pocket.
Mackenzie's telling the truth.
Yeah, that happens sometimes in court.
No, no, no. Somebody has to be lying.
What's he doing here?
Who?
It's Ben Urich.
He's the reporter from the Post.
So does this mean you want a rematch?
I told you I'd find you.
How did you know I wasn't a mugger?
Muggers don't usually wear
rose oil or high heels.
At least, this far from Chelsea.
Come here.
There's something I wanna show you.
Wait a second.
Exactly how many women
have you brought up here, anyway?
You're my first.
- Good answer.
- I thought that was the right answer.
Look at this.
It's so beautiful.
I know. This was my favorite view
of the city when I was a kid.
I really wanted you to see this.
What's this?
Oh, that's from my mother.
- For good luck.
- It's beautiful.
It's a good-luck charm, huh?
I could use one of those.
Do they make them in Braille?
She gave it to me right before she died.
What happened?
She was killed.
Right in front of me. I was 5.
I'm sorry.
No Greek tragedies, okay?
Okay.
- I should go.
- No. Just wait.
- No, I'm gonna go--
- Wait, wait, wait. It's about to rain.
- No, it's not.
- It is. I'm telling you, it's--
The temperature dropped two or
three degrees. I can smell the moisture.
And when it rains, it's like
there's a rooftop on the world.
Each raindrop makes a sound
the first time it falls on a surface.
Just then, it's like I...
It's like I can see again.
And I just wanna...
I just wanna see you.
Okay.
Look, here it comes.
My God.
You are so beautiful.
Remember me?
Maybe you remember the Kingpin.
- You remember me now?
- What?
- Matt, what's wrong?
- What are you, stupid?
You think you can hold out
on the Kingpin, huh?
Matt.
I have to go. I'm sorry.
I have to go.
Matt. Matt.
No, no, no. No, no, please.
You remember me now?
What are you, stupid? You think you
can hold out on the Kingpin, huh?
Get away from me!
Stay out of Hell's Kitchen.
This ain't your neighborhood no more.
Kitchen belongs to the Kingpin now.
Please.
Please don't hurt me.
I'm not the bad guy, kid.
I'm not the bad guy.
I'm not.
You know the great strength
of the Church?
Its sense of community.
- Good morning, Father.
- Good morning.
Now, this may come as a bit
of a surprise to you, Matthew...
...but we are open on Sundays.
I like the quiet.
I don't think so, son.
I think you like the solitude.
And you find it in here,
do you, Matthew?
Sometimes.
Sometimes not.
You don't have to go it alone, Matthew.
My confessional is open to you
all the time.
There's no keeping secrets
from God, son.
Spend 30 years in one of them little
boxes, there's nothing I haven't heard.
Well, let's keep it that way.
So we'll be seeing you Sunday,
then, huh?
Oh, okay. I have to call you back,
because he just came in.
Good morning.
Your ears must've been burning.
- Why?
- This just came by messenger.
It's your invitation to the Black
and White Ball at the Grand. Plus one.
Plus one. All right.
- Coffee?
- No. No, thank you.
I'd love a cup, Karen. Thank you.
Guess she's making a fresh pot.
Wow, they spent some serious money
on this invitation.
I mean, you should feel it. It's engraved.
- What time are you gonna pick me up?
- I'm not going.
What? Are you crazy?
That place is gonna be crawling
with people. Rich people.
People who pay their legal fees
with money, not with fish...
...or with wheels of cheese
or with sports supplies.
I'll fill you in on a little secret.
This place doesn't look like a law office.
It looks like the set of Sanford and Son.
Every time I walk in, I'm waiting
for Lamont to walk down the stairs.
- Then you go.
- Look at me, Matt. I'm a plus-one.
Plus-ones don't get anywhere alone.
They need somebody to bring them.
Are you finished? We only have
an hour to prepare for court.
What's eating you?
Rough night.
Well, you wanna talk about it?
No.
It's about Elektra, isn't it?
And Natchios owns the Grand Hotel...
...and Elektra's the reason
you were invited to the ball.
She's out of my league
and I'd rather just end it before it starts.
That's gotta be some kind of record.
You just completely bypassed the whole
relationship phase, right into the breakup.
Trying to save some time, huh?
What happens to that lie detector
when it detects your own bullshit?
Must really bury the needle, huh?
Swish.
Look, Matt, seriously,
the ball's in your court.
Plus one, huh?
Thank you.
This is what I'm talking about.
Aren't you happy you listened to me?
This is gonna be great
for business, Matt.
Thank you.
Matt Murdock. Ben Urich,
New York Post.
Ben Urich, nice to meet you.
You write the articles
about urban legends, right?
Well, yes, among other things.
Settle something for us. You know
the alligators in the sewers? My partner--
I followed that piece
you wrote about the Kingpin.
One man running all the crime in New
York City sounds a little far-fetched.
Yeah, but then again, so does a vigilante
who thinks every day is Halloween.
They gotta be huge by now,
right, the alligators?
It's a myth.
Look, I'd like you to give me a call--
Sorry.
Cool color.
I wouldn't know.
Yeah, but do give me a call. There is
something I'd like to talk to you about.
Nice to meet you. Enjoy the party.
Look at that.
Wilson Fisk is in the hizzey.
We might never get a chance
like this again. Come on, let's go.
- We should talk about this.
- Mr. Fisk. Hi.
It's Franklin Nelson
from Nelson & Murdock--
Hey, yeah, you wanna talk to Mr. Fisk,
you make an appointment.
- Okay?
- Wesley. I know who you are.
You're the blind lawyers
from Hell's Kitchen.
Right. Actually, he's the blind one.
I'm deaf.
Give them a card, Wesley.
I'm always on the lookout
for new blood.
I'm sorry, Mr. Fisk.
My partner's a little overzealous.
We can't represent you.
And why is that?
Yes, why is that, Mr. Murdock?
Because we only handle
clients who are innocent.
"Innocent," he said. He's pretty funny.
I've learned one thing
in my years in this business.
What's that?
Nobody's innocent.
Nobody.
- Have a great time at the party.
- Thank you.
I just-- You know, Matt,
for one night, I just wish...
I just...
Matt, I just wish I could
give you my eyes for one night.
- It's like that?
- It's like that.
You want me to take you
up there, Matt? Matt?
Matt?
Now I found you.
Look, I'm really sorry
about the other night.
You're here now.
That's all that matters.
Wow, engraved cuff links, huh?
- Because it's Wesley Owen Welch--
- Let me cut to the chase.
If this were up to me, and it is...
...do you really think
that this corporation would hire...
...some pro Bono, storefront Hell's
Kitchen lawyers, let alone a blind one?
Come on. I've already filled our quota
of handicapped employees for the year.
Go back to the Kitchen, Franklin Nelson.
That dick.
You look beautiful tonight.
Do you mind?
No, I just-- Sometimes it makes
people uncomfortable, that's all.
Not me.
But you should know...
...that the only reason
I got dressed up for this thing...
...was that I wanted
to look beautiful for you.
I wish you could see me tonight.
Me too.
Matt.
What's wrong?
It's just...
...good things don't happen
to me very often.
When they do, I get scared.
Nothing bad is gonna happen. I promise.
Hi.
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Doesn't she look beautiful?
I think she's happy.
I haven't seen her smile like that
since before her mother was killed.
Poor girl. Right in front of her eyes.
What, you have to bring that up now?
History has a way of repeating itself.
- What are you saying?
- Just saying goodbye, old friend.
Just saying goodbye.
- Something's happening.
- What is it?
Papa!
Go back to the party.
What's wrong?
Elektra!
Stavros will take you home.
Papa. Papa.
Tell me where you're going.
You wait.
I'm sorry.
- What is going on?
- New York is not a safe place tonight.
That's all you need to know.
Watch out!
I missed. I never miss.
Drop something?
Bullseye.
Daddy.
Get that over to Forensics right away.
Hey, Nick.
What do you want, Urich?
Does all this make you happy?
Looks like you got your story.
Police are still investigating the murder
of Nikolaos Natchios--
--will identify Natchios
as the so-called Kingpin.
--believes that the self-styled
vigilante is wanted for murder.
--implication of Daredevil.
How did you get past my security?
Oh, you mean that guy?
Was that really necessary?
Necessary? No, it was fun.
You know, you've exceeded
all my expectations.
You even managed to implicate Daredevil
in the process. You should be pleased.
He...
...made me...
...miss.
There's an old saying that
too much pride can kill a man.
The devil is mine.
Really?
I've heard that before, all too
many times. But answer me this:
How do you kill a man without fear?
By putting the fear in him.
I like that. But first...
...give Elektra all my best.
Is there anything else?
Yeah.
I want a fucking costume.
And what happened from there,
Mr. Jackson?
Oh, well, let's see...
Man, I was so high,
I can't remember everything.
Excuse me one second, Your Honor,
I'm working alone here today.
Just a second.
It's Braille. It's Braille.
It says here-- Okay, Mr. Jackson,
it says here that you were...
...at Chumley's...
Chumley's Tavern until 10:15...
...and then you went to meet a friend.
Terp. That's right, I went to meet Terp
because he owed me some money.
Yes! And it was there that you passed
out from drinking. Is that correct?
Smoking weed, mostly.
Thank you for clarifying that.
Now, Officer Mackenzie has testified...
...you were found
at that time holding a handgun.
- That's a lie.
- In fact, you don't own a handgun...
- ...do you?
- No, sir.
- Have you ever owned a handgun?
Do you have any intention
of owning a handgun?
- No, sir.
- Thank you.
Can't hit nothing with a handgun.
- But a shotgun...
...now that's a whole different story.
Shotgun got buckshot.
- That's all.
- When you shoot it...
...they spray out.
So it can hit everything in front of it.
Thank you, Mr. Jackson.
I have no further questions, Your Honor.
Court's in recess.
Mr. Nelson.
For your sake, I hope your partner
comes back soon.
Me too. Me too.
- I know how you feel.
- You don't know how I feel.
I want revenge.
Revenge won't make the pain go away.
Trust me. I know.
There's no place for me now.
Yes, there is.
Stay.
Stay with me.
Please.
Elektra.
Elektra, wait.
Please.
Drive.
Matt.
Why are you following me?
- It's me, Ben Urich.
- Yeah, I know who it is.
What do you want?
Your client's innocent.
Well?
I have a source for my Kingpin story...
...named Lisa Tazio.
Lisa Tazio had access to the Kingpin?
No. One of his guys. Pillow talk.
She was selling me information
bit by bit. I never got a name.
Will you testify to that?
First Amendment and all that. Plus, the
case is still open, far as I'm concerned.
Can you tell me anything
that could help?
Yeah. I got a cousin over in Hoboken,
runs a Mercedes dealership.
He sold a 500 SL to a Robert Mackenzie.
Officer Mackenzie. Doesn't make sense.
He was telling the truth.
Matt...
...that's three years' cop salary.
Guy ain't telling the truth.
Could've bought him a future.
Our future.
Our children.
Gotta love that new-car smell,
huh, Mackenzie?
Murdock, what the--?
Never driven a stick shift.
How does this work?
- Stop it!
- Take it easy, Mackenzie.
We'll go for a ride. Nice car.
Where'd you get it?
- Lots of cops got Mercedes these days.
- Yeah.
I'll bet.
Jesus Christ!
- You're crazy!
- Yeah, I'm crazy.
- Who killed Lisa Tazio?
- Dante Jackson.
Stop the goddamn car!
See, here's the hard part,
parallel parking.
How is it, like this?
What do you want?
I wanna know why your goddamn
heart rate hasn't changed.
- When'd you get the pacemaker?
- Three years ago. So what?
You lied in court. That's perjury.
You think I'm the only one?
You take me down, there's 100 more
just like me to take my place.
This is bigger than you, Murdock.
It's bigger than all of us.
The Kingpin.
He runs the whole goddamn town.
You cross him, you're gonna end up
like Natchios.
Eighty-sixed by some maniac
like Bullseye.
And he won't stop there.
- What does that mean?
- Kingpin doesn't just kill you.
He kills your whole family.
I have coffee.
Did you get ahold of Matt?
No. He'll call. Don't worry.
You should really get home, Karen.
I'm fine. How are you doing?
Oh, me? I'm great.
I'm making ridiculously little progress...
...for the amount of time
I've invested in this.
- Is your mom coming to town?
- My mom? No.
- What's that note?
- Oh, that?
That's Matt's big contribution
to the Tazio case...
...which has surprisingly turned out
to be completely useless.
What's the date of the murder?
August 9th. Why?
Maybe you're looking at it wrong.
August 9th.
August 9th, wow.
"Wesley Owen Welch."
Son of a bitch.
Oh, cha-ching.
This better be good, Kirby.
You know me, Urich.
It's always good. Come here.
Okay. Are you ready to see
something really, really cool?
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Come on, man. I'm throwing you gold.
- Give me my money.
- Why?
- I've seen it. Come on.
All right, well...
But have you seen this?
And tighty righty, loosey left--
You said to look out
for anything weird, yes?
That's some pretty weird shit
right here, man, right?
You have no idea.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, this is Franklin Nelson.
This is not a good time.
It's about Lisa Tazio.
Remember me?
Wait!
It wasn't me.
Stop!
It was a hit man named Bullseye.
- I didn't kill your father.
- Liar.
- I'm not gonna fight you.
- Good.
Then this will be quick.
I wanna look into the eyes
of my father's killer as he dies.
Wait. Wait.
Now you know.
Oh, God.
I was just trying to protect you, Elektra.
- I'm sorry.
- Elektra.
That's him. That's Bullseye.
Listen to me. You have to run.
- He has to pay for what he's done.
- No, you don't understand.
I don't wanna lose you again.
I'll find you.
Come on, girl.
Hey, orphan. Let's play.
Nice. Come on.
You're good, baby. I'll give you that.
But me...
...I'm magic.
And now for my next trick.
No! No!
N.Y.P.D. Aviation.
Please do not move.
Get on your knees
and put your hands on your head.
I repeat, get on your knees
Help me.
Stay. Just stay with me.
Everything's clear.
Matthew. Matthew.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
This is my confession, Father.
God's mercy is infinite.
All you gotta do is ask.
Everything I had
has been taken from me.
Now I'm supposed to ask for mercy?
I don't ask for mercy. People ask me.
Oh, is that a fact?
First one's a warning...
...Padre.
- Is there a back door out of here?
- Yeah.
- Take it. Call the police.
- What about you?
- I have to finish this.
- You can't fight like this.
Have faith, Father. Isn't that right?
You.
Let's play.
Kane, I want the blueprints and
the city grids. Secure the perimeter.
- Yes, sir.
- Where the hell's my SWAT team?
- Doors are locked from the inside, sir.
- Break them down.
- It's a church, sir.
- Your point?
Yes, sir. Let's get a battering ram
in here now.
You got it.
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go. Go, go, go.
- Hey, Coyle. Keep them in your sights.
- Which one?
Both of them.
I want a man on that roof.
Ready?
The man without fear. Looks like
I found something you're afraid of.
Let's bring on the pain.
Let's bring on the noise.
Fisk was right about you.
He said you wouldn't go easy.
Fisk? Fisk is the Kingpin?
Yeah.
The whole red rose thing,
he loves that shit. It's not my style.
He hired me to kill Natchios.
And to gut your pretty girlfriend too.
But me, I'm going for the hat trick.
I told him I'd do you for free.
The devil is mine.
Oh, my hands! My hands.
You took away my hands.
Show mercy?
Bull's-eye.
- Freeze!
- Don't move!
Detective, look!
Good luck, son.
There's been a problem.
Bullseye failed.
Correct.
Then he'll be coming here next.
Why would you say that?
Because that's what I would do.
Well, then we'll be ready for him, sir.
Send the guards home.
- But, sir--
- I was raised in the Bronx, Wesley.
This is something
you wouldn't understand.
Yes, sir.
- I have to talk to you.
- Give me a break, Urich.
- Doors are open, detective.
- Terrific. Just in time.
- Keep those people back!
- You're gonna wanna hear this.
I just got an anonymous tip
on the Tazio murder.
Phone it in.
I got much bigger problems tonight.
It leads to Wilson Fisk.
Nick, he's the Kingpin,
and I can prove it.
Come on, you got nothing on Fisk.
No. But I got the guy that does.
- Would you care for another martini, sir?
- No, I come here for the view, asshole.
Wesley Owen Welch?
Who wants to know?
Detective Nick Manolis. I'd like to talk
to you about the murder of Lisa Tazio.
- I want my lawyer.
- I haven't charged you with anything.
I won't talk to you
without my lawyer present.
All right. Then I'll talk. You listen.
And then we can talk
about your plea bargain.
Check.
Daredevil.
Kingpin.
It's a shame you came here wounded.
I would have loved to fight you
in your prime.
They call you the man without fear.
If that's true, why are you afraid
to show your face?
I don't believe it.
No. No.
The blind lawyer from Hell's Kitchen?
You killed the only two people
I ever loved.
Why?
Business.
That's all it ever is, business.
I was working for Fallon at the time.
Your father was supposed
to throw a fight...
...and your girl was in the wrong family
at the wrong time.
It's always business.
I'll find you.
You've been in my business
for too long.
I've been thinking about this day
since I was 12 years old.
I don't understand.
I'm not the bad guy.
You hear that, blind man?
The sirens.
They're coming for you.
For me?
Didn't you hear?
The word's out on the Kingpin.
They're coming for you.
I can hear the police radios from here.
No, no.
I swear I'll tell them who you are.
Yeah? Go ahead, tell them.
Tell the guys at Riker's all about
how you got beat by a blind man.
It'll be like blood in the water.
Don't worry about that,
because I'll get out.
Yeah, I know.
And I'll be waiting.
Justice is served.
I'll get you.
It's not over with yet.
Not over with Daredevil.
This is for you, Dad.
Congratulations.
Thank you, Mr. Murdock.
I appreciate everything.
- Yeah, seriously, congratulations.
- You the man, though.
All right, yeah. Keep it real.
All right.
I appreciate everything, man.
I'm feeling you, man.
If you ever need anything, you come
down to 117th Street, you ask for me.
- So great. So great.
- That's it, dog.
Stuck by me. Nobody wanted
to touch me with a 20,000-foot pole.
- I feel you.
- I appreciate that, man.
I could cry right now.
You like a brother to me.
You know what I'm saying?
"Though there were no witnesses, police
think Daredevil brought Fisk to justice."
There were no eyewitnesses.
It's in black and white.
How can you be a skeptic?
If there's no eyewitnesses--
Bigfoot has eyewitnesses.
- Please.
- The alligators in the sewers--
So there are alligators in the sewers?
I didn't admit that. I'm explaining--
Do you concede that there are
alligators in the sewers?
- Do I concede that? No.
- Answer the question.
How can you not concede? You--
Judy, we're over here.
How you doing?
I'm doing okay. I'll be all right.
You wanna talk about it?
No, but thanks.
- I'm gonna get some air.
- I got this.
Thanks.
Good to see you.
And you too. How are you?
Nice to see you.
- Thank you so much.
- Bye, now.
See you next week. Okay.
Maybe next week, Matt, huh?
Maybe.
Matt.
Ben.
Promised my kids I'd quit.
Gum's gonna kill me quicker.
How are you?
I'm all right. I'm good. Thank you.
Well, don't thank me so quick.
See, there's this other story
I've been working on.
I wanted to tell you about it
before it hit the paper.
I know the truth about Daredevil.
Justice is blind.
Ben, if you run that story...
...I'm finished.
But I'm a reporter, kid.
It's what I do.
Violence doesn't discriminate.
It hits all of us.
The rich, the poor, the healthy, the sick.
It comes as cold and bracing
as a winter breeze off the Hudson...
...until it sinks into your bones...
...leaving you with a chill
you can't shake.
They say there's no rest for the wicked.
But what about the good?
The battle of good versus evil
is never-ending...
...because evil always survives...
Bull's-eye.
...with the help of evil men.
Braille.
As for Daredevil, well...
Soon the world will know the truth:
That this is a city born of heroes.
That one man can make a difference.
Go get them, Matt.
Hell's Kitchen is my neighborhood.
I prowl the rooftops and alleyways
at night...
...watching from the darkness.
Forever in darkness...
...a guardian devil.