Ever since I was three...
I wanted to play quarterback
for the New York Giants...
like my personal hero, Eli
Manning.
Annual salary is between ten and
twenty million dollars a year.
Thank you.
Next up, Reed.
Mr. Richards?
Earth to Richards.
Beam me up, Scotty.
Okay, come on, guys.
Oh, sorry.
When I grow up...
I want to be the first person
in human history...
to teleport himself.
I'm sorry, what?
It's already possible to transport
quantum information...
from one location to another.
Right now there are supercomputers
that can transport...
quantum information through
space...
so, why not a machine that can
send people through space?
Well, even if you could build
the thing, which you can't...
I've already built it.
Well, I'm building it.
In my garage.
Is it next to your flying car?
I'm not working on that, anymore.
Just this, now.
I call it The Biomatter Shuttle.
Biomatter...
Technically, I'm shuttling matter
from one place to another.
Well, first, matter...
but once I test on biological
materials, I can...
All right, well... thank you,
Mr. Richards...
this is all very interesting,
but the assignment...
was to pick a real career, in
the real world.
Redo the report and I'll let
you try again tomorrow.
Ben?
Hey, where you going?
I got homework.
What?
Look at that fridge pile.
Idiot.
What'd you say?
Hey! Clobberin' time.
Come here.
What'd you think, you think
you can talk to me like that?
Huh, you think you can talk
to me like that?
Punk, I ought to beat...
What the hell's the matter with you?
Huh? Huh?
Ma...
I didn't do nothing, ma, I
swear to God.
Go check on that fuss.
You didn't do nothing?
I watched you.
What's the matter with you?
How many times do I have to
tell you, you don't hit a kid!
Hey!
Hello?
Who's in there?
Please don't kill me.
Take that off.
I know you... from school.
I'm just looking for a power
converter.
I'm building something.
Ben! What's going on out there?
Hold on!
That teleporting thing?
I can show it to you, I just
need the converter.
All right.
Is that it?
Yeah. Help... me.
Here you go.
Your family owns a junkyard?
Mm-hm.
That place is awesome.
Here, you're stripping the
head.
You might want to cover your
ears.
Stand back a little.
What the hell?
Dammit.
It's all right.
All right, come on.
Don't blow up.
Come on, man, guy's open!
What?
Reed, what did you do?
Now!
Reed!
Did it work?
Where'd the rocks come from?
From the same place the car
went to.
Where's that?
I don't know yet.
Reed.
What?
You're insane.
Thanks.
Mr. Richards.
Shall I alert the fire department?
Hmph.
What is this?
Uh, this is a Cymatic Matter
Shuttle.
Me and my associate Ben
have been working on it...
every day, since fifth grade,
when we launched...
the beta version in my garage.
And today is our first public
demonstration.
What does it do?
It modulates the frequency of
matter...
from one location to another,
and back again.
It's a teleporter.
A teleporter.
Model car, please.
Model... the model car, please,
Ben.
I don't have the model car.
Why don't you have the model car?
I brought it in for this...
I specifically said...
Mr. Richards?
Okay, I will use this model plane.
Hey, I just need to use this
for, uh, one second...
I'll give it back, I promise,
thanks.
Here we go.
Ben?
Please.
You may want to cover your ears.
Great. Now Ben, bring it on back.
Yeah.
Oh, keep them covered.
All right, come on...
What?
Do this...
Oh!
Okay.
Now, if I can have your attention,
please.
What you're looking at, is sand,
presumably...
from the Gansu desert in China...
or perhaps even from the
Sahara...
You're disqualified.
We're not entirely sure...
Mr. Richards.
Yeah?
You're disqualified.
Wait, what?
This is a science fair, not a
magic competition.
I don't see any real science,
here.
And you're paying for the
backboard.
What did you put in the sensors?
Everything is the same.
I know, but your smashing the
buttons.
It's delicate, you can't smash it.
Hey, kid, I'm really sorry
about your plane.
You're a dick.
You cranked it up too high.
I didn't crank it up too high...
it's on the same settings as
the first time.
It's very... I know, it's very
precise.
Excuse me, guys.
Let's pack it up. Yeah?
Did you really build this in
your garage?
Mm-hm.
Now, this is elegant.
What are these?
Um, sonic projectors using
cymatics, to modulate the fuel.
That's why we can't bring the
matter back...
from the other dimension.
Uh, what?
We've gone so far as to send
matter to another dimension...
but we haven't been able to
maintain the fuel long enough...
to bring that matter back.
You just did.
Oh, you're serious?
I think you've cracked
inter-dimensional travel.
Ah, I mean, we're not... we're
not sending anything...
to another dimension...
we send something, we think,
to another part of the planet...
but, I don't know about another
dimension.
We found the same thing you did.
We've had it analyzed repeatedly...
but no one's ever seen anything
like it.
Oh, wow.
I'm sorry, we're from the Baxter
Foundation.
This is my daughter, Sue.
Hi.
Hey.
We'd like to give you a full
scholarship.
Uh, where did you say you were
from, again?
Hey. They could put the whole
neighborhood in there.
What's your name?
Uh, Reed.
Richards! Yes, of course, we've
been expecting you.
They actually wear lab coats,
here.
This is you, sir.
Here.
What?
What is this?
A going away present.
I'm not going away...
I'm like, a forty minute train
ride from Oyster Bay.
Reed, look at this place.
You belong here, I've been two
minutes and I already know that.
I'm just going to school, here...
it's where I'm going to be
working.
It looks like you're home, buddy.
Hey.
This place is pretty incredible...
they have molecular chem books
from the 1950s.
Oh, hey.
Sorry, did you say something?
Yeah, I was just asking, uh...
what are you listening to?
Portishead.
Never heard of him.
Them.
I'll have to check them out.
I love this book.
It's about this guy, Captain
Nemo...
he invents a submarine that goes
deeper than anything in history.
Yeah, I know, I read it.
So, you like music? Is that,
kinda like, your thing?
Pattern recognition.
Pattern recognition?
Music is just a series of
altered patterns.
The musician creates the pattern
and makes us...
anticipate a resolution...
and holds back, makes you wait
for it.
There's patterns in everything
and everyone.
Hmm.
What's mine?
You want to be famous.
Your parents, teachers, all
told you one thing...
one way to be, and...
you ignored them.
And now I'm here.
So, you are.
Am I that predictable?
Everybody is.
Well, you're wrong, I don't
want to be famous.
I just want my work to make
a difference.
Well, here you are, Captain
Nemo. Go for it.
Bye.
Let me guess, some kid from
the internet.
Science Fair.
Franklin, this board has invested
a great deal...
in your little orphanage.
We need real world applications.
This has real world applications.
I truly believe that there is
an entirely...
An entirely new universe, just
beyond our ability to see.
Yes, I read your paper.
Once we get there...
If, we get there.
we'll be able to discover new
resources...
energy sources, which will
revitalize our own.
This is our chance to learn
more about our planet...
and maybe even, save it.
And I'm sure you all would
agree...
that even if such a...
Wait, what is this?
Victor Von Doom is on, here.
He started this project...
and devoted a decade of his
life, to it.
He deserves to be in jail.
He deserves another chance.
He set fire to your data
servers, before he left.
I'm going to personally
supervise him.
I need his talent.
I believe he and Reed can finally
get us there.
We want to support you Franklin...
but you put a lot of faith in
these kids.
I put all my faith, in them.
So, someone stole my design.
No one stole anything, Victor.
Someone else figured out your
idea, and made it work.
That's what happens when you
drop out of the world.
Other people finish what you
started.
Well if you came to ask for
help, it'd be better you...
didn't insult both of us, and
turned back around.
Don't you want to even look at
the designs?
I told you I'm done working
for you and your employers.
They're not my employers.
You can't do a thing without
their permission...
yes?
Wake up, you're an employee.
They'll stay out of my way this
time, trust me.
Oh, it's not you I don't trust.
Yeah.
Well...
I hate to interfere with all
your important work.
Guess we'll just have to make
history without you.
Is Sue going to be there?
I trust her.
Yes Victor, she'll be there.
Clean yourself up, son.
Holy shit.
It's amazing.
Oh.
Thanks.
It's amazing you didn't black out
the entire western hemisphere.
Hmm?
You basically ripped a hole in
the fabric of space-time...
with unspeced components and
no supervision.
Yeah, that was uh, an accident.
And if by accident you upped
the power...
you would have created a
run-away reaction...
that opened a black hole, and
swallowed the entire planet.
Well, I'm glad that didn't
happen.
Are you helping on this?
I'm making the environment
suits.
Based on the soil samples from
our experiments...
anyone who goes to the other
dimension...
is going to need to be protected.
Who's that?
Victor.
Who's Victor?
He started this whole project.
Oh.
Does he go here, too?
It's complicated.
Rudimentary.
Elementary.
It's basically a child's drawing.
You know what Albert Einstein
said.
If you can't explain it simply...
you don't understand it well
enough.
Ten years searching for something
that is...
basically runner-up for a baking
soda volcano.
We were actually disqualified.
The potato clock got second.
Reed Richards, Victor Von Doom.
Victor started the Quantum Gate
project...
when he was younger than you.
Well, it's great to meet you.
Hi, Susan.
Hey, Victor.
Do you prefer Susan?
No. It's been awhile.
I didn't expect to see you
back here.
Yeah, well I couldn't resist.
When I heard about the design...
I needed to see it with my own
eyes.
I gotta say it's pretty impressive...
Thank you.
that you nearly destroyed an
entire planet...
with speaker cable and aluminum
foil.
Yeah, that was an accident.
He did get it to work.
What is this?
This is where your little, uh,
accident leads to.
We put a camera on a drone we
sent over there.
The drone didn't come back, but
those images did.
Huh.
It's beautiful.
Yes it is. New energy, resources.
It's a whole new world.
Which can help save this one.
Not that it deserves to be
saved.
I mean think about, the people
running the Earth...
are the same ones running it into
the ground...
so, maybe it deserves what it's
got coming to it.
Dr. Doom, over here.
The failures of my generation
are the opportunities for yours.
There are no greater minds,
than the ones in this room.
Is he gonna give a speech?
He's gonna give a speech.
But you're going to have to
all come together.
Each of you working together
with a level of commitment...
and collaboration, putting aside
petty squabbles...
if you want to fix what my
generation broke.
If you can do that, work
together...
then you can change the course
of history.
That's a pretty good speech.
I'm in.
Me too.
I'm here, right?
First, design. We figure out
what went wrong and correct it.
Then we build, then we send
organic matter over there.
But more importantly, we bring
it back.
And then, most importantly,
they send us.
Us?
"Us", us?
We're going over there?
Not unless you get to work.
So, get to work.
Johnny Storm.
So, that's the piece of shit
Toyota you been talking about.
Well, yes it is.
Now, you promise me, we'll still
be cool after I dust your ass.
No.
Come on.
Rookie!
Bye bye.
Ha ha ha ha!
Aw, sh...
I cannot believe you are out
here doing this nonsense again.
I told you.
What?
I told you, I was doing 45 when
I spun out.
Yeah...
The ground was wet and I
hydroplaned.
Funny, I don't seem to remember
any rain, today.
You were probably too busy to
notice.
Johnny!
I thought you were turning
things around, what is this?
What are you talking about?
This, this!
Is this the way you want the
rest of your life to be?
You keep acting out!
You have the potential and the
IQ to do so much more.
Oh, you mean like Sue?
I know you think you know what's
best for you...
but trust me son, you do not.
Can you stop that?
What? Stop what?
Stop talking to me like I'm
one of your students.
Well, you're not getting the
car back.
Excuse me?
You're not getting the car
back.
I built that thing from scratch,
with my own two hands.
With my money.
My money, my car.
You want it back, you're gonna
have to earn it.
You're gonna have to come work
for me.
I'm not wearing a lab coat.
I appreciate your work, miss.
Aw, you gotta untuck that shirt,
man.
Is that... Adolph?
Long time.
I'm still not German. And, we
don't need any more help.
Yes, you do.
With what, his boundless
enthusiasm?
Oh, why, thank you, Victor.
He can build anything.
With a broken arm.
What exactly happened?
What?
Were you racing, again?
I don't know what you're talking
about.
I could use some help, actually.
Oh, this guy doesn't take orders
well.
Yeah, especially from people
who say shit like...
"I don't take orders well."
What you need, buddy?
Oh, that's brilliant.
What's up?
Hey.
Johnny.
Reed... nice to meet you.
Have you welded before?
Of course.
Hey.
What's up?
I gotta say, it's fun having
you here.
Mm-hm.
You kinda look like you're in
your element.
Look, don't get used to this.
I'm just here to get my car
back.
Right.
It's good seeing you, too.
Sorry.
Oh, my God.
Why did you do that?
Sorry.
I freak out like that, I was
like... sorry.
You were sort of, sleeping.
Was I?
Is that what that was?
It's okay if you need to take
a nap, or something.
No, I'm good, thanks.
Uh, so, that must have been...
cool, with, uh, Dr. Storm as
your dad.
Yeah.
Did he adopt you?
Mm-hm.
Yeah, I know what that's like.
You were adopted?
No, I... I just wish that I was.
Why?
I don't know, I just, we don't
really understand each other.
Where were you born?
Kosovo.
Kosovo...
You don't have an accent.
I don't?
Hey Reed, can I have a word?
Okay, yeah.
Hey.
You're being unprofessional.
You're supposed to be down
here, working.
Yeah, I am.
That's what we've been doing.
That's not what it looks like.
We're finished.
What?
Yeah, we, we finished it.
Do you want to see?
Yeah.
Hey, Sue.
Can you show him?
I'm really tired, I'm going to
go take a nap.
Can you tell Dr. Storm for me?
We did it, Victor.
Harvey.
Franklin.
Big day. Didn't think we'd make
it here, but, well done.
I told you these kids could
do it.
Harvey's here.
Organic test commencing.
Clear for launch.
Goggles up.
Ten...
nine...
eight...
seven...
six...
five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
Standing by for video on
position.
Status unknown, stand by.
Trying an alternate frequency.
We've got signal.
Look at the plates, it's almost
primordial.
Unformed, like Earth over a
billion years ago.
That place could explain the
origin of our species...
the evolution of our planet...
answers to questions we don't
even know to ask, yet.
EPS, body temp, ventilation
rates are all elevated.
Let's bring him back.
Goggles up.
In five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
How is he?
The vitals are good.
They're really good.
He made it.
It's safe.
All right.
Looks like we're next.
Gentlemen.
Everyone.
You all deserve an enormous
pat on the back.
I think it's time to start
coordinating...
with our friends at NASA.
What?
It works. We have to start
thinking about sending men.
Yeah.
Us.
Look, I won't deny that what
you've created here is incredible.
But this isn't the school
Science Fair, anymore.
We have to bring in help, now.
Well, hey, why just NASA?
Why not the Army, or the CIA?
We could send our political
prisoners there...
waterboarding in the 4th dimension
could prove very effective.
Why don't we discuss the details
of this, someplace else?
In the meantime, we appreciate
your service.
Oh, hey, thank you.
I won't let this go, I promise
you.
Just give him a second to figure
this out.
Look, I don't know about you
guys, but, uh...
I could use some...
One drink?
Ethanol kills brain cells.
You are a light-weight.
Looks like we need another
refill.
Yep.
Hey, Vic.
You guys know who built the
Apollo spacecraft...
went to the moon?
Yeah.
Yo' momma.
So, the answer's no?
But you know who Neil Armstrong
is, right?
Oh, yeah, of course.
Of course.
Buzz Aldrin.
Yeah.
First men to walk on the moon.
Famous faces hired to conquer
dreams that weren't even theirs.
Dreams of someone else, some
other scientist...
who probably died penniless
and alone...
and sat in a bar telling people
he sent men to the moon.
That's gonna be me.
I think it's all of us.
Unless we go first.
Why don't we go first?
God, this thing works, okay?
We can go up there, take five
minutes...
we could take a flag, plant it
down...
get our footprints down there...
we're going to be the first
people over there, okay?
Screw those guys.
My dad might actually kill me,
this time.
Johnny, by the time your dad
finds out, we'll already be back.
Think about it.
Just the three of us?
Hello?
I'm not going without you.
What time is it?
Look, we started this thing
together, we're going together...
I'm not taking no for an answer,
okay?
Forget Neil Armstrong!
Come on.
Neil Armstrong?
You're drunk.
Yeah, I am a little drunk.
Doesn't matter.
Look, the machine works.
The machine works, Ben, and
I need you to come with me.
Now?
Yeah.
Look, Ben, I need you to come,
'cause we're going tonight.
I told the guys that I'm not
going without you.
Okay?
Who's going to have my back?
All right, fine, just w... just
give me a second, all right?
Okay.
Please, all right?
All right, bye.
Thank you, thank you.
He's with me.
Hey, what's up, man?
What's up, buddy?
How you doing. Oh, it's you.
Thanks, Pano.
No problem, Mr. Richards.
Why are we doing this tonight?
Huh?
You trust me, right?
Ta-da!
It's just like ours.
But expensive.
Guys.
This is Ben.
How you doing.
What's up.
Are you his lucky charm?
I'm sorry, this is Borat.
Borat's a dick.
You guys sure you're in the
best shape to be doing this?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
We're good.
Let's do this.
So, I guess I should come up
with something better than...
"One small step for man?"
Strap in and get comfy kids.
We're about to make history.
Yeah, or die.
Either or.
Wow. That's great, Ben.
Thanks.
All right, gentlemen.
Hands and feet must remain inside
the ride, at all times.
Shit.
Dad, you need to come to the
lab.
Remote launch, initiated.
Ten...
Don't blow up.
nine...
Please don't blow up.
Oh yeah, that's what I want
to hear...
before going into another
dimension.
Yeah, don't worry, he does that.
five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
Initiate launch.
What happened?
Did we abort?
Uh, I don't think that we went
anywhere.
Goddammit.
Johnny?
Guys, can you hear me?
I made it.
Wow.
Ben.
Look at this place.
It's amazing.
We did it.
I think we did.
Oh yeah, this one is definitely
going on Instagram.
All right, let's do this.
Ready? After three.
One, two, three!
Woo! Look at that.
Whoa.
Hey Victor, I think you should
see this.
The energy seems to be converging
over there.
Come on, let's check it out.
All right, well, let's do it
quickly...
so we can get out of here.
Hmph. Nope.
Uh-uh.
I'm good.
Reed?
What's he doing?
We need to climb down there,
so we can get a better look.
Oh, you guys go on without me.
Stay here.
We need an anchor.
Huh. Yeah, yeah yeah, I'll be
a great anchor.
Easy does it.
Just a little further.
Right behind you.
Okay.
It's responding to physical
stimulus...
almost like a nerve impulse.
I can feel it...
the energy, it's alive.
It's incredible.
There's no expenditure.
Reed!
What?
I think we should go back.
This is important, Ben.
Come take a look.
Let's go!
Come on!
Come on, come on, come on!
Hurry up!
Come on Reed, come on!
Victor!
Reed!
Hold on!
Reed, pull me up!
Victor!
Grab my hand!
Reed!
Pull me up!
Come on... come on!
Victor, hold on!
Reed! I can't hold it!
Don't let go!
Help me!
No, Victor!
Victor!
No!
Reed!
Let's go, come on!
Victor!
Come on!
We can't leave him.
Reed, we gotta go now, come on!
All right, come on!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Go, go, go!
Move your ass, Reed!
Move it!
Keep moving!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Reed, let's go!
Okay!
Reed, come on.
The re-entry's not working,
I don't know what to do!
Get us out of here!
Reed, do something, we gotta go!
Guys, can you hear me?
Sue!
Sue, Sue, can you hear me?
Johnny!
Do you have any idea how much
trouble you're in?
Yes, yes, I do, Sue, listen...
I need you to manually override
the re-entry, okay?
Okay, okay, I got it.
Manually override the re-entry!
I'm trying!
Sue, just do it!
Reed, the door!
I can't close the door!
Ben!
The door won't close!
Ben?
Ben!
Johnny?
Reed!
Ben!
Come...
Ben?
come help me!
I'm coming!
Reed, help me.
Can't move.
Ben, where are you?
Reed.
Ben.
Reed, help me.
I can't move.
I'll get you out of there.
Oh, my God.
Reed.
Can you move your hand?
Where's Ben?
Keep trying, Reed.
Hey, do you guys know where
my friends are?
Can you lift your index finger?
I, I...
I'm trying...
Where's Ben? Did you see him?
He was covered in the rocks.
Why won't you answer me?
Where are my friends?
Help me!
Increase sedative, 50 CCs.
What have you guys done to me?
So, just for the record...
this program was under your
supervision, was it not?
I already told you it was, but
I wasn't there when it happened.
All I want to know, is where
are my children.
I need to know if they're
alive.
She's unconscious.
Somehow she's shifting in and
out of the visible spectrum.
We don't know how.
Her vitals are stable.
She doesn't seem to be able to
control it.
Looks like we have some activity.
Son!
My God...
Help me, Reed.
Please help me.
Come on, Reed.
Is anybody there?
Ben?
Somebody?
Help, Reed.
Help me!
Can anybody hear me?
Please, help me.
Help.
Somebody, answer me!
Anybody.
Ben?
Ben!
Reed?
Oh, my God.
Ben.
Reed, what, what happened to me?
I don't know, but I'm going to
figure this out.
Ben!
Please help me, Reed!
Subject 1 has escaped containment.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Ben. Ben, I'm coming back for
you, I promise.
No, no no no, Reed, Reed,
help me!
Please, don't leave me!
I'm Sorry.
Reed, do something, please!
Where is he?
Where is Reed?
I don't know.
He's scared, Harvey.
They're all just scared kids.
We don't know what they are,
right now. All we know...
is that they are dangerous
and powerful...
which makes them extremely
valuable...
to the guys who run this
place.
If you think for a minute that
I'm going to allow you...
to turn these kids into some
kind of...
You don't have a choice Franklin,
and neither do I.
Either we play ball with the
government...
or who knows what happens to
those kids.
Now...
here's how this is gonna go.
So, you're Ben Grimm.
Where's Reed?
I can't begin to imagine what
you are going through.
He said he'll fix it.
Where is Reed?
Reed's gone, and your friend
isn't coming back.
Look, I know you're scared.
You should be.
But we can help you.
You want to find a cure?
We have resources here, the
best in the world.
We're analyzing what happened
to you.
Whatever it is, we can find
a way to reverse it.
We can help you, Ben.
But you need to help us, too.
What do you want me to do?
His combat effectiveness this
past year has been unprecedented.
In terms of potential, you
already know...
what he's accomplished in the
field.
He's been active in covert
operations...
with a 100% success rate.
Protecting our men and women
in battle...
and saving countless lives.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is
only the beginning.
The other survivors of the Baxter
incident...
all exhibited unique physical
conditions.
We developed suits which allow
them...
to contain and control these
conditions.
This subject's suit...
controls her spectral flares
and refractive visibility.
With intense concentration,
she's also developed...
the ability to render other
objects invisible...
and to neuropathically produce
forcefields.
All these abilities come from
one place.
Another dimension that our
scientists...
have taken to calling "Planet
Zero."
A planet infused with the same
energy...
that transformed these
survivors...
and potentially could transform
our military capabilities.
We have the direct link.
With your continued support...
once the Quantum Gate 2 project
is finished...
we'll have control over more
than that world.
We'll have control over ours.
Everyone, have a look.
What the hell is that?
Subject number 2.
Two thousand meters in six
seconds. New record.
I still work on my take-off.
I can make it in five.
All target drones, neutralized.
Keep holding your breath Susan,
as long as you can.
Directional stability is 33/10...
rise is steady, pitch is eight
degrees.
Your balance is getting better!
Hey.
They're gonna send me on a
project.
Like Ben?
We should use these powers to
do something.
They're not powers...
they're aggressively abnormal
physical conditions...
Okay, all right.
that we're gonna fix.
Can you turn that off?
And what if they can't?
What if it takes more time to
get it right?
We could be talking years.
I am not going to be a tool.
Johnny.
Stan, you ready?
Yes, we are.
Flame on.
Okay, Johnny.
Thank you, Sue.
Don't forget, we're here to get
our lives back.
The subjects have agreed to
cooperate with us until we find...
the source of their powers and,
potentially, cure them.
Why don't we go see the big
guy?
Hi, Ben. I've got some friends
of mine...
here from Washington D.C.,
visiting.
You got a second to say hello?
It's an honor to meet you,
Mr. Grimm.
We appreciate all you're doing
for us.
Well, that was the deal, right?
And there she is, the Quantum
Gate herself...
the, uh... star of the show.
Franklin.
I'd like for you all to meet
Franklin Storm...
who is our supervisor here on
the floor.
How do you do, Sir?
Good morning.
How long until it's ready?
Well, we've had a few issues,
but we're getting closer.
Closer, every day.
All right, Dr. Allen.
We'll give you what you need.
In the meantime, we'd like to
put more of your subjects...
in the field.
Subject 2 is ready to go.
Get him ready for combat.
Susan!
Can I have a word with you?
They're sending Johnny into
the field.
You mean he's sending himself
into the field.
The only way to stop him is to
cure him.
And that means finishing the
gate.
I can't finish it without Reed.
Reed's not coming back.
He abandoned us, left us here.
He was afraid. He didn't know
what this place was.
I can't believe you're still
defending him.
Help me track him down, Susan.
He'll listen to you.
We'll reopen the gate, find
a cure, end this.
Johnny's your brother.
It's never been as easy for
him, as it has for you.
And like it or not, he's family.
And family means we take care
of each other.
What can I do?
The FBI, CIA, and NSA have blips
of Reed here and there.
But they can't seem to see...
The pattern.
Pattern.
Where was he last seen?
Three months ago, in Panama.
Did you get an IP?
Early on, he was using some
old buried e-mail accounts.
Bouncing off satellites, he's
keeping himself pretty well hidden.
For a short while we were able
to ping him here and there.
Caught him on a few sites.
He was looking for scrap metal,
buying parts.
Never stayed online that long.
Is he looking for anything else?
He was searching for him.
I'm gonna need some music.
Excuse me?
Any music.
It helps me think.
Gracias.
Captain Nemo.
That's him.
He's routing his e-mails through
this relay.
Got him.
You did what you had to do.
Hi, Ben.
We've got another project
for you.
I think you're gonna like
this one.
Freeze!
Do not move!
Get down!
On the ground!
Freeze!
Oh, my God, Ben!
So, this is where you been
hiding out.
Wait, stop.
Okay, let me explain.
Why?
I'm no good to you, to anyone.
This is all my fault.
That, we can agree on.
Does it hurt?
I'm used to it.
I'm sorry.
That's what you said when
you left.
I'm going to fix this.
You can't fix this.
Nobody can.
I promise you, I'm going to
fix this.
I stopped believing in your
bullshit, a long time ago.
You were my best friend.
Look at me.
I'm not your friend.
You turned me into something
else.
Nice work, Ben.
Hey, Reed.
Look, I'm sorry, but I didn't
have a choice.
We need your help to finish
the gate.
It's the only chance we have to
figure out what happened to us...
and reverse it.
You really think that they care
about us?
You know how they've used Ben.
Yeah.
I do.
And they're gonna do the same
thing to Johnny...
if we don't stop them.
The only shot we've got is on
the other side of that gate.
Do you ever wonder what life
would've been like...
if you hadn't come to the
Science Fair, that day?
We can't change the past.
But we can change the future.
You said you wanted your work
to make a difference.
This is it.
This is your chance.
You ready?
You made it ugly.
It's good to see you again,
son.
I'm gonna need ten minutes.
To do what?
I need to make a couple adjustments
to the source code...
you have a few steps that are
out of order.
It can't be that simple.
It might not be ten minutes,
could be a little less.
Come on, let's go.
I've got a good feeling Stan,
I'm gonna crack five seconds.
Hey, could I take a couple
minutes with my son?
Sure, no problem.
Guys, can you give us five
minutes?
What's going on?
Reed is back. We're closer than
we've ever been before.
Closer to what?
Our old lives.
Oh, you mean your life.
No, son.
You always said I had the
potential...
to do something important.
Who's to say this isn't it?
Sometimes things just happen
for a reason.
Johnny, you have no idea what
they are planning to do to you.
They're not doing anything to
me, I'm doing this with them.
Johnny, you need to listen
to me.
I did listen to you, and that's
what got me here...
in the first place.
I'm an adult. I'm old enough
to make my own decisions.
Clear for launch.
Stand by.
Look who it is.
Hey.
It's good seeing you, man.
Good to see you, too.
Sonic projectors engaged.
Goggles up.
Initiating launch.
Systems check, complete.
We have a visual.
Roger that, Control. Are you
receiving atmospheric data?
Copy that.
Checking configuration.
Data transmission looks good.
The landscape's changed.
How?
I don't know, it's just different.
Commencing element/geological
test series.
Copy.
Hey control, I'm picking up
a heat signature...
about 60 yards away.
Now, what could that be?
Hard to make out.
The signal keeps fluctuating.
It's moving, heading towards us.
Copy that.
Proceed with caution.
Do you have a visual?
It appears to be a human form...
with some sort of foreign
element, around it.
I knew you would come back.
Victor?
Not possible.
Subject appears injured.
Get the med kit.
Let's get him to the shuttle.
Okay.
Now, easy, guys. Come on!
Abort.
Bring him back.
Aborting mission. Stabilizing
subject. Prepare for transport.
Preparing for launch!
Transfer the subject to
Containment Room 1.
Copy that.
His thermal signature is barely
registering.
His biochemistry is off the
charts.
I want to talk to him.
Nobody talks to him until I do.
Confine the others to their
quarters.
Victor?
We don't know how you survived
over there, but...
we're still analyzing the data.
It appears that...
the environment suit fused
with your body, but...
we're working on that.
We're going to help you, Victor.
We're working with the
government, now.
We're going to send more expeditions
to the other side, but first...
you need to tell us everything
you know about that place.
You want to know how I survived?
That place kept me alive.
Gave me strength, power.
What kind of power?
The kind, men like you must
never possess.
You couldn't resist coming
back.
It's not enough to ruin your
world.
Now you want to ruin mine.
Victor...
If this world must die so that
mine may live, so be it.
Code Red.
There is an emergency in this
building.
Follow standard emergency
protocols.
Proceed to the nearest exit and
leave the building, immediately.
Code Red, Code Red.
...in this building.
Follow standard emergency
protocols.
Code Red.
Got to get outside!
Hurry, go, go, go!
Get out of here!
Code Red, Code Red.
There is an emergency in this
building.
Follow standard emergency
protocol.
Proceed to the nearest exit and
leave the building, immediately.
Running away, again?
No.
Sue!
My bad, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Where's dad?
Victor, no.
Just stop!
Out of my way, Franklin.
I'm going home.
This is your home, son.
Not anymore.
There's nothing for you, over
there.
Only the power to create a
new world.
Victor, we're not gods.
We're just people.
And we are stronger together,
than we are apart.
What good is it, if you're
alone?
I have always been alone.
Victor, stop!
Just stop.
It's too late, Susan.
The Earth is dying.
Humanity had its chance.
No!
Dad!
Dad, no! I'm Sorry!
No!
Dad, move!
Victor!
No!
Promise me.
Look after each other.
Dad, I'm sorry!
Dad, I'm sorry...
No!
He's overloading the system
to create a runaway reaction.
It's not gonna stop!
It'll create a black hole
that'll swallow the Earth!
It's pulling everything into
the other dimension.
Hold on.
Johnny!
Got it.
The matter from Earth is being
converted to energy.
We need to stop Victor, he's
the source.
He's mine.
I have an idea.
This is what I do.
Where are you, Susan?
Victor, don't do this!
There is no Victor.
There is only Doom.
I saw a different future for
us, Susan.
Help me!
Reed!
Ben.
Goodbye, Susan.
Reed!
Is he dead?
If that thing's still active,
so is he.
We can't beat him.
He's stronger than any of us.
Yeah, he is. But he's not stronger
than all of us.
Look, this place gave him his
powers...
but it gave us all of ours, too.
It's who we are, now.
Maybe it's who we're meant
to be.
We opened this door, we're
gonna close it.
So, what's the plan?
Enough!
When your world's destroyed
and I'm all that's left...
then it will be enough.
Always so smug, thinking you
were smarter than me.
I am smarter than you.
Now!
Hey!
It's clobbering time!
This better work.
Let's get the hell outta here!
While the world may not know
what you did to save it...
the men and the women in this
room, do.
And so does the President.
That said, we'd like to continue
our existing relationship.
So...
if we're all in agreement?
We're not.
Excuse me?
We're not remotely all in
agreement.
We don't need you, or anybody
else to keep an eye on us.
We just want a place where we
can work.
And whatever we come up with
belongs to us.
And what if we say no?
Say yes.
How much space are we talking
about?
A lot.
Oh, boy! So, uh, I thought there
were going to be four of you.
Oh, there is.
Labs are upstairs, engineering's
on the south side, and...
assembly's downstairs.
We've been operating out of
here for...
over twelve years, now. Well,
officially, that is...
but you still won't find our
name on any government books.
Most people just refer to this
as, uh... Central City.
But, call it whatever you want.
We work for you, now.
Oh, wow!
Now, that's what I'm talking about.
That's pretty nice.
I'm taking that area over
there.
I could get used to this.
I got it!
The "Franklin-Storm Research
Center."
Dad was kind of allergic to
his name in big letters.
Which reminds me, I think
that...
the four of us, should have
a name.
Why would we need a name?
Because we're a team now, and
there's four of us...
so, we should come up with a
name, for it.
I like "The Human Torch and
the Torchettes."
Ugh.
No.
You kidding me?
How about "The Big Brain and
his Neurons?"
her Neurons?"
How about "Two Guys, a Girl, and
The Thing That Nobody Wanted?"
Hey, we both know that you
could take him.
Hey!
What?
We've come a long way, since
the garage.
Yeah, I'll say.
It's fantastic.
Say that again?
Yes, it is.
Guys, I got it!
Ready?
Yeah.