Benedict.
Is this true?
You have found the boy?
Yes.
He's not safe here.
Nonsense, this is a fortress.
The full resources of the Order...
...are at our disposal.
Respectfully...
...Benedict, the devil himself
wants this child.
Only one place is safe.
That is the Sanctuary.
The Rider must take him.
You do enjoy your wine, Moreau.
ln a few days...
...the winter solstice will be past
and with it the hour of the prophecy.
Then the boy will be
of no use to anyone.
By that time...
...brother...
...you will all be dead.
This conversation is finished.
They're inside!
Go!
Nadya!
l can help you!
Damn it. Danny!
l can protect you!
Where are they?
Shut up!
Perfect.
Who is this guy?
Screw this.
Duck!
lt doesn't matter how far you run.
There are some demons
you just can't escape.
My name is Johnny Blaze.
l rode a motorcycle for a living.
l did a bare-ass, 360...
...triple backflip
in front of 22,000 people.
lt's kind of funny.
lt's on YouTube. Check it out.
But when my dad got sick...
...l did something
way crazier than that.
You look like you could
use a little help.
Are you willing to make a deal...
...John?
Attaboy.
Do it.
Save his life.
Do it!
Yeah, that is right. l'm the guy
who made the deal with the devil.
I know what you're thinking.
Doesn't this kid watch movies?
Does this ever work out fine?
Let's just say good judgment
was not exactly my forte.
I was possessed by
an ancient demon.
ln the presence of evil,
l change into a monster...
...and I prey...
...on the wicked...
...and l suck out their souls.
And you don't wanna be around
when that happens.
See, there's good and bad in all of us.
And maybe you're not a murderer...
...but you did something
you wouldn't want the Rider to see.
A white lie, an illegal download.
What about you? And you?
l've tried to fight it, to hold it back...
...but the darkness inside me
only gets stronger.
That's why l had to run...
...halfway across the world.
And l'm still running.
Who are you?
My name is Moreau.
My brothers are dead...
...as should l be,
if not for the intervention of God.
And you are John Blaze.
Go away.
l can't do that.
lt likes...
...the dark places.
l don't know what you're talking about.
The Rider.
You thought that you could control it.
Make it work for you, huh?
That you were stronger...
...than this deep, hungry thing?
This...
...sickness.
Why are you here?
What do you...
...want from me?
l need your help
and you need your soul.
So we make a deal.
You know about making deals,
don't you, Johnny?
Nice bike.
This child.
He is in danger...
...and for more than his life.
You will save him.
l don't...
...save people.
What brought you out here,
Johnny Blaze?
Thousands of miles
from your place of birth...
...and your dark rebirth.
You were brought here for this.
This little kid,
what makes you think l can find him?
This man that you met years ago
that put the curse...
...on you?
Roarke.
The devil has many names.
He is the link that connects you
to this child.
Let the Rider follow his stench.
lt will lead you to the boy.
You said something about a deal.
The church of my masters
is an ancient one.
We are prepared to give to you the
one thing you want the most of this world.
Bring us the boy,
and we will lift your curse.
Hello.
Hi.
l noticed you were looking at me.
-Yes?
-Was l?
Nice suit.
Oh, thank you very much.
lt's....
Are you Roma?
Gypsy?
Why do you ask?
Well, what people say about....
What?
Listen...
...l am a businessman.
l have a lot of money.
Yeah?
-And....
-And?
Hey, Mommy. Where's Daddy?
-l.... Excuse me.
-No, no, no.
-lt's okay.
-No, really.
No, really, l.... Yeah.
Sorry.
Somebody's gonna have
a lot of explaining to do.
We won't always have to do this.
Okay?
l wanna make a life for you.
This is a life.
You know l love you more
than anything.
l love you too, Mama.
So many times I've tried to keep the Rider
from coming out, but tonight...
...l need him.
Hold on!
What happened?
Hold on.
Stay in and lock the doors.
Nadya.
No!
lt's been...
...a long time, pumpkin.
Carrigan.
l see you're still an unbelievable...
...pain in the ass.
Look, l got people after
Danny and me...
...so just let me go.
Let me go!
l'm the people after you.
No!
Don't touch him!
Get off!
Get up.
Unbelievable.
Still the fighter.
Carrigan.
-Yes?
-Please.
He's my son.
l know.
But he's not mine.
And part of you...
...had to know it might
end up like this.
Well, kill it.
Hungry.
Oh, God.
Slugthrowers, now.
Don't look at it.
No!
Get some.
Move, now!
Get him in the car.
Get in!
Danny!
-Oh, you have awake.
-Hi.
lt's funny,
because when you walked in...
...l thought l was still dreaming.
You have hallucinate?
No, no, man, l'm not hallucinating.
Look, l'm flirting with you.
You're beautiful.
Okay.
Morphine?
You got any morphine?
Oh, no, no, morphine,
you already have.
Dilaudid, Valium? What?
Your wounds....
Very weird...
...mister.
The poliţie want to talk to you
when you wake up. l tell them you wake.
No!
Please.
l'm fine. Let me go!
Take a piss.
Carrigan.
l got your package, but the cost
of doing business with me just went up.
l don't understand.
What's not to understand?
l want more. You understand that?
We had an agreement, Carrigan.
Changing the defined terms of an
agreement is something we just don't do.
You told me to get a kid.
Not a problem.
l've done that for people before.
And l have history
with his bitch of a mom...
...so there's no better guy for the job.
But what you didn't tell me...
...is that l'd be walking into the middle
of a goddamn horror movie.
Oh, this is funny...
...to you?
Three of my guys got turned
into matchsticks last night...
...by a dude on a motorcycle
with his head on fire.
Come again?
You heard me. I've seen things...
...weird things, bad things.
But that thing last night? No.
-No, no, no.
-Put the boy on the phone.
Talk.
Danny, do you hear me?
l want you to listen...
...very closely. Listen to me.
What the hell was that?
Think of the child as a sort of computer.
You know computers, right?
l just uploaded a little program.
A firewall.
Our friend on the motorcycle won't be
able to sense him now, to track him.
Of course, he still may be able...
...to find you,
so l suggest you keep moving.
Hello?
Who sent you to find me?
ls it the devil?
The devil that walks among men?
Does the devil own you? Answer me!
The kid, Danny. He's your son?
Bullets can't hurt you
when you walk with the demon.
But they'll do
what they're supposed to...
...right now.
Tell me why l can trust you.
You can't.
But if l don't find your son...
...l'd just as soon be dead.
So if you...
...wanna pull...
...that trigger...
...do it.
Please.
You tracked us last night.
Can you do it again?
l could feel him before.
l could sense him and then nothing.
No, no, he's not dead,
he's just blocked.
But you know something.
Let's go.
Yeah, okay, well, let me just
get something straight.
The guy who kidnapped Danny
and tried to kill you and blew me up...
...with grenades...
...you two were like
boyfriend, girlfriend?
Carrigan was a gunrunner,
a drug dealer, a mercenary.
l didn't care about that.
l just saw a ticket out.
Right, okay, and so Danny is...?
Danny, what, is Carrigan's son?
No.
When you met...
...the seducer,
he offered you something.
Yeah. My father's life.
Shocker, he lied.
For me, it was only myself.
lt was supposed to be big
for Carrigan, but it went bad.
l made it out a third-floor window.
I was choking on my own blood.
l knew l was gonna die.
l could feel it.
And that's when he found me.
You look like you could
use a little help.
Roarke.
He promised to take the pain away...
...to save my life.
But he asked for something in return.
A son?
-Maybe you can never understand.
-No, l get it.
You're the devil's baby mama.
l guess that explains why Moreau...
...wants...
...Danny so bad.
-Moreau?
-Yeah.
Black, French, alcoholic priest,
a dick. Know him?
He tried to help us. l didn't let him.
Well, we're both gonna work
on our decision-making.
Where you headed?
Someone l know.
He does Carrigan's dirty work.
He'll know where to find him.
Why does the devil walk on earth
in human form anyway?
l have no idea.
Maybe he doesn't know either.
Maybe he just...
...passes on from body to body...
...through history,
waiting for the perfect fit.
But I know one thing:
On Earth, he's weak.
His powers are limited.
He needs emissaries...
...to do his dirty work...
...so he finds them or makes them
using his greatest power:
The power of...
...the deal.
Can l open a window?
You think you can just talk?
Your mom thought she could just talk,
until l kicked her little Gypsy face in.
Grab him.
Get me-- Get me out of here!
l told you to stop eating the Twinkies.
-Get me out of here!
-Get off me.
Boss!
Come here.
Try that again, you little turd....
What?
Dude, what happened?
You speak English?
Yeah. What happened?
ls that your van?
-Yeah.
-Does it run?
Yeah.
When we get...
...where we're going,
the Rider's going to come out.
And when he does...
...he'll destroy whoever's got it coming.
Nadya, this thing...
...there's no reason, no conscience...
...just hunger.
ln his eyes...
...you're no different than Carrigan.
You're no different than any of them.
l'm not afraid of you.
Yeah? Well, you should be.
That's the guy?
He looks like he works...
...on a cruise ship.
Am l gonna regret taking you?
Yeah, probably.
Count every dollar!
l don't want these idiots robbing me.
Everyone's robbing me!
lt makes my balls hurt!
Hello, Vasil.
Long time, Nadya.
You look good.
Shut up.
He's talked to Carrigan.
The last couple of days
and a few hours ago.
John?
You talked to Carrigan?
l talk to a lot of people.
l got what you need for the shakes...
...my friend.
Carrigan must've told you...
...about that thing that killed
his men last night. Yeah?
That thing...
...is inside of me. See...
...you're a bad man and this thing,
the Rider, he feeds on bad men.
And he's hungry. He's hungrier
than he's been in years.
That's why l'm shaking!
Because right now...
...the only thing standing
between you and the Rider is me.
And he's just-- He's--
He's scraping at the door.
Scraping...
...at the door!
lf you don't tell me...
...what l wanna know,
l'm gonna let him out.
And when he's done with you, there won't
be anything left, do you understand?
Do you understand?
Shake your head yes or no. Good.
Good girl.
Where's Carrigan?
l want the kid! The kid Carrigan has!
You will tell me...
...or l will eat your stinking soul!
The quarry. For more guns, more men.
He's putting together...
-...a goddamn army.
-l know the place.
You won't mention this
conversation to anyone?
No, no, no.
Yeah. All right, well,
that was a good answer.
-Yeah, good.
-John.
We gotta go. We gotta go, we gotta go.
FGM-148 Javelin.
Lock on, fire and forget.
American bunker buster.
Two-stage detonation.
The first creates...
...a super vacuum.
lt sucks the oxygen from the air.
-The next--
-l know what it does.
Give me four of them,
with extra heads.
How many men you go up against?
Just one.
Danny?
-Mom?
-Are you okay?
l'm so sorry. l'm so sorry.
l'm gonna get you out of here.
-What?
-l think my ankle's broken.
Come on, hold on.
Oh, no.
Come on, hold onto me.
Showtime.
Hey!
What is it?
l don't care.
Give me that thing.
-Give it to me.
-Now.
Shit!
That was awesome.
Reload. Just reload.
Give me that.
Okay.
l'm sorry, did that hurt?
lt looked like...
...it did.
Come on.
Let's go.
Hurry!
Sorry. Does it hurt?
lt looks like it does.
What are you waiting for? Do it! Do it!
He's coming.
Let me go.
Enough.
Let her go.
So that happened.
There you go.
lt was a bee. l thought it was
gonna sting your face.
Well, are you feeling better?
Your leg's all healed, huh?
Like all by itself.
That's weird.
Where's my mom?
She's gassing up the truck.
l know that it's a little awkward.
Me rolling with you guys.
l mean, after everything that you've...
-...been through.
-Dude.
You're cooler than the guys
she usually hangs out with.
Hey.
So, what's next?
Moreau thinks that the danger
will pass in a few days.
lf we just get Danny someplace safe...
...a holy place,
where his people can protect us...
...then we can ride it out.
Okay.
l've already contacted Moreau.
He's gonna catch up with us on the road.
We gotta move fast because the ones
who are hunting us, they're not done.
Plus, l have some personal issues
l'd kind of like to get fixed.
You're not done, Carrigan.
You were to bring me Nadya's son.
l do expect you to fulfill your obligation.
S.... S.... S.... Sorry, jackass...
...but l'm dead.
lnconvenient.
What'd you do to me?
Gave you a second chance.
You're a little less than alive now.
But also more.
You see, l've given you power.
The power of...
...decay.
Of darkness.
l want that boy, Carrigan.
Now you've got no...
...excuses.
The machine last night?
Yeah?
You made it change.
That's how it works.
Whatever he rides changes with him.
And what if he took a taxi?
l don't know. l don't know. Why?
Or a roller coaster or a ski lift
or a camel or a--
Dude.
What if you have to pee
while you're on fire?
Oh, it's awesome. lt's like a flamethrower,
you know? lt's like:
When you change, when you're him...
...does it feel good?
Sometimes.
What does it mean? Are we just bad?
No.
This power that we have
comes from a dark place...
...but it's not who we are.
lt never will be.
And we can use it to do good...
...to help people.
Like l'm helping you and your mom.
l know why you're helping.
She says you wanna get rid of it.
l can't ever do that.
Hey, Nadya. l hope you have
finished shooting at me!
Hey.
You wanna have some fun?
Hang on.
That is so weird.
So this is it, Moreau's happy place.
These guys will lift my curse?
They don't even have shoes.
Amen.
You mustn't be afraid.
lt was God that led you here.
What's up?
l know. A little...
...uptight. Not so bad...
...once you get to know them.
Now go on.
They will take...
-...good care of you.
-What about...
...you two?
We will join you later. we have some
business to complete between us.
l made a promise to you, John.
Why can't he come with us?
-No!
-Danny.
Danny...
...you're safe here.
We made it.
The only thing that can hurt
you and your mom now...
l need to make sure
that will never happen.
lt'll be all right.
l promise.
Whatever.
Come on.
Are you sure about this?
-Where are we going?
-To my favorite room.
lf there is one thing
these sons of bitches know...
...it's wine.
This bottle would fetch
50,000 euros at an auction.
Moreau.
Oh, yeah.
-What is it?
-lt's--
This thing inside of me.
l'd like to know before we...
...commence.
Zarathos was an angel...
...a Spirit of Justice.
Sent to protect the world of men.
But he was tricked...
...captured...
...brought down to hell...
...corrupted.
Driven insane.
His mission to protect the innocent
was perverted...
...into a lust to punish...
...the guilty.
He became...
...the Spirit of Vengeance.
Yeah, but the angel,
the Spirit of Justice...
...he's alive in there?
Somewhere?
He could be.
Do you feel him?
No.
Cheer up, my man.
Soon you will be free.
This bottle....
This one is over 2000 years old.
l've had my eye on it for a while.
When this is over...
...we will share it, huh?
There's something else.
This thing that Roarke has done to you
is not easily undone.
You risk death.
Worse than death.
You must confess...
...the one thing that is most difficult
for you to talk about.
My dad.
l didn't do it for him.
l made the deal for me.
l couldn't let him go.
lt was selfish.
He was ready to die.
He knew it was his time.
And l thought l could change that.
l'm sorry.
This is the lamb of God...
...that takes away all the sin
from the world.
Happy are those
that are called to receive him.
You say that you're not worthy
to receive him.
l'm not.
Okay, that's good enough.
The body of Christ.
Amen.
You've been carrying this bread
around for a while.
May God lead you
into the eternal life.
That is, John, if today is,
in fact, your last.
Where you go now, l cannot follow.
Are you ready?
Hello?
Hey.
Merry Christmas, you assholes!
Make the deal.
Moreau!
You did it!
lt worked.
No! Let me go!
Help me!
-Hey! What are you doing?
-Get off me!
Let me go!
What are you doing?
What will be done.
The day of prophecy is tomorrow.
We were to hold the boy
until the danger passes.
The danger will not pass, Moreau.
As long as the boy exists...
...the power...
...will always be inside him.
You lied to me.
You lied to me!
This child must be destroyed.
No!
You might have protested
while the child was being conceived.
Now it is too late.
Take them away...
...until the thing is done!
Go!
Danny's soul can still be saved!
That boy is one of God's children!
No!
He is not.
Pretty neat, huh?
Peace, brother.
Damn.
Bet you're happy to see me.
Did Danny do this?
No. Somebody got here
before they could--
Before they could kill him.
There's no sign of him.
Whoever did this wanted...
-...him alive.
-l think we all...
...have a pretty good idea
who that would be, Moreau.
Yeah. So now he's...
...with Roarke.
Some protectors you turned out to be.
What exactly does Roarke
have in mind for Danny?
What are his plans for his son? ls he
putting money away for college? What?
lt is the day...
...of prophecy.
As was the day Danny was conceived.
The child must be in his 1 3th year...
...before the rite can be performed
on the dawn of winter.
The rite.
Roarke fathered the boy as a vessel,
as a container for his power.
The ritual will transform his essence...
...his soul into the boy.
There will be no more Danny.
-Only Roarke.
-No!
-Why the hell didn't you tell us this?
-Hey.
You made a deal with Roarke!
Both of you!
Something l would never do.
The prophecy had to happen
at the dawn of a new day.
Maybe there's still time.
-Do you know where Roarke has him?
-l think so.
What, so now you want to play hero?
You got what you wanted.
Yes, l did.
Thank you for holding up
your end of the bargain.
You're welcome.
lf l can spend my last day...
...as a free man without a curse...
...over my head, l'll take it.
But l promised Danny he'd be safe.
And if l walk away now...
...l'm just trading
one demon for another.
So let's go.
-Was there ever any doubt?
-Don't...
...touch me.
Cutting it a bit close, aren't we?
You have any idea...
...what l had to go through...
...to get this little turd?
Look...
...the planets don't align for your
pagan party until daybreak tomorrow.
So get off my ass
because l'd say l'm ahead of schedule.
Danny.
Do you know who l am?
Well, l'm sure your mother told you...
...a lot of things about me.
What's the matter with your face?
Uzak Gökten.
The farthest point from heaven.
That is where the ritual is to take place,
according to the prophecy, of course.
Of course.
Without the Rider, we stand
very little chance against Roarke.
You were supposed to have faith.
l do.
But also,
l think we should have weapons.
Guns...
...and wine.
Naughty priests.
l'm starting to like you again, Moreau.
You wanted to know
why l look this way.
Think of...
...a flamethrower.
ls that funny?
Okay.
A flamethrower
made out of papier-mâché.
All that...
...power.
But try to use it, you burn up.
This body l'm living in...
...it's weak, human.
lt's dying.
lt was never made to do
the things that l can do.
But you...
...you're only part human.
You have all the power
that l have inside of you.
Like father, like son.
But this...
...corporeal...
...form...
...can wield the power
without burning itself up.
To help you...
...relax.
That will keep him sedated
until the ceremony.
Who are they?
Politicians, murderers,
people of influence.
The devil's soldiers.
They've traveled
from all over the world...
...to witness the anointing
of the new king.
The new king.
Please.
lf Roarke succeeds...
...he'll have a new form,
one more powerful than he's ever known.
And a shadow will fall upon the earth.
Twenty-five...
...30 men. More inside.
The ritual has already begun.
Danny's soul will be lost forever...
...at the break of dawn.
This is when Roarke is at his weakest.
Nadya?
You all right?
l've made a lot of mistakes, Blaze.
But Danny....
Danny's the one....
The one good thing...
...l ever did.
Well, that being the case...
...we had better make sure he doesn't
turn out to be the Antichrist.
Okay. Not much time.
What's the plan?
Plan is you go, you grab the boy,
you run and you don't stop.
What about you?
Me? l'm going through the front.
Okay.
Not bad.
This might be good on a salad.
Johnny Blaze!
Go.
Catch this one, huh?
What a waste of good wine!
That felt good.
Come on.
Danny, listen to me.
l shouldn't have gotten rid
of the power.
l know that now.
He's gonna erase you, Danny.
Moreau.
l can still see the light!
That's gross.
You have no power, Blaze.
You're nothing but an insect...
...like the rest.
Food for the mills...
...of hell.
No.
Not yet.
Oh, you wanna watch?
The apple doesn't rot far from the tree!
Danny.
This is not who you are.
lt never...
...will be.
My powers and yours are the same.
That's what you said.
Right?
Dad?
Like father, like son.
Do it.
No!
Come here.
Enough!
l was never afraid of you.
Roadkill.
You!
Worst fucking deal l ever made.
Go home.
Danny!
The angel.
Moreau...
...said that the Rider
was an angel that went crazy.
l can feel him...
...the angel.
l can feel him.
Danny?
Did we win?
l'm gonna say yes.
Hell, yes.
My name is Johnny Blaze.
l'm the Ghost Rider.