Ferguson, Herman.
6 month sentence at Aspen served. Welcome
back, citizen. Your living assignment:
Y-block, Heavenly Haven, red quad.
Move on! Come on!
Welcome home.
That's it! I think that's Heavenly Haven!
Better than prison.
Jesus Christ!
Eat recycled food for a happier life!
Be kind and peaceful to each other.
Eat recycled food. It's good
for the environment and OK for you.
Hey, look what I got!
A little cupcake.
What have we got here?
You a Judge spy, little man?
Me a spy? This guy, he's funny!
No. I live here! I mean I'll live here.
If I live. Maybe I should go to a hotel.
No way, man! Don't you hear 'em out there?
It's block war, man!
Block war. Block war!
Like an academy simulation, right down
to the cross fire! I lead off, you follow.
This is no sim, rookie!
You will stand down and wait for backup!
Hershey and Brisco in position!
We're under fire from the upper floors.
Inside Heavenly Haven. Request backup!
Level Y, yellow, repeat! Nearest Judge!
Holly crud!
He knows what he's doing.
I am the law!
Drop your weapons!
These blocks are under arrest!
This is your final warning!
Judge Dredd!
Hey! You wanna be afraid of somebody?
Be afraid of me!
I got it! Why don't I run down there
and surrender? Sorta throw him off guard?
Bad idea.
- Hey, Dredd! Come and get us!
I knew they'd do that.
- Take cover!
They're firing 20 millimeter
caseless flechet rounds at 300 meters.
The effective lethal range is 200 meters.
You're safe!
What are you doing there, Judge Hershey?
Waiting for backup.
It's here.
Move it out! Keep it simple,
single file, standard relay, I'm point.
You're last.
Grenade!
Meet me on the 40th!
- Hey, get some more ammo!
Be kind and peaceful to each other.
Eat recycled food.
Hey, you guys with us?
- Yeah!
All right!
- Move out!
This room has been pacified.
- Next one's mine!
No!
This room is under arrest.
You're under arrest! Throw down
your weapons, be prepared to be judged!
Judge this! Lawgiver man!
- No! Don't, they're booby trapped!
Holy drock!
- Auto rapid fire. Armor piercing!
Drop dead, Dredd!
Double whammy.
Mega City Municipal code 2-13,
willful destruction of property. 2 years.
Code 3-10, illegal possession
of assault weapons. 5 years.
Code 4-57, resisting arrest, 20 years!
And code 36-13.
The first degree murder of a Street Judge.
Let me guess. Life.
Death.
Court's adjourned.
53 hospitalized. 5 ofthem children.
19 dead.
Damn it!
I'm supposed to be watchin' out for him.
Don't blame yourself, Hershey.
He made the mistake, not you.
Wouldn't it feel good to have an emotion?
Emotions.
There outta be a law against them.
Halt!
You have 5 seconds to surrender!
- Dredd, it's just a servadroid.
Five, four, three, two, one!
Boy, am I glad to see you!
Mega City Municipal Code 75-92.
Willful sabotage of a public droid.
That's 6 months, citizen. Your Unicard!
Come on, give me a break, Judge Dredd.
Dredd? Holly God!
H. Ferguson, hacker. Illegal tampering of
droids, computers, cash machines, taxis.
And not even out of jail for 24 hours.
He's habitual. Automatic 5 year sentence. How do you plead?
- No guilty?
I knew you'd say that.
- 5 years?
I had no choice! They killed each other!
- You coulda gone out the window.
40 floors? It woulda been suicide!
Maybe! But it's legal.
Judges! Five years, Aspen Penitentiary!
Case closed. Take him away!
Don't close the case!
You're misjudging me! Open the case!
And if he told the truth? Never heard
ofextenuating circumstances?
I've heard it all, Hershey.
I knew you'd say that.
My fellow Judges,
have we forgotten the lessons of history?
However quickly
these block wars can be contained,
it's clear: They're becoming an epidemic!
We should deal with it at once. A tougher
criminal code is the only solution!
Our situation gets worse every day.
73 citizen riots in 16 different sectors
in the last two months alone!
- Violent crime is rising at 15 percent
every quarter! Lfwe don't increase
our resources, they will be inadequate.
In less than three years.
- Three years? They are inadequate now!
My fellow council members. As a city,
we continue to grow. Growth is painful.
65 million people living in an area
designed for no more than 20!
It's not enough that they rely on us
for food, clothes, water, for clean air.
Chief Justice. The city is in chaos!
For social order we need tighter reins!
Incarceration didn't work as a deterrent.
I say we expand execution
to include lesser crimes!
My fellow Judges. I was barely in my teens
when I put on this badge.
When it comes time for me to take it off,
please, let me do so knowing
that it still stands for freedom.
And not for repression.
53 hospitalized. 19 dead!
4 ofthem killed by a gang of squatters,
who were themselves killed
in summary executions by Judge Dredd.
As my special report continues I take you
behind the scenes ofthe halls ofJustice.
With a probe into these recent riots
and block wars. Coincidence or deliberate?
Dredd?
Joseph.
- Chief Justice Fargo.
You may stand at ease, Joseph.
So tell me, seven summary executions?
Were they necessary?
Unavoidable, sir.
- Unavoidable.
Life doesn't mean much to some people
any more. You'd see that if you weren't…
If I weren't what?
- Always at the Academy, sir.
Oh, don't you mean
at the Academy wiping cadets' asses?
That's what they say in the squad room.
- It's irrelevant. You set the standards.
Well, now you do. Well, at least
to many young cadets you're a legend.
Sir.
You remember your days as a cadet, Joseph?
- I remember what you taught me, sir.
You were my finest student.
So I got a new assignment for you.
Starting tomorrow, you're going to spend
two days a week at the Academy.
I'd be honored, sir. Unarmed combat or marksmanship?
- Ethics.
Remain still. Identify yourself.
- Miller. Warden.
Voice sample recognized.
Thank you, Warden.
So why are you here?
You come for another chat?
Just a short one, I'm afraid. Duty calls.
Ah, duty. Feeding these parasites here?
At the public's expense?
Yeah. You especially.
I don't cost anything! I'm a ghost.
And we're both prisoners here.
You're behind your desk.
And I'm behind this.
What a clever reward from Fargo.
I mean considering the services.
When you started killing innocent people,
Rico, you went beyond service.
The innocent exist only until inevitably
they become perpetrators. Like you.
Guilt and innocence is a matter oftiming.
Your, our mysterious benefactor
has sent you a package.
Deactivate shield. Auto guns only.
What is that?
- That's an ancient puzzle
that contains the meaning of life.
So tell me, Rico.
What is the meaning of life?
It ends!
Activate alarm!
Voice not recognized. Guns are training.
No!
Secure good! Three, one, two. Come on!
Kevlar-9-helmet and body armor.
Yours when you graduate.
Lawgiver 2. 25 rounds of side arm
with variable voice programmed ammunition.
Signal flare! Yours if you graduate.
Mark-4-Lawmaster, improved model.
With dual on-board laser canons,
vertical take-off and landing flight
capabilities. Range: 500 kilometers. Men?
Yes, sir.
Yours if you can ever get it to work.
All ofthese things you see here are toys.
At the end ofthe day.
When you're all alone in the dark.
The only thing that counts is this.
The law.
And you will be alone
when you swear to uphold these ideals.
For most of us is death on the streets.
For the few of us who survived to old age.
The proud loneliness ofthe Long Walk.
A walk that every Judge must take
outside these city walls.
Into the unknown ofthe Cursed Earth.
And these spend your last remaining days
taking law to the lawless.
This is what it means to be a Judge.
This is the commitment I expect.
Class dismissed.
I can hear you thinking.
I caught your lecture today. You think
the cadets really need to hear that?
I told them the truth.
- Your truth maybe.
You made it sound like our lives are over!
Don't you think ours are, Hershey?
I have a personal life. I have friends.
You're the smartest one ofthe new breed.
You've only been on the street a year.
You haven't gotten use
to the isolation yet.
No. I don't think that's right.
No one is supposed to be always alone.
Is that really been what it's been
like for you? Have you never had a friend?
Yes. One.
What happened?
Dredd! Wait. I want to know.
I judged him.
2 loads from the prison factory in hold 1.
We're closed for the night.
You're holding a package for me.
The code name is Lazarus.
I'll just be a second.
You got a nice place.
Yeah. A lot ofthis is antiques.
That's funny. I thought they destroyed
all these ABC Warriors during the war?
Well, you can still collect 'em.
As long as they're non-functioning.
Like my wife.
Yeah, these must be 50 or 60 years old.
Anyway.
There you go.
Hey, wait a second! Don't touch it!
Why is that?
- Why it's a Lawgiver.
That's programmed to only recognize
a Judge's hand. It'll take your arm off!
Gee. How do you like that?
I must be a Judge.
Happy Birthday.
Status?
How 'bout bodyguard.
Commander?
- Rico.
Mission?
- Mission?
We're going to war.
War.
I followed up some grumblings
confirming a suspicion of mine.
The cancer of oppression goes far deeper.
- You're going to say that over the air?
It's the truth.
- Vardis, you're insane. I'm a reporter.
They'll never let this get on to the air.
This could bring down the Council.
Maybe it should. The whole system
is the problem. Not just Judge Dredd? No!
OK, baby, up we go.
OK, hang on to your seat, cuz here we go!
Step outta the car, please.
- What the hell's the problem now?
Get outta the car! Unicard, please!
Did you hear me? Unicard!
Mr. Susa. You have a suspended license.
3 counts of driving under the influence.
Hey! You better listen! I suggest
you walk away and bother somebody else!
I have powerful friends, I mean powerful!
Are we having a problem here, Hershey?
- Not at all. Nothing that I can't handle.
Suspended license. Three DUls.
- That's getting boring. What's the tab?
How much? You name your price.
Hershey, call control for an H-wagon.
- What? You're gonna tow me?
Towing iffor a first violation. That's
your 4th, bar breath. How do you plead?
Not guilty.
- I knew you'd say that.
Hey, wait a second. What are you doing?
- Grenade. - No!
Happy motoring.
Subtle.
Judge Joseph Dredd!
Dredd. You're under arrest.
- What's the charge?
Murder.
Joseph.
- Sir?
Is it true?
- I'm innocent.
The Council's said to have irrefutable proof.
- You believe that?
Let there be a full tribunal.
Do you believe that, sir?
I just needed to look into your eyes
for myself. I'm sorry I asked.
I would never do anything to disgrace you.
I'll use every resource to find out.
Have you selected someone to defend you?
- Judge Hershey. - Why Hershey?
At the Academy she was at the top
of her class in interpretation ofthe law.
And I trust her.
The facts will come out at the tribunal.
I'll personally make sure ofthat.
Sir?
I'm sorry about this.
Dredd? No!
Stop video.
The video is prima facia evidence
that the defendant is guilty as charged.
Mark it peoples' exhibit A.
- Objection, your Honor.
This video is inadmissible as evidence.
If I may begin in a moment to explain.
Please do.
I have an affidavit from Nathan Olmeyer,
currently a junior at the Academy.
He has been acknowledged by every one
of his instructors to be an expert
in digital and video graphics.
The surveillance video, as his affidavit
states, is of such low definition.
No positive identification can be made
ofthe killer.
The uniform of a Judge can be counterfeit.
And the badge can be duplicated.
Neither the video nor the audio
in this presentation identify the accused.
I repeat my objection to this video
being allowed as evidence in this case.
And I ask for a ruling.
Objection sustained.
The video is inadmissible.
Yes!
Admit it, Dredd.
- What? You're impressed.
Very.
- You owe me.
I have to move to technical information
of a criminal nature.
I will need the court's permission
to access top secret documentation
with the help of Central Computer Bank.
- You may proceed.
Central, are you on line?
- On line, Judge McGruder.
I wish you to access weapons schematic.
Please describe the working of
the standard Judge's sidearm, Lawgiver 2.
Model 2 is coded to the personal DNA
ofthe Judge using the weapon.
By the skin's contact with the grip.
Did you know it? - No.
- The DNA is
from my medical files and upgraded
automatically when the weapon is reloaded.
When a round is chambered, the projectile
is tagged with that relevant DNA.
The defense was not made aware ofthis.
Judge Hershey! The prosecution
must be given time to finish.
Central, were the bullets recovered
from the bodies ofVardis and Lily Hammond
so DNA coded?
Yes, Judge McGruder.
It could not be otherwise.
What was the result ofthe computer check
ofthe DNA on those bullets?
The DNA's a perfect match for Judge Dredd.
A lie! The evidence has been falsified!
It's impossible!
I never broke the law! I am the law!
We have no case!
- You've gotta believe me!
You have to believe me! Say it!
Your Honor, the prosecution rests.
The tribunal needs to confer.
What have I done?
How could I have been so wrong!
Dredd! Both ofthem homicidal! This time
it will be impossible to cover up!
Chief Justice. We carefully buried
the Janus project. Nine years ago.
Along with Rico and all his victims.
No one'll ever learn ofyour involvement.
The media knows how close I am to Dredd.
They'll find the truth. The best excuse
to ruin what government we have left.
Your motives are pure. You thought Dredd
was different, that's why you spared him.
A mistake which may bring down
the Judicial System.
There is a way out, Chief Justice.
Lfyou'll forgive me.
The Long Walk.
That's a death sentence, Judge Griffin.
Mine.
Your retirement grants you the power
to save Dredd's life!
This gesture may also allow Janus
to remain a secret.
In the charge of premeditated murder,
this tribunal finds Joseph Dredd guilty!
As charged.
Joseph Dredd, you're aware ofthe law
allows only one punishment for your crime.
Death. However,
it has long been our custom
to carry out the last order
of a retiring senior Judge.
And so…
I step down. - No!
- I can't believe it.
As I leave to take my long walk
into the Cursed Earth
I ask that this court honor my last order.
Be lenient with Judge Dredd.
In gratitude for his years ofservice.
We will so honor this one, Judge Fargo.
Dredd! Step forward!
The sentence shall be life imprisonment!
At Aspen. To be carried out immediately!
As it is written!
- Justice Griffin!
The trial was a farce! I demand an appeal!
You will accept the court's decision,
Judge Hershey!
Dredd, I'm so sorry. I let you down.
You did your best, Hershey. Thank you.
Let the betrayer ofthe law
be taken from our courts!
Let his armor be taken from him.
And all his garb ofjustice.
Let him be stricken from our hearts
and our memories for ever!
Let his name be recorded
in every place of honor.
Let him take the law he served so well
to those who have it not.
Let him be written. In our hearts.
And our memories forever.
Judge Hershey.
Ah, there's gotta be some.
What's this?
Baby Dredd?
Ah, I can't believe you were ever a baby.
Who's this?
Chief Justice Griffin.
It's got a nice ring to it.
- We were supposed to meet a place safe!
What's not safe?
Your reporter's dead, right?
Fargo's on his walk. Dredd's in Aspen.
So what's not safe?
- It's unfortunate
Hammond had to be silenced.
He'd find out about Janus.
But I coulda used Dredd.
- Forget Dredd! There is no Dredd!
Let me tell you what Dredd worships.
He worships the law! He'da blow you away!
The minute he found out
how much you're pissin' on it!
Yeah. Let him see what it's like
to freeze his ass off in Aspen!
Let him see what it's like to be me!
There's a lot ofwork to be done.
Janus? Well, where is it?
You'll see it!
- When? Soon enough!
In the meantime, I want chaos, Rico.
That block war was just the beginning!
Now I want fear
racing through every street!
Then the Counsel will have to turn to me.
And to Janus!
You want fear? I'm fear.
You want chaos? I'm the chaos!
You want a new beginning?
Here! I am the new beginning!
Dredd? Don't hit me! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Don't hurt me.
What are you doing here?
I was convicted of a crime.
Wrongly convicted.
Really? That's kinda weird.
What are the odds?
Two wrongly convicted guys?
Sitting right next to each other!
You got the sentence the law required.
Five years? Just for saving my own ass?
That was a mistake.
- The law doesn't make mistakes.
Really? Then how do you explain
what happened to you?
You can't, can you?
Great! Mister "I-am-the-law" can't!
So maybe this is some kinda typo?
Maybe it's a glitch?
Or maybe it's poeticjustice!
So someone's comin', Pa!
Praise the Lord
for bringing us this generous bounty.
My sons.
Gather the harvest.
So maybe you're here
as some sorta field trip?
Yeah. Maybe this is
as some sorta surprise party?
Gonna catch me some city boy!
Knife! Knife!
It's payback time, Dredd!
Dredd! What's happening?
By a blast of God they parish!
And by a breath of his nostrils
are they consumed.
Hallelujah!
Central, I need you to access database.
I want you to run an ID on this man.
Scanning for identity. Unknown male.
Approximately 200 centimeters tall.
Skin tone three. Ten, nine, eight.
Central. Hello?
This terminal has been disconnected
from the main system.
This is Capture Team. No sign of Dredd.
He appears to have survived the crash.
You are in error, Capture Team.
No one survived the shuttle wreck.
The pilot, sir. He's alive.
No one survived the shuttle wreck! Do I make myself clear?
- Yes, sir!
Am I dead? Am I dead? I'm dead.
Awake? Good! We're running outta sinners!
Oh my God!
Dredd! Do something!
- Dredd?
You talk too much.
Can it be?
The great man ofthe law himself.
Oh Lord, you have blessed us indeed!
Judge. Rat. Dredd.
You creeps are under arrest.
- Is that so? Let me crush him, Pa.
Excuse me, we're not together.
Allow me to introduce you to my family.
There's Link, my oldest.
Bite me.
- Hi!
My youngest, Junior. - Howdy.
And this here is Mean. We had to make
some alterations when he was a child.
Well, the Cursed Earth's a tough place
on young folks.
I now have him set on one.
I don't suggest you make him angry.
The legendary Angel family.
Cursed Earth pirates,
murderers, scavengers.
And of course, scumbags!
- Oh, how to win 'em over!
Did I leave something out, Pa?
Let me kill him, Pa. I want his ears.
- I want his teeth!
Does that come with a fork handsome?
Hallelujah, brother!
- Wait a minute!
Can it be? Can it be that from the City
ofthe Fallen we have one ofthe faithful?
Amen, brother! Praise the Lord!
I'm a believer!
We have a believer in the gallery?
- Yes!
Cut him down!
- Go tell it on the mountain! - Fergie!
You're making a big mistake.
Well, maybe the law doesn't make mistakes,
but I'm free, and you're toast.
Actually, you're toast!
I forgot to mention it:
Your new friends they're cannibals.
You're cute!
- Fresh meat! Prepare the supplicant for sacrifice!
Wait! You can't eat me! I've got eczema!
I've got warts! I've had gonorrhea!
Eat Dredd, he works out!
It's been fun. Law man.
Mean? Finish Dredd.
My pleasure, Pa.
- Come on!
Kill him!
- Come on, Junior!
Guilty!
Dredd! Look out!
Dredd!
Get up!
Well, we did it. We got 'em all!
Pussies! Is that all you got?
They are dead, right?
Have you been crying?
- No! I've got something in my eye!
Have you ever had allergies?
Dredd! Look out!
Chief Justice?
- Joseph. Together again.
Together again, sir.
No!
God! Not again!
You've got three strikes, lawman.
Strike one!
Strike two!
Strike three!
Lawman, you're too late!
You killed Junior! You got Link!
He who killed my Pa!
Mega City Municipal Code 47-22.
Illegal use of city electricity.
How do you plead?
I knew you'd say that!
Graphics analysis, now.
Olmeyer, you stupid futz! I can't…
You analyzed the wrong viewie. This one!
I don't believe it!
You just wasted three hours!
Lfthis is the wrong picture,
why is it a fake?
What?
- Look!
It's full of anomalies,
really clever ones, too!
Somebody must have used
a CGI terminal and a scan quad
to make this state ofthe art.
20 years ago.
Are you saying that this isn't real?
Yeah. Look.
I'll drop out all the artificial pixels.
Dad. Mom.
Foreground. Background.
All fake.
The only thing that's real is the baby.
The blind lady.
Who is she?
- Justice before your time.
We should have never taken Justice
out oftheir hands.
You put order to chaos, sir.
- Yeah. That we did. Solved many problems.
And created many more!
Being a Judge, Joseph, you unite perhaps
too much power in one person's hands.
We once tried to compensate.
Created the perfect Judge.
We called it Janus.
Four decades ago, DNA samples
were taken from the original Council.
One was chosen: Mine.
We altered it
to enhance the best qualities.
And to screen out the worst weaknesses.
Frailties.
We created you.
You didn't create me, sir.
I have a family.
- No.
At the Academy you said they were killed when I was very young.
- I lied.
I have a picture ofthem.
- They're a fake. We lied to both ofyou.
Both?
In that experiment another infant
was created. But something went wrong.
Genetically mutated
to the perfect criminal.
I have a brother?
- You were best friends at the Academy.
Star pupil, and then he turned.
And for his crimes, you judged him.
Rico?
Rico!
You let me judge my own brother?
You never told me, sir.
- I couldn't!
You were like a son to me.
A son?
My whole life is a lie.
Rico had to be executed.
To protect you. To protect the city.
Rico.
He's alive!
No. I signed the order myself.
I saw the report.
I didn't kill Hammond. It was him!
It was his DNA that convicted me.
Griffin. It was Griffin!
Griffin, yes.
- We've both been deceived. I'm so sorry.
Rico's killed me and destroyed you.
Find them, Joseph!
Don't die.
What do we do? What do we do?
Find Rico.
Welcome to Janus.
Ah, Rico, I think you know Dr. Hayden.
I remember you.
Justified in front ofthe Council
that I was insane. And therefore innocent.
I tried to save you.
- You insulted me!
Because I knew exactly what I was doing!
Then and now.
Miss Hayden has been a loyal supporter
ofthis project for a long time.
She's kept it alive for me. I'm sure
you'll find her expertise invaluable.
Excuse me? That's useless if you can't get
into Central's Janus files
because the Counsel has 'em locked!
- Leave it to me! Meanwhile, you've work.
On the streets. Ilsa will help you.
- I don't need to help. Thank you.
I thought you said he was created here
by the finest scientists of Mega City?
A bold experiment.
A patchwork child.
Let's not bicker!
We're all committed to do the same thing!
An ordered society.
You'll have your new order.
Attention, all Judges! Reporting unrest.
Code D 9-2-4.
Downtown sector twelve. Backup requested!
My boy.
Dredd, there's no way in!
Hello? Have you been listening to me?
We can'tjust knock on the wall and say,
"Hello, Cursed Earth pizza."
There is a way in. Six years ago,
two refugees figured it out.
The vent to the city's incinerator.
There's a burst twice a minute.
That means you could run through that tube
and have 30 secs before it flames again.
And these refugees made it through, right?
Actually, they were roasted.
But the theory's sound.
Maybe we should consider other theories?
I'm in green quad 4-11. Need a pick-up!
Copy, Hershey. I have Central for you.
Patch it to my Lawmaster.
Oh my God!
The latest report: 96 Judges assassinated!
Someone knows our procedures, our security
measures, even our scrambled frequencies!
No Judges on the streets riots break out.
We can't replace those Judges!
Even ifwe put the cadets on the streets!
There is a solution.
Project Janus.
The Council tried to play God once before.
Lfthis wholesale slaughter of Judges
continues, there won't be a Council!
Janus could.
- Janus could what?
A new bath oftest tube babies won't solve
this crisis! We don't need reliable Judges
20 years from now. We needed them today!
Accelerated growth incubators
are more developed now.
We could create adult subjects.
I'm only asking to unlock the Janus files.
That way we at least have an option!
Lfthe Council decides not to go forward,
I'll accept that decision. And resign.
You ready, kid?
- No! Now what's wrong?
What's wrong? Did this helmet compress
your brain? You're going to get me killed!
There's a maniac loose in the city!
- What a coincidence! One's out here, too!
Oh!
- Great time I'm having!
The shuttle crash! The Cursed Earth!
Cannibals! And now a fireball up my ass!
All your fault! - My fault? Yes!
- You care to explain that?
Lfyou hadn't arrested me,
I wouldn't be here in the first place!
Hey Dredd, why don't you just kill me now?
That's it! I'm through schlepping!
I'm going to stay here until I'm caught.
Or until you apologize!
- The law can't!
That's just it! You're not the law
anymore! Now apologize! I deserve that!
I've never apologized.
Now run!
30, 29, 28, 27!
Run!
- 25, 24, 23,
22, 21, 20, 19!
Dredd! Dredd!
Dredd! No!
Run!
I'm alive! I'm alive!
Oh, so are you.
Esposito, Carlos. Council Judge.
Authorize access to file. Code name Janus.
Acknowledged.
McGruder, Evelyn.
Authorize access to file. Code name Janus.
Acknowledged.
Silver, Gerald.
Authorized access to file code name Janus.
Removing security blocks now. Awaiting
password command from Chief Justice.
Password: "origin".
Janus file open.
I'm lost. Is this the bathroom?
- Hey.
Now you have to admit, I helped out
on that one. I mean that was all me, baby.
Central, using current technology,
how long would it take for Janus
to produce a fully grown adult subject?
Using genetic engineering,
an adult subject could be incubated
in approximately 8 hours.
- We could replace our losses in a day!
Madness!
Dredd. - Silence!
Dredd.
Dredd!
- Silence!
It's inhuman.
It's not for this Counsel to play God!
No, Griffin, restore the security blocks.
It seems none of you have the force
ofwill that these times require.
Central. Leave Janus unlocked!
Griffin, this is treason!
You have just sealed your fate.
No! You have just sealed yours!
Rico!
Who says politics is boring?
Hey, Dredd. I thought it was you!
That's right! Cover your ears!
Joseph!
Get outta here! Now!
Oh, you son of a…
- No!
You're under arrest, Griffin.
- Really?
Stop him! He killed the entire Counsel!
Move it out!
- Dredd, tell them I'm innocent!
Come on, Fergie! Come on!
You're a lot offun to be with, Dredd,
you know that?
What do you do? Now what so we do?
Hope it works!
Shit!
- Work!
Dredd, you may want to wash this seat
after we get offthe bike.
Sorry. Dredd!
Cover the rear!
- I never fired a gun!
What kinda criminal are you?
- A nice criminal.
Nothing's happening!
- You got to cock it first, moron!
You didn't say anything about cocking!
She'll not get her cleaning deposit back!
I mean that's for sure!
It doesn't pay to be one ofyour friends.
Sorry!
Hands against the wall!
You know the drill.
Who are you? - Dredd said…
- Shut up!
What happened?
- Why don't you tell me?
We're dying out there!
148 Judges in 48 hours!
What the hell is going on?
Do you think I'm part ofthis?
- I don't know who or what you are!
I would never do anything to her.
Nothin'.
All right.
You tell me about him.
You make me believe in you
like I did when I defended you!
His name is Rico. And he's my brother.
The DNA sample has been taken out of
frozen stasis. Ready for cloning process.
We got a slight change of plans here.
I want to take the existing DNA sample
right now and trash it.
Activate this DNA sampling counsel.
What are you doing?
- Central! Take this DNA sample!
Now!
- This wasn't part of our plan!
Griffin would have never authorized this!
Griffin got to be my keeper
by putting me behind bars.
What's your excuse?
He said I had no feelings and no emotions.
Now you know why.
- Dredd.
Look at me.
The Janus Project didn't do that to you.
You did that to yourself.
Sorry, guys, I'm getting nowhere with
your terminal! But I fixed the microwave.
Is this a bad time?
Hey, look, I tried dialing everything
I could think ofto find this Janus thing.
It isn't in the program! Nowhere! Nothing!
They won't put it on the computer network,
but they need power.
They've to steal it. So check every sector
for blackouts and sudden power surges.
Let's stay here longer!
- Wait a second!
There was a big power surge just before
they blew up my Lawmaster in sector 4!
Three blocks wide!
The last time I felt something like that
they shut down the whole power grid.
- But they moved the statue of Liberty
and put it on top of it.
- Could we go?
Dredd? That's twice you owe me.
Rico! Dredd got away from the hunters.
He's about to be seriously outnumbered.
Right, Central?
Affirmative.
The new DNA samples have been multiplexed.
And the gametes are already diving.
- New sample?
You left that DNA there for over 30 years.
Somebody has to clean out the fridge.
We made the sample from the best specimens
on the Council of Judges!
What did you replace it with?
No. My God.
You know you should congratulate me
because I'm about to become a daddy.
And you're being very rude!
You don't know what you're doing!
- The next batch of Janus Judges
are going to be my brothers and sisters!
And mine to control!
- Just stop all this!
Central! Help me!
I'm sorry, Chief Justice, the ABC robot
is not tied into my main processors.
That's right, Griff. You know
you got to get with this high-tech stuff?
- Robot! Rip his arms and legs off.
- No!
And you save his head for last!
I don't want him to miss anything!
You stay here.
- I wanta go with you.
You need me to shut down the Janus system.
We're a team! We could use some work,
but we're still a team.
I'll handle it.
- I bring you luck!
Luck?
You are still alive, Dredd.
- Hm.
I'm getting a signal.
Jesus Christ!
Get back!
Dredd!
Drop the gun.
Robot? On the count ofthree,
break her neck. One, two.
No!
Hershey.
I'm still here.
How romantic.
Step inside.
He looks a lot like you.
He is a lot like me.
- I'm nothing like you.
The only difference about us is:
You destroyed your life
to embrace the law.
And I destroy the law to embrace life.
And speaking of life.
Send in the clones.
Behold.
This is where you were born.
You feel that magic?
You must have known. All along.
You were different.
Fergie?
Are you still alive?
- Technically yes.
Your brother and your sister
will be born in two hours.
One big, endless supply of perfection!
We have a choice. We can stand here
and create a whole race of goddamn
brainwashed morons. And call them Judges!
Or create some free-thinking people?
We'll call them human.
Human.
You could never control yourself.
What makes you think
you can control these things?
Because you're in control.
You'll be head ofthe Counsel. You choose.
And you choose quickly, too.
I shall put you down myself. Personally.
You know, I never understood that!
Why did you judge me?
Why?
- You killed innocent people!
The means to an end!
- A massacre!
A revolution!
- You betrayed the law!
No! I betrayed this!
You are Counsel's experiment which failed!
In you!
I was your brother, blood and friend!
Who betrayed who? When will you stop
being the goddamn slave and grow up!
That's your birth right, your family!
I'm your family! The only family you had!
Now choose!
The best thing that you can do: Kill me.
Why?
Because it's your only chance,
brother!
Fido!
Rip this bitche's arms and legs off!
Save her head for my brother!
- No!
Halt!
Rip his head off instead! Give it to her!
What's a matter with you?
Rico!
Boy, is he pissed!
- Fergie!
Dredd!
Hack you, asshole!
Rico!
Central, hatch the first set of clones!
- The process is not finished.
The clones will be only 60% complete.
I need reinforcements!
Hatch the goddamn clones! Now!
Fight girls much? Do ya?
Bitch!
Judge Bitch!
I'm the only one who never lied to you.
I'll be the Judge ofthat!
Now, Joseph Dredd, I herebyjudge you.
The charge: Betraying your flesh.
Guilty! And the charge of being human!
When we coulda been Gods!
Guilty.
The sentence is death.
- Don't miss.
Lethal rounds exhausted.
Phaser flare!
Court's adjourned.
Dredd!
Give me your hand.
Stand back, Hershey.
Am I under arrest?
That won't be necessary.
Central broadcasted Janus plan after
Griffin's death. They all know the truth.
Judge Dredd.
We have to reconstitute the Counsel.
We would like you to consider
the first position of Chief Justice.
I'm a Street Judge.
Mr. Olmeyer.
I'm dying. I'm too young to… Excuse me!
Oh, that's great, he's the number one!
Dredd?
I told him everything he knows.
Dredd? That's it?
A mere death experience and no goodbye?
- Goodbye, Hershey.
It goes without saying that I kiss better.
Ow! Come on, guys, let's get going!
Feels good to be human, don't you
think?
I knew you'd say that.