Hurry!
Do you not understand?
Krypton's core is collapsing.
We may only have a matter of weeks.
I warned you.
Harvesting the core was suicide.
It has accelerated...
- ...the process of implosion.
- Our energy reserves...
...were exhausted.
What would you have us do, El?
Look to the stars, like our ancestors did.
There are habitable worlds within reach.
We can begin by using the old outposts.
Are you seriously suggesting
that we evacuate the entire planet?
No. Everybody here is already dead.
Give me control of the Codex.
I will ensure the survival of our race.
There is still hope.
I have held that hope in my hands.
This council has been disbanded.
On whose authority?
Mine.
The rest of you will be tried
and punished accordingly.
- What are you doing, Zod? This is madness.
- What I should have done...
...years ago.
These lawmakers...
...with their endless debates...
...have lead Krypton to ruin.
And if your forces prevail...
- ...you'll be the leader of nothing.
- Then join me.
Help me save our race. We'll start anew.
We'll sever...
...the degenerative bloodlines
that led us to this state.
And who will decide
which bloodlines survive, Zod?
You?
Don't do this, El.
The last thing I want
is for us to be enemies.
You have abandoned the principles
that bound us together.
You've taken up the sword...
...against your own people.
I will honor the man you once were, Zod...
...not this monster you've become.
Take him away.
Sir? Is everything all right?
Out of the way.
I said...
Get me Lara.
Jor. Behind you.
Lara, you have to ready the launch.
I'll be with you as soon as I can.
H'Raka!
Hyah!
- Can you see the Codex?
- It's just beneath the central hub.
But I'm compelled to warn you.
Breaching the genesis chamber
is a Class-B crime...
Nobody cares anymore, Kelex.
The world is about to come to an end.
Jor-El, by the
authority of General Zod...
...surrender the Codex.
Unh!
Ahhh!
Easy, H'Raka.
Did you find a world?
- We have.
- Orbiting a main sequence yellow star...
...just as you said it would.
A young star.
His cells will drink its radiation.
It's a seemingly intelligent population.
He'll be an outcast.
A freak.
They'll kill him.
How?
He'll be a god to them.
What if the ship doesn't make it?
He'll die out there...
...alone.
I can't do it.
I thought I could, but...
- Lara.
...now that he's here...
Krypton is doomed.
It's his only chance now.
It's our people's only hope.
What is it, Kelex?
Five attack ships
converging from the east.
Citadel's defenses
are being scanned and evaluated.
I'll upload the Codex.
No, wait.
Lara.
Just let me look at him.
We'll never get to see him walk.
Never hear him say our names.
But out there...
...amongst the stars...
...he will live.
Goodbye, my son.
Our hopes and dreams travel with you.
Concentrate fire on the main doors.
Lady Lara.
- The phantom drives are coming online.
- Proceed to ignition.
General.
We have identified an engine ignition
within the citadel.
A launch.
Hold this platform, commander.
I know you stole the Codex, Jor-El.
Surrender it...
...and I'll let you live.
This is a second chance
for all of Krypton...
...not just the bloodlines you deem worthy.
What have you done?
We've had a child, Zod.
A boy child.
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
And he will be free.
Free to forge his own destiny.
Heresy.
Destroy it.
Ah!
Lara...
...listen to me.
The Codex is Krypton's future.
Abort the launch.
No!
Your son, Lara...
...where have you sent him?
His name...
...is Kal...
...son of El.
And he's beyond your reach.
Bring that ship down.
Target locked.
Lay down your weapons.
Your forces are surrounded.
General Zod...
...for the crimes
of murder and high treason...
...the Council has sentenced you
and your fellow insurgents...
...to three hundred cycles
of somatic reconditioning.
Do you have any last words?
You won't kill us yourself!
You wouldn't sully your hands!
But you'll damn us...
...to a black hole for eternity!
Jor-El was right.
You're a pack of fools,
every last one of you.
And you.
You believe your son is safe?
I will find him.
I will reclaim
what you have taken from us.
I will find him.
I will find him, Lara.
I will find him!
Argh!
Lady Lara, shouldn't
you find refuge?
There is no refuge, Kelor.
Jor-El was right.
This is the end.
Make a better world than ours, Kal.
Watch it, dumb-ass!
Keep your eyes open
or you're gonna get squashed.
Where the hell did they find you,
greenhorn?
Let's get this trap in the air.
Gentlemen, secure the deck.
We just got a distress call
from a rig due west of us.
Secure the deck.
All civilian boats, stand clear.
The sub-sea valves failed
and the rig is about to explode.
Roger, Coast Guard.
What about the men left inside?
- Forget them. They're dead.
- Greenhorn...
...fetch me my binoculars.
Greenhorn.
This is the last of the oxygen. I don't
know how much longer we can hold out.
This is Coast Guard 6510.
We'll make one more pass then get out.
Wait, wait.
I got some guys on the helipad.
Right here!
Come on, come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
- Let's go!
Get that last guy loaded.
We have got to go.
Hey, let's go. What are you doing?
Go! Go!
Argh!
...when Kansas
became a territory?
Clark.
Are you listening, Clark?
I asked if you could tell me who first...
...settled Kansas.
Are you all right, Clark?
Clark.
Clark!
Clark, come out of there.
Leave me alone.
Clark, I have called your mother.
Clark?
Ah!
I'm here.
Clark, honey, it's Mom.
Will you open the door?
- What's wrong with him?
- He's such a freak.
Crybaby.
His parents won't even let him play
with other kids.
I know.
Sweetie.
How can I help you if you won't let me in?
The world's too big, Mom.
Then make it small.
Just, um...
...focus on my voice.
Pretend ifs an island...
...out in the ocean.
Can you see it?
I see it.
Then swim towards it, honey.
What's wrong with me, Mom?
Clark.
- Did you get everything I need?
- Yep.
Hold it, hold it.
Hey, ass-wipe.
What do you think? You see the game?
- Leave him alone, Pete.
- What are you, his girlfriend?
I wanna hear what he has to say.
Come on...
...dick-splash.
My son was there.
He was in the bus.
- He saw what Clark did.
- I know he did.
- I'm sure what he thought he saw was...
- Was an act of God, Jonathan.
This was providence.
I think you're blowing
it out of proportion.
No, I'm not. Lana saw it too.
And the Fordham boy.
This isn't the first time...
...Clark's done something like this.
I just wanted to help.
I know you did, but we talked about this.
Right?
Right? We talked about this. You have...
Clark, you have to keep this side
of yourself a secret.
What was I supposed to do?
Just let them die?
Maybe.
There's more at stake here than just our
lives, Clark, or the lives of those around us.
When the world...
When the world finds out what you can do
it's gonna change everything. Our...
Our beliefs, our notions of...
...what it means to be human.
Everything.
You saw how Pete's mom reacted, right?
She was scared, Clark.
Why?
People are afraid
of what they don't understand.
Is she right?
Did God do this to me?
Tell me.
We found you in this.
We were sure the government
was gonna show up on our doorstep...
...but no one ever came.
This was in that chamber with you.
I took it to a metallurgist...
...at Kansas State.
He said whatever it was made from
didn't even...
Didn't even exist on the periodic table.
That's another way of saying...
...that it's not from this world, Clark.
And neither are you.
You're the answer, son.
You're the answer to
"Are we alone in the universe?"
I don't wanna be.
And I don't blame you, son.
It'd be a huge burden for anyone to bear.
But you're not just anyone, Clark,
and I have to believe that you were...
That you were sent here for a reason.
All these changes that you're
going through, one day...
One day you're gonna think of them
as a blessing. When that day comes...
...you have to make a choice.
A choice of whether to stand proud
in front of the human race or not.
Can't I just keep pretending I'm your son?
You are my son.
But somewhere out there you've...
You have another father too,
who gave you another name.
And he sent you here...
...for a reason, Clark.
And even if it takes you the rest of
your life, you owe it to yourself...
...to find out what that reason is.
Bound by wild desire
I fell into a ring of fire
Wait a second.
Aren't you here for the exercise?
No, there was a change in the plans.
Somebody found something
strange on Ellesmere.
- Aircom's making runs out there all week.
- That rat hole?
- You gotta be kidding me.
- I know. It's crazy.
The Americans are there too,
lots of them.
Anything else? They're
calling it an anomalous object.
- Whatever that means.
- Back off, Ludlow. I'm serious.
- Oh, come on, Chrissy.
- Knock it off.
- Sit down.
- Let me go.
Hey. Leave her alone, man.
Or what, tough guy?
Or I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
I think I'll probably just leave
when I'm good and ready.
Ooh.
Oh, there he is.
It's not worth it, sweetie.
Hey, asshole,
don't forget your tip.
Strike.
Thanks.
Hi.
Miss Lane. How you doing?
- Good.
- Jed Eubanks, Arctic Cargo.
How far to the station?
- Camp's just over the rise. I'll walk you over.
- Great.
Joe can take your bags. Joe.
Help her out.
Careful with those. They're heavy.
I gotta confess, Miss Lane...
...I'm not a fan of the Daily Planet.
But those pieces you wrote when you were
embedded with the 1st Division were...
Well, they were pretty impressive.
Well, what can I say? I get writer's block
if I'm not wearing a flak jacket.
Miss Lane.
I'm Colonel Hardy, U.S. Northcom.
Dr. Emil Hamilton...
...from DARPA.
- You're early.
- Hi.
We were expecting you tomorrow.
Which is why I showed up today.
Look, let's get one thing straight,
guys, okay?
The only reason I'm here
is because we're on Canadian soil...
...and the appellate court overruled
your injunction to keep me away.
So if we're done measuring dicks...
...can you have your people
show me what you found?
NASA's EOS satellites...
...pinged the anomaly first.
The ice shelf plays hell
on the echo soundings.
- But there's something there.
- A submarine, maybe?
Soviet-era?
Doubtful. That's 300 meters.
Considerably larger than anything
we know they built back then.
But herds the spooky pan.
The ice surrounding the object...
...it's nearly twenty thousand years old.
Miss Lane?
Try not to wander.
Temperatures drop to minus 40
at night around here.
Wouldn't find your body till after spring.
And there you go.
What if I need to tinkle?
There's a bucket in the corner.
Where the hell are you going?
Hello?
It's all right, it's all right,
it's all right. It's all right.
You're hemorrhaging internally...
...and if I don't cauterize this bleed...
How can...?
I can do things that other people can't.
Now hold my hand.
This is gonna hurt.
What Colonel Hardy
and his team surmised...
...was a Soviet-era submarine...
...was actually something
much more exotic.
An isotope analysis of the surrounding
ice bores suggests that an object...
...had been trapped in the glacier
for over 18,000 years.
As for my rescuer?
He disappeared during
the object's departure...
A background check revealed
that his work history...
...and identity had been falsified.
The questions raised by my rescuer's...
...existence are frightening
to contemplate...
...but I also know what I saw.
"And I have arrived
at the inescapable conclusion...
...that the object and its occupant...
...did not originate on Earth."
I can't print this, Lois.
You might have hallucinated half of it.
What about the contractors
who corroborated...
- ...my story?
- The Pentagon is denying that there was a ship.
Of course they are. They're supposed to.
It's the Pentagon.
Perry, it's me we're talking about.
- I'm a Pulitzer Prize-winning reporter.
- Then act like it.
- Print it or I walk.
- You can't.
You're under contract.
I'm not running a story
about aliens walking among us.
Never gonna happen.
That's a Scotch, straight-up, for the lady.
I'm sending you the article.
My editor won't print it,
but if it leaked online...
Got it.
But didn't you once describe my site...
...as a creeping cancer of falsehoods?
I stand by my words, Woodburn,
but I want this story...
- ...out there.
- Why?
Because I want my mystery man
to know I know the truth.
Recursive diagnostics complete...
Guiding presence authenticated.
All systems operational.
To see you standing there
having grown into an adult...
If only Lara could have witnessed this.
Who are you?
I am your father, Kal.
Or at least a shadow of him.
His consciousness.
My name was Jor-El.
And Kal?
That's my name.
Kal-El. It is.
I have so many questions.
Where do I come from?
Why did you send me here?
You came from Krypton.
A world with a much harsher environment
than Earths.
Long ago...
...in an era of expansion...
...our race spread out through the stars...
...seeking new worlds to settle upon.
This scout ship was
one of thousands launched into the void.
We built outposts on other planets...
musing great machines to reshape
environments to our needs.
For 100,000 years,
our civilization flourished...
...accomplishing wonders.
What happened?
Artificial population control
was established.
The outposts on space exploration
were abandoned.
We exhausted our natural resources.
As a result,
our planet's core became unstable.
Eventually, our military leader...
...General Zod, attempted a coup.
But by then it was too late.
Your mother and I foresaw
the coming calamity...
...and we took certain steps
to ensure your survival.
This is a genesis chamber.
All Kryptonians were conceived
in chambers such as this.
Every child was designed to fulfill
a pre-determined role in our society...
...as a worker...
...a warrior, a leader and so on.
Your mother and I believed Krypton
lost something precious.
The element of choice, of chance.
What if a child dreamed
of becoming something...
mother than what society
had intended for him or her?
What if a child aspired
to something greater?
You were the embodiment
of that belief, Kal.
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
That's why we risked so much to save you.
Why didn't you come with me?
We couldn't, Kal.
No matter how much...
...we wanted to.
No matter how much we loved you.
Your mother, Lara, and I...
...were a product of the failures
of our world as much as Zod was...
...tied to its fate.
- So I'm alone.
- No.
You're as much a child of Earth now
as you are of Krypton.
You can embody the best of both worlds.
A dream your mother and I
dedicated our lives to preserve.
The people of Earth
are different from us, it's true.
But, ultimately,
I believe that's a good thing.
They won't necessarily
make the same mistakes we did.
Not if you guide them, Kal.
Not if you give them hope.
That's what this symbol means.
The symbol of the house of El
means hope.
Embodied within that hope
is the fundamental belief...
...in the potential of every person
to be a force for good.
That's what you can bring them.
Why am I so different from them?
Earth's sun is younger and brighter
than Krypton's was.
Your cells have drunken its radiation...
...strengthening your muscles,
your skin, your senses.
Earth's gravity is weaker,
yet its atmosphere is more nourishing.
You've grown stronger here
than I ever could have imagined.
The only way to know how strong...
...is to keep testing your limits.
Unh!
Uh... Oh.
Whoa!
You will give the people of Earth
an ideal lo strive towards.
They'll race behind you.
They will stumble.
They will fall.
But In time...
...they will join you in the sun, Kal.
In time...
you will help them accomplish wonders.
How do you find someone who has
spent a lifetime covering his tracks?
You start with the urban legends...
- ...that have sprung up in his wake.
- That's Joe.
The friends of a friend...
- ...who have seen him.
- He worked here.
For some he was a guardian angel.
For others, a cipher...
...a ghost who never quite fit in.
Well, I was saying we were...
...coming towards the oil rig.
As you work your way back in time,
the stories form a pattern.
I'm looking for a Pete Ross.
Do you know him?
Yeah, he works at the IHOP.
If you go down the road...
Pete Ross?
I'd like to talk to you about an accident
when you were younger.
A school bus that went into the river.
Dusty. Shh-shh-shh.
Mrs. Kent?
I'm Lois Lane. I'm from the Daily Planet.
Quiet.
I'm from the Daily Planet
and I'd like to talk to you about your son.
I figured if I turned over enough stones
you'd eventually find me.
Where are you from?
What are you doing here?
Let me tell your story.
What if I don't want my story told?
It's going to come out eventually.
Somebody's going to get a photograph
or figure out where you live.
- Then I'll disappear again.
- The only way you could disappear...
...is to stop helping people altogether,
and I sense that's not an option for you.
My father believed that if the world
found out who I really was...
...they'd reject me...
...out of fear.
I'm tired of safe.
I just wanna do something useful
with my life.
So farming, feeding people.
That's not useful?
I didn't say that.
Our family's been farming
for five generations.
Your family, not mine.
I don't even know why I'm listening to you.
You're not my dad.
You're just some guy
who found me in a field.
Clark.
It's all right, Martha.
He's right. Clark has a point.
We're not your parents.
But we've been doing the best we can.
And we've been making this up
as we go along, so maybe...
Maybe our best
isn't good enough anymore.
Look, Dad...
Hold on.
Go for the overpass.
Go for the overpass!
Take cover! Take cover!
- Over there. Just follow them.
- Take cover.
She's stuck.
Hank's still in the car.
Hank's in the car.
- I'll get him, I'll get him.
- No, no.
Get your mom to the overpass.
Hank! Hank! Come!
Jonathan!
- Mom, ifs okay.
- Jonathan!
- Mom, stay here.
Dad!
I let my father die
because I trusted him.
Because he was convinced
that I had to wait.
That the world was not ready.
What do you think?
You better watch out, Lois.
Hey, Perry's gunning for you.
He knows you're Woodburn's anonymous source
and cannot wait to rip you a new one.
Oh, look at her. Ha, ha, ha.
I told you not to run with this,
and what do you do?
You let Woodburn just shotgun it
all over the Internet.
Now the publishers want me to sue you.
Well, if it makes a difference,
I'm dropping it.
Whoa, just like that?
Yep.
What happened to your leads?
They didn't pan out. The story is smoke.
Or it didn't get the traction you hoped?
Two weeks leave...
...no pay, that's your penance.
You try something like this again...
- ...you're done here.
- Fine.
Let's make it three weeks
since you're so willing to agree.
- Perry.
- No, no. Don't. Don't.
I believe you saw something, Lois.
But not for a moment do I believe
that your leads just went cold.
So whatever your reasons are
for dropping it...
...I think you're doing the right thing.
Why?
Can you imagine how people
on this planet would react...
...if they knew there was
someone like this out there?
Go get him.
Well, look at you.
A reporter came by here.
She's a friend. Don't worry.
Oh.
Mom.
- Heh, heh, heh.
- What?
- I found them.
- Who?
My parents.
My People.
I know where I come from now.
Wow.
That's wonderful.
I'm so happy for you, Clark.
- What?
- It's nothing.
When you were a baby I used to lay
by your crib at night...
...listening to you breathe.
It was hard for you.
You struggled.
And I worried all the time.
You worried the truth would come out.
No.
The truth about you is beautiful.
We saw that the moment
we laid eyes on you.
We knew that one day,
the whole world would see that.
I'm just...
I'm worried they'll take you away from me.
I'm not going anywhere, Mom.
I promise.
General Swanwick, sir.
What am I looking at, doc?
Comet? Asteroid?
Comets don't make
course corrections, general.
Wanted you to see this before some amateur
with a telescope creates a worldwide panic.
The ship appears to have...
...inserted itself into
a lunar synchronous orbit...
...though I have no idea why.
Have you tried... communicating with it?
Well, they haven't responded as of yet.
I'm just speculating, but I think
whoever's at the helm of that thing...
...is looking to make a dramatic entrance.
Anybody know where we keep the toner?
- What's going on?
- It's all over the news.
You gotta see this.
Clark.
Yeah?
Coming.
This is a breaking news. An unidentified...
You are not alone.
It's coming in on the RSS feeds.
It's on my phone too.
My name is General Zod.
I come from a world far from yours.
I have journeyed across
an ocean of stars to reach you.
For some time, your world
has sheltered one of my citizens.
I request that you return
this individual...
...to my custody.
For reasons unknown,
he has chosen to keep his existence...
...a secret from you.
He will have made efforts to blend in.
He will look like you.
But he is not one of you.
To those of you who may know...
...of his current location...
...the fate of your planet...
...rests in your hands.
To Kai-El, I say this:
Surrender within 24 hours...
...or watch this world
suffer the consequences...
Ah!
We hardly know anything
about him, isn't that right?
If he truly means us no harm...
...he'll turn himself in
and face the consequences.
And if he won't do that...
...then maybe we should.
The Daily Planet's Lois Lane
knows who this guy is. She's...
...the one we should
be questioning.
- Hold on. You're saying Lois Lane...
- Hello?
Are you watching this crap?
Been running all morning.
For once I agree with Woodburn.
Have you seen him?
- Do you know where he is?
- No. Even if I did, I wouldn't say.
The entire world is being threatened here.
This is not time for you to fall...
...back on journalistic integrity.
This is serious, Lois.
The FBI is here. They're throwing around
words like "treason."
I gotta go.
FBI. Hands up.
Drop the bag. Now.
Regarding the visitors
themselves we know...
...very little.
According to government officials...
...the visitors do not
represent a threat...
...despite the ominous tone
of their message.
Then of course there's the question
on everyone's mind:
"Who is this Kai-El person?
Does he actually exist?"
"How could he have remained
hidden from us for so long?"
Come on, Kent.
Come on. Fight back.
Get up, Kent.
So is that it?
Is that all you've got?
Come on, Kent.
Come on!
Did they hurl you?
You know they can't.
That's not what I meant.
I meant, are you all right?
I wanted to hit that kid.
I wanted to hit him bad.
I know you did. I mean...
...part of me even wanted you to,
but then what?
Make you feel any better?
You just have to decide what kind of man
you want to grow up to be, Clark.
Because whoever that man is,
good character or bad, he's...
He's gonna change the world.
What's on your mind?
I don't know where to start.
Wherever you want.
That ship that appeared last night.
I'm the one they're looking for.
Do you know...
...why they want you?
No. But this General Zod...
...even if I surrender, there's no
guarantee he'll keep his word, but...
...if there's a chance I can save Earth
by turning myself in...
...shouldn't I take it?
What does your gut tell you?
Zod can't be trusted.
The problem is...
...I'm not sure the people of Earth
can be either.
Sometimes you have to take
a leap of faith first.
The trust part comes later.
All right. You've got our attention.
What is it you want?
I would like to speak to Lois Lane.
What makes you think she's here?
Don't play games with me, general.
I'll surrender, but only if you
guarantee Lois's freedom.
Why are you surrendering to Zod?
I'm surrendering to mankind.
There's a difference.
You let them handcuff you?
Wouldn't be much of a surrender
if I resisted.
And if it makes them feel more secure...
...then all the better for it.
What's the S stand for?
It's not an S.
On my world it means hope.
Well, here, it's an S.
How about...
...Super...
Sir?
- Hi, my name is Dr. E...
- Emil Hamilton.
I know, I can see your ID tag
in your breast pocket.
Along with a half-eaten roll of Lifesavers.
I can also see the soldiers
in the next room...
...preparing that tranquilizing agent
of yours.
You won't need it.
Sir, you can't expect us
to not take precautions.
You could be carrying
some kind of alien pathogen.
Been here for 33 years, doctor.
- Haven't infected anyone yet.
- That you know of. We have legitimate...
...security concerns. You revealed
your identity to Miss Lane over there.
Why won't you do the same with us?
Let's put our cards on the table here,
general.
You're scared because you can't control me.
You don't, and you never will.
But that doesn't' mean I'm your enemy.
Then who is?
Zod?
That's what I'm worried about.
Be that as it may...
...I've been given orders
to hand you over to him.
Do what you have to do, general.
Thank you.
For what?
For believing in me.
Didn't make much difference in the end.
It did to me.
They're coming.
You should leave now.
Go, Lois.
Kal-El.
I'm sub-commander Faora-UI.
On behalf of General Zod,
I extend you his greetings.
- Are you the ranking officer here?
- I am.
General Zod would like this woman...
...to accompany me.
You asked for the alien.
You didn't say anything
about one of our own.
Shall I tell the general
you're unwilling to comply?
I don't care what you tell him.
It's all right.
I'll go.
The atmospheric composition on our ship
is not compatible with humans.
You need to wear a breather...
...beyond this point.
Kal-El.
You have no idea how long...
...we've been searching for you.
I take it you're Zod?
General Zod.
- Our commander.
- It's all right, Faora.
We can forgive Kal any lapses in decorum.
He's a stranger to our ways.
This should be cause...
...for celebration, not conflict.
- Unh.
- Not conflict.
I...
...feel strange.
Weak.
What's happening to him?
He's rejecting our
ship's atmospherics.
Clark.
You've spent a lifetime
adapting to Earth's ecology...
...but never adapted to ours.
Help him.
I can't. Whatever's happening...
- ...has to run its course.
- Clark.
Help him.
Hello, Kal.
Or do you prefer Clark?
That's the name they gave you.
Isn't it?
I was Krypton's military leader...
...your father our foremost scientist.
The only thing we agreed on...
...was that Krypton was dying.
In return for my efforts...
...to protect our civilization...
...and save our planet...
...I and my fellow officers
were sentenced to the Phantom Zone.
And then the
destruction of our world...
...freed us.
We were adrift, destined to float...
...amongst the ruins of our planet...
...until we starved.
How did you find your way to Earth?
We managed to retrofit
the phantom projector into a hyperdrive.
Your father made a similar modification
to the craft that brought you here.
And so the instrument of our damnation...
...became our salvation.
We sought out the old colonial outposts...
...looking for signs of life.
But all we found was death.
Cut off from Krypton, these outposts...
...withered and died long ago.
We salvaged what we could...
...armor, weapons...
...even a world engine.
For 33 years we prepared...
...until finally we detected
a distress beacon...
...which you triggered...
...when you accessed
the ancient scout ship.
You led us here, Kal.
Now it's within your power...
...to save what remains of your race.
On Krypton...
...the genetic template
for every being yet to be born...
...is encoded in the registry of citizens.
Your father stole the registry's Codex...
...and stored it in the capsule
that brought you here.
For what purpose?
So that Krypton can live again...
...on Earth.
Where is the Codex, Kal?
If Krypton lives again...
...what happens to Earth?
The foundation has to be
built on something.
Even your father recognized that.
No, Zod.
I can't be a part of this.
Then what can you be a part of?
No!
Zod!
Your father acquitted...
...himself with honor, Kal.
You killed him?
I did.
And not a day goes by
where it doesn't haunt me.
But if I had to do it again, I would.
I have a duty to my people...
...and I will not allow anyone
to prevent me from carrying it out.
What's the sit-rep, major?
DSP pinged two bogeys
launching from the alien ship.
- Put it up.
- Yes, sir.
There it is.
Re-task IKon-4...
- ...and get me a closer look.
- Yes, sir.
Command, the word...
...of the day is trident.
We have two alien craft
on aggressive approach.
Ikon-4 coming online.
Air speed?
380 knots, entering Kansas...
...airspace.
Not responding to our hails.
You're wasting your efforts.
The strength you derived
from the Earth's sun...
...has been neutralized aboard our ship.
Here...
...in this environment...
...you are as weak as a human.
Unh!
Where did you come from?
The command key, Miss Lane.
Thanks to you, I'm uploading
to the ship's mainframe.
Who are you?
I am Kai's father.
Can you help us?
I designed this ship.
I can modify its atmospheric composition...
...to human compatibility.
We can stop them.
We can send them back
to the Phantom Zone.
How?
I can teach you.
And in turn, you can teach Kal.
Will you help me?
The ship's crew are alerted.
We need to move quickly.
Retrieve the command key.
- Did you do that?
- Yes. Pick up her sidearm.
What's happening?
To your right.
Fire.
Behind you.
Secure yourself inside the open pod.
Safe travels, Miss Lane. It's unlikely...
...we'll see each other again.
Remember, the phantom drives
are essential in stopping them.
Move your head to the left.
Is it true what Zod said about the Codex?
Strike that panel.
We wanted you to learn...
...what it meant to be human first...
...so that one day, when the time was
right, you could be the bridge...
...between two peoples.
Look.
Lois.
You can save her, Kal.
You can save all of them.
You'll be safe here.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I didn't wanna tell them anything,
but they did something to me.
- They looked inside my mind...
- It's okay, Lois.
They did the same thing to me.
Clark!
The craft he arrived in...
...where is it?
Go to hell.
There.
Unh!
The Codex is not here.
Argh!
Ah!
Where has he hidden it?
I don't know.
Where is the Codex?!
Ahh!
You think you can threaten my mother?!
Ah!
What have you done to me?
My parents taught me to hone...
...my senses, Zod.
Focus...
...on just what I wanted to see.
Without your helmet...
...you're getting everything.
Unh!
And it hurts...
...doesn't it?
Argh!
Get away from the window.
Get inside. It's not safe.
All players, this is
Guardian. I am airborne mission commander.
I have previously encountered
and observed...
...the beings we're about to engage.
They are extremely dangerous
and we have been authorized...
...to use deadly force.
Roger, Guardian,
we are inbound to target.
Cleared hot. Weapons free.
Copy, 11. Weapons free.
Thunder 11...
...tally three targets.
Unh!
Thunder 11...
...good hit.
Request immediate re-attack.
Roger, Guardian.
We'll make a second gun run...
...on a heading of 212 degrees.
Thunder 11, eject!
Eject!
I have a bogey incoming!
Oh, shit.
Argh!
You are weak...
...son of El.
Unsure of yourself.
The fact that you possess
a sense of morality...
...and we do not...
...gives us an evolutionary advantage.
And if history has proven anything...
...it is that evolution always wins.
Ragh!
Unh!
CCT, we're approaching...
...LZ Jayhawk. Get down in five.
Let's go. Go to the LZ.
Roger, sarge. let's go!
All rangers, I need you...
...to engage the targets.
Guardian, this is Badger 01.
What about the guy in blue?
I said engage...
...all targets.
Contact. Contact.
Ah!
You okay?
We're auto-rotating, going in hard.
Brace for impact.
We're going in hard!
Fallen angel. Fallen angel. Guardian
is down. I repeat, Guardian is down.
Guardian, do you read?
Thunder 12, calling Guardian.
- Do you read?
- Thunder 12...
...this is Guardian.
Put down everything you've got
north of my position.
- This will be danger-close.
- Copy, danger-close.
Good luck, sir.
A good death is its own reward.
You will not win.
For every human you save...
...we will kill a million more. Unh!
Do we have an all clear?
Alpha team, sit-rep. Alpha team.
Do you copy? Alpha team.
This man is not our enemy.
Thank you, colonel.
Mom?
I'm all right.
Nice suit, son.
I'm so sorry.
It's only stuff, Clark.
It can always be replaced.
But you can't be.
Mom, Zod said this Codex...
...he's looking for can
bring my people back.
Isn't that a good thing?
I don't think they're interested
in sharing this world.
Clark.
I know how to stop them.
What happened down there?
He exposed a temporary weakness.
It is of little consequence...
...because I have located the Codex.
It was never in the capsule.
Jor-el took the Codex...
...the DNA of a billion people,
then he bonded it...
...within his son's individual...
...cells.
All of Krypton's heirs...
...living hidden in one refugee's body.
Does Kal-El need to be alive...
...for us to extract the
Codex from his cells?
No.
Release the world engine.
What just happened?
The ship just split in two.
Track one is heading east,
track two to the southern hemisphere.
- How fast is that bogey moving?
- Approaching...
...Mach 24 and accelerating.
It's gonna impact
somewhere in the Indian Ocean.
The rest of the ship is descending.
Put it on the board now.
Yes, sir.
Oh, my God.
Bring the phantom drive online.
We are now slave to the world engine.
Initiate.
- What have they hit us with?
- Looks like some kind of gravity...
...weapon.
It's working in tandem with their ship.
Somehow they're increasing
the Earth's mass...
...clouding the atmosphere
with particulates.
Oh, my God.
They're terraforming.
What's that?
Planetary engineering...
...modifying the Earth's atmosphere
and topography.
Turning Earth into Krypton.
- But what happens to us?
- Based on these readings...
...there won't be an "us."
General Swanwick, sir.
I'm on with the control tower.
Colonel Hardy's on his way
and he's got Superman in tow.
Superman?
The alien, sir.
That's what they're calling him.
Superman.
We have a plan, general.
Is that what I think it is?
It's the ship he arrived in.
This ship is powered by something
called a phantom drive.
It bends space.
Zod's ship uses the same technology, and
if we can make the two drives collide...
A singularity can be created.
- Like a black hole.
- Yes.
So if we open up this doorway...
...they should be pulled back in.
So you want us to bomb them with that?
General, that craft maxes out...
...17,000 pounds,
we can drop it from a C-17.
It's a viable plan.
If I don't stop that machine
over the Indian Ocean...
...the gravity field will continue...
...to expand.
If that thing is making Earth
more like Krypton...
...won't you be weaker around it?
Maybe.
I'm not about to let that
stop me from trying.
You might want to step back a little bit.
Maybe a little bit more.
Faora.
Take command.
- Yes, sir.
- I need to secure the genesis chamber...
...and pay my respects to an old friend.
Guardian en route to Metropolis...
...package in tow.
Be advised,
F-35s inbound to rendezvous point.
You should have visual contact now.
Command key accepted.
Genesis chamber coming online, sir.
Stop this, Zod...
...while there's still time.
Haven't given up lecturing me,
have you, even in death?
I will not let you use the Codex like this.
You don't have the power to stop me.
The command key I have entered
is revoking your authority.
This ship is now under my control.
Northcom, Lightning 1, request...
...permission to unleash the hounds.
Lightning 1...
...you are clear to engage. Send battle
damage assessment when able. Out.
Avionics are going haywire.
The gravity field...
...is pulling our missiles down.
We gotta get closer.
All right, everybody...
...we're leaving.
We're leaving the building now.
I just lost my wingman.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
Everybody, this way! Come on!
Everybody, come on!
Keep moving, keep moving.
Jenny!
Oh, my God.
Perry!
Go! There! Go!
Our people can co-exist.
So we can suffer through years of pain
trying to adapt like your son has?
- You're talking about genocide.
- Yes.
And I'm arguing its merits with a ghost.
We're both ghosts, Zod.
Can't you see that?
The Krypton you're clinging onto is gone.
Ship, have you managed to quarantine
this invasive intelligence?
- You'll fail.
- I have.
Then prepare to terminate it.
- I'm tired of this debate.
Silencing me...
...won't change anything.
My son...
...is twice the man you were.
And he will finish what we started.
I can promise you that.
Tell me...
...you have Jor-El's memories,
his conscience.
Can you experience...
...his pain?
I will harvest the Codex
from your son's corpse...
...and I will rebuild Krypton...
...atop his bones.
Argh!
Jenny.
- Jenny. Jenny, where are you?
- I'm here!
- I'm here. Here.
- Jenny.
Hold on, hold on.
I'm stuck.
- I can't get free. I'm stuck.
- Okay.
We'll get you out of there, all right?
Just sit tight.
No, no, no!
- Don't leave me.
- We're not gonna leave you.
- Okay.
- Lombard!
- Get your ass over here and help me.
- Damn it.
- We just gotta move this.
- Here.
Slide that in. You push, I'll pull, okay?
Go.
- Push!
- Oh, my God.
It's getting closer!
Come on, push!
Northcom, this is Guardian.
Are we cleared?
Negative, Guardian.
Come on! Push!
Ahh!
Argh!
He did it.
Northcom, this is Guardian.
We're passing through phase line red.
Good to go.
Godspeed, Guardian.
Arm the package. You are cleared hot.
We're lining up for the final run.
It's up to you and Hamilton now.
You gotta be kidding me.
Loadmaster, is the package...
...ready to drop?
Negative, Guardian.
There's something wrong.
It's not supposed to do this.
What's it supposed to do?
- It's supposed to go in all the way.
- Let me take a look.
Co-pilot's aircraft.
We are lined up for the drop.
What's the hold up?
We've had a setback.
Target that aircraft.
Target locked.
Stop!
If you destroy this ship...
...you destroy Krypton!
Krypton had its chance.
Argh!
Miss Lane! It's not safe for you...
...over there!
Miss Lane!
Ah!
Move now! Go!
A good death...
...is its own reward.
Ah!
Argh!
Are they gone?
I think so.
He saved us.
You know, they say it's all downhill
after the first kiss.
I'm pretty sure that only counts
when you're kissing a human.
Look at this.
We could have built a new Krypton...
...in this squalor.
But you chose the humans over us.
I exist...
...only to protect Krypton.
That is the sole purpose
for which I was born.
And every action I take...
...no matter how violent...
...or how cruel...
...is for the greater good...
...of my people.
And now...
...I have no people.
My soul...
...that is what you have taken...
...from me.
I'm going to make them suffer, Kal.
These humans you've adopted,
I will take them all from you...
- ...one by one.
- You're a monster, Zod...
...and I'm gonna stop you.
Argh!
There's only...
...one way this ends, Kal.
Either you die...
...or I do.
Unh!
I was bred to be a warrior, Kal.
Trained my entire life...
...to master my senses.
Where did you train? On a farm?
Argh!
If you love...
...these people so much...
...you can mourn for them.
Don't do this!
Stop!
Never.
Ahh!
Are you effing stupid?
It's one of
your surveillance drones.
That's a $12,000,000
piece of hardware.
It was.
I know you're trying to find out
where I hang my cape.
- You won't.
- Then I'll ask...
...the obvious question:
How do we know you won't one day
act against America's interests?
I grew up in Kansas, general.
I'm about as American as it gets.
Look...
...I'm here to help...
...but it has to be on my own terms.
You have to convince Washington of that.
Even if I were willing to try,
what makes you think they'd listen?
I don't know, general.
Guess I'll just have to trust you.
What are you smiling about?
Nothing, sir.
I just think he's kind of hot.
- Get in the car, captain.
- Mm-hm. Yes, sir.
He always believed
you were meant for greater things.
And that when the day came...
...your shoulders would be able
to bear the weight.
Yeah, I just wish he could have
been here to see it finally happen.
He saw it, Clark, believe me.
What are you going to do
when you're not saving the world?
- Have you given any thought to that?
- I have, actually. Heh, heh.
I gotta find a job
where I can keep my ear to the ground.
Where people won't look twice...
...when I want to go somewhere dangerous
and start asking questions...
Come on, Lois.
When are you gonna throw me a bone?
Courtside seats to the game tonight.
- What do you say?
- I say...
...you should go back
to trolling the intern pool.
You'll probably have more luck. Sorry.
Courtside?
- Don't. Ha, ha, ha.
- No.
Lombard, Lane,
I want you to meet our new stringer.
I want you to show him the ropes.
This is Clark Kent.
Good luck, kid.
Hey. Steve.
- Nice to meet you.
- You too.
Hi.
Lois Lane.
Welcome to the Planet.
Glad to be here, Lois.