Who am I? You sure you wanna know?
The story of my life is not
for the faint of heart.
If somebody said it was
a happy little tale...
...if somebody told you I was just
your average guy, not a care in the world...
...somebody lied.
But let me assure you, this,
like any story worth telling...
...is all about a girl.
That girl. The girl next door.
Mary Jane Watson.
The woman I've loved since
before I even liked girls.
I'd like to tell you that's me next to her.
Aw, heck, I'd even take him.
Hey! Stop the bus!
That's me.
Tell him to stop! Please!
Stop!
Hey! Stop the bus!
Stop the bus! He's been chasing us
since Woodhaven Boulevard.
Catch a cab, Parker!
Thank you. I'm sorry I'm late.
What a geek!
- Don't even think about it.
- You're so lame, Parker.
Would you date him?
Midtown High seniors.
No wandering.
Proceed direct... Knock it off.
Remember, it is a privilege to be here.
We're guests of Columbia
University's Science Department.
So behave accordingly.
Let's not have a repeat
of our trip to the planetarium.
Come on, people, stay together.
Proceed up the steps
and into the building.
- Where were you?
- Checking out the library.
- Looking at the books.
- Yeah, right.
Charles, can we drive
around the corner, please?
Why?
The entrance is right there.
Dad, these are public-school kids.
I'm not showing up in the Rolls.
What, you want me to trade in
my car for a Jetta...
...because you flunked out of every
private school I sent you to?
- It wasn't for me.
- Of course it was.
Don't ever be ashamed of who you are.
I'm not ashamed of who I am.
It's just...
Just what, Harry?
Forget it.
Pete!
- Hi, Harry.
- Hey, man. What's up?
Harry.
- Won't you be needing this?
- Thanks, Dad.
Peter, may I introduce
my father, Norman Osborn.
I've heard so much about you.
- Great honor to meet you, sir.
- Harry says you're a science whiz.
You know, I'm something
of a scientist myself.
I read all your research on nanotechnology.
Really brilliant.
- And you understood it?
- Yes, I wrote a paper on it.
Impressive.
Your parents must be very proud.
I live with my aunt and uncle.
They are.
Hey, you two! Let's move!
- Nice to meet you. Yeah.
- Hope to see you again.
- He doesn't seem so bad.
- Not if you're a genius.
I think he wants to adopt you.
There are over 32,000 known
species of spider in the world.
They're in the order Araneae,
divided into three suborders.
That's amazing!
This is the most advanced electron
microscope on the Eastern Seaboard.
It's unreal.
Arachnids from all three groups possess...
...varying strengths to help
them search for food.
For example, the Delena spider,
family Sparassidae...
...has the ability to jump to catch its prey.
For the school paper?
Next, we have the net web spider,
family Filistatidae...
...genus Kukulcania.
Spins a funnel-shaped web whose
strands have a tensile strength...
...proportionately equal
to the high-tension wires used in bridges.
- Leave him alone.
- Or what?
Or his father will fire your father.
What's Daddy gonna do? Sue me?
What is going on?
The next person who talks will fail
this course. I kid you not.
- This grass spider...
- Let's go.
...hunts using reflexes with
nerve-conduction velocity so fast...
...that some researchers believe
it almost borders on precognition.
- An early awareness of danger.
- They're jerks.
A spider-sense.
Hey, look at that spider.
Some spiders change colors
to blend into their environment.
It's a defense mechanism.
Peter, what makes you think
I would want to know that?
Who wouldn't?
Over five painstaking years,
Columbia's genetic research facility...
- You gonna talk to her now?
- Oh, no. Come on. You talk to her.
Armed with these DNA blueprints...
...we have now begun what
was once thought impossible.
- Disgusting.
- Yeah, hateful little things.
I love them!
Yeah, me too.
You know, spiders can
change their color...
- ...to blend into their environment.
- Really?
- Yeah, it's a defense mechanism.
- Cool.
...transfer RNA to encode
an entirely new genome...
...combining the genetic information
from all three spiders...
...into these 15 genetically
designed super-spiders.
There's 14.
I beg your pardon?
- One's missing.
- Yeah.
I guess the researchers
are working on that one.
Do you know that this is
the largest electron microscope...
...on the Eastern Seaboard?
You were talking throughout that
woman's entire presentation.
Let's go talk about how we listen.
Now, I don't know what it's like
at those fancy private schools...
...but at Midtown High...
Hey.
Could I take your picture?
I need one with a student in it.
- Sure. Yeah.
- Great.
Where do you want me? Over here?
Yeah, that's great.
Don't make me look ugly.
That's impossible.
Perfect.
- Is that good?
- Great.
That's great.
M.J., let's go!
Wait. Thanks!
Parker, let's do it.
We solved the horizon glide
and the multi-G balance issues.
I've already seen the glider.
That's not what I'm here for.
General Slocum, good to see you again.
Mr. Balkan, Mr. Fargas.
- Norman.
- Mr. Osborn.
Always a pleasure to have
our board of directors visit.
I want to see the progress report
on human performance enhancers.
We tried vapor inhalation with rats.
Their strength increased by 800 percent.
- Excellent.
- Any side effects?
In one trial, yes.
An aberration. All the tests
since have been successful.
In the trial that went wrong,
what were the side effects?
Violence, aggression...
...and insanity.
- What do you recommend?
- That was only one test.
Except for Dr. Stromm, our entire
staff certifies the product...
- ...ready for human testing.
- Dr. Stromm?
We need to take the whole
line back to formula.
- Back to formula?
- Dr. Osborn.
I'll be frank with you.
I never supported your program.
We have my predecessor to thank for that.
The general has approved Quest Aerospace...
...to build a prototype
of their exoskeleton design.
- They test in two weeks.
- And if your performance enhancers...
...have not had a successful
human trial by that date...
...I'm gonna pull your funding.
I'm going to give it to them.
Gentlemen. Ladies.
And the Lord said, "Let there be light."
And voilà! There is light.
Forty soft, glowing watts of it.
Good boy. God will be thrilled.
Just don't fall on your ass.
I'm already on my ass, May.
When the plant's senior electrician
is laid off after 35 years...
...what else would you call it?
I am on my ass.
Hand me that dish. The green one.
The corporation is downsizing the people...
...and upsizing their profits.
Ben, you'll get another job somewhere.
Well... Well, let's look
in the paper and see.
There are the want ads.
What do we got here?
Computer...
Computer salesman, computer
engineer, computer analyst.
My Lord, even the computers
need analysts these days.
May, I'm 68. I'm too old for computers.
And besides, I have
a family to provide for.
I love you. And Peter loves you.
You're the most responsible
man I've ever known.
We've been down-and-out before.
But somehow, we survive.
Yeah.
Hi, sweetie. You're just...
Just in time for dinner.
Hey. How you doing, buddy?
How was the field trip?
I don't feel well.
I'm gonna go to sleep.
- You won't have a bite?
- No, thanks. Had a bite.
Did you get some pictures, Peter?
I gotta crash. Everything's fine.
What's that all about?
In this recombination lab...
...we use synthesized transfer RNA
to encode an entirely new genome...
...combining the genetic information
from all three spiders...
...into these 15 genetically
designed super-spiders.
Dr. Osborn, please.
The performance enhancers aren't ready.
The data just doesn't justify this test.
Now, I'm asking you for the last time.
We can't do this.
Don't be a coward.
Risks are part of laboratory science.
Let me reschedule, with a proper
medical staff and a volunteer.
- Just give me two weeks.
- Two weeks? In two weeks...
...we'll have lost the contract
to Quest and OSCORP will be dead.
Sometimes you gotta do things yourself.
- Get me the Promachloraperazine.
- For what?
It begins catalyzation when
the vapor hits the bloodstream.
Forty thousand years of evolution...
...and we've barely even tapped
the vastness of human potential.
Oh, that's cold.
Norman?
Norman!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! Norman?
Oh, my God! Norman!
Norman?
Back to formula?
Weird.
- Peter?
- Yeah?
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Any better this morning?
Any change?
Change?
Yep. Big change.
- Well, hurry up. You're gonna be late.
- Right.
Okay.
- Goodness me!
- Jeez. I thought you were sick.
- I got better.
- You see?
- Bye, guys.
- Have you got your lunch money?
Hey, Michelangelo, don't forget,
we're painting the kitchen after school.
Sure thing, Uncle Ben.
Don't start without me.
And don't start up with me.
Teenagers. Raging hormones.
They never change.
You're trash!
You're always gonna be trash!
- I have to go to school.
- Who's stopping you?
Hi, M.J.
Hey, M.J.
I don't know if you realize this,
but we've been neighbors since I was 6.
And I was wondering if we
could get together sometime.
I got the car. Hop in.
Do something fun?
Or, I don't know.
I thought it'd be time
to get to know each other.
Or not.
- Sorry, Parker, the bus is full!
- Hey!
Hey!
- Stop the bus! Hey! Hey.
- Catch a cab!
Tell him to stop.
- Check him out!
- Dork!
Dad!
Dad, are you all right?
Harry.
What are you doing on the floor?
I don't know.
Have you been there all night?
Last night I was...
What?
- I don't remember.
- Mr. Osborn?
Sir, I asked her to wait in the foyer.
- My father's not feeling well.
- Mr. Osborn, Dr. Stromm is dead.
What?
They found his body in the lab.
He's been murdered, sir.
- What are you talking about?
- And the flight suit and the glider...
- What about it?
- It's been stolen, sir.
Great reflexes!
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Hey, you have blue eyes.
I didn't notice without your glasses.
You just get contacts?
Well, see you.
- What happened?
- He's freaking weird.
Did you see that?
Parker?
- It's a fight!
- Think you're pretty funny, freak?
- Flash, it was an accident.
- So is my breaking your teeth.
- Come on, Flash, stop.
- I don't wanna fight you, Flash.
- I wouldn't wanna fight me neither.
- Kick his ass.
Help him, Harry.
How'd he do that?
Which one?
He's all yours, man.
- Yeah!
- Flash, get up!
Jesus, Parker, you are a freak.
Peter, that was... That was amazing.
I'm out of here. Come on.
Peter!
Go, web!
Fly.
Up, up and away, web!
Shazam!
Go! Go!
Go, web, go!
Tallyho.
- Is she back with the beer yet?
- What?
Bring me some beer.
- Get up off your ass!
- I paid for beer...
- Stop yelling.
- Stop it!
You're as stupid as your mother.
Get away from me!
You are drunk, do you know that?
Where's she going?
Where you going?
These dishes are not done.
Somebody's gotta do the dishes.
- Why don't you do them?
- Get in here and do the dishes.
- You do them. They're yours, anyway.
- I'm going out!
- Were you listening to that?
- No.
Well, I heard, but I was just
taking out the trash.
I guess you can always hear us.
- Everybody shouts.
- Your aunt and uncle don't.
Oh, they can scream
pretty good sometimes.
Listen, M.J., about today
at school with Flash...
You really freaked us out.
I'm sorry. Is he okay?
He's just happy you didn't give
him a black eye for graduation.
So where are you going
after you graduate?
I wanna move into the city.
And hopefully get a job
as a photographer.
Work my way through college.
What about you?
Headed for the city too.
Can't wait to get out of here.
I wanna...
What?
No, come on. Try me.
I wanna...
...act...
...on-stage.
Really?
Oh, that's perfect.
You were awesome in all the school plays.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I cried like a baby when
you played Cinderella.
Peter, that was first grade.
Well...
...even so.
Sometimes...
...you know people.
You can just see what's coming.
What do you see coming for you?
I don't know.
Whatever it is, it's something
I never felt before.
And what for me?
For you?
You're gonna light up Broadway.
You know...
...you're taller than you look.
I hunch.
Don't.
Hey, M.J.! Come take a ride
in my new birthday present.
Come on.
I gotta go.
Bye.
- Oh, my God, it's gorgeous!
- Yeah, right?
- Look at it!
- Hop in.
Oh, my God! What a cool car!
Pretty tight, huh?
Wait till you hear the sound system.
Hey, don't scratch the leather.
Cool car.
Peter?
What's going on in there?
I'm exercising.
I'm not dressed, Aunt May.
Well, you're acting so strangely, Peter.
Okay. Thanks.
Something's bothering him.
Maybe he's too embarrassed to tell me.
Maybe I'm too embarrassed to ask him.
I just don't know anymore.
I'm going to the downtown library.
See you later.
- Wait, Pete. I'll drive you there, buddy.
- I'll take the train.
No, I need the exercise.
Go on. Go, go, go.
- Thanks for the ride, Uncle Ben.
- Wait a minute, we need to talk.
- We can talk later.
- Well, we can talk now. If you let me.
What do we have to talk about?
Why now?
Because we haven't talked for so long...
...May and I don't know
who you are anymore.
You shirk your chores. You have all
those weird experiments in your room.
- You start fights at school...
- I didn't start that fight, I told you that.
- You sure as hell finished it.
- Was I supposed to run away?
No, you're not supposed
to run away, but...
Pete, you're changing. I went through
exactly the same thing at your age.
No. Not exactly.
Peter...
...these are the years
when a man changes...
...into the man he's gonna
become the rest of his life.
Just be careful who you change into.
This guy, Flash Thompson,
he probably deserved what happened.
But just because you can beat him up...
...doesn't give you the right to.
Remember, with great power
comes great responsibility.
Are you afraid I'll become a criminal?
Quit worrying about me, okay?
Something's different.
I'll figure it out. Stop lecturing me.
I don't mean to lecture or preach.
And I know I'm not your father...
Then stop pretending to be!
Right.
I'll pick you up here at 10.
Bone Saw! Bone Saw! Bone Saw!
- One, two, three. That's it!
- Who's the man?
Yeah!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...give it up for Bone Saw McGraw.
For $3000...
...is there no one here man
enough to stay in the ring...
...for three minutes with this
titan of testosterone?
Who?
I know who.
The Flying Dutchman!
Next.
There's no featherweight
division here, small fry. Next.
No, no. Sign me up.
Okay. You understand the NYWL
is not responsible...
...for any injury you may and
probably will sustain in said event?
And you're participating
under your own free will?
Yes.
Down the hall to the ramp.
May God be with you. Next.
Told you! Told you!
Winner!
Next victim!
Are you ready for more?
Bone Saw is ready!
Will the next victim please
enter the arena at this time?
If he can withstand just three minutes
in the cage with Bone Saw McGraw...
...the sum of $3000 will be paid to...
- What's your name, kid?
- The Human Spider.
That's it? That's the best you got?
- Yeah.
- Oh, that sucks.
The sum of $3000 will be paid to...
...the terrifying, the deadly...
...the amazing Spider-Man!
- It's "The Human Spider."
- I don't care, get out there.
- No, he got my name wrong.
- Get out there, you moron.
Bone Saw will eat you up
and spit you out.
I hope you brought your mommy.
- We'll break you!
- You'll need someone to cry to.
I'm gonna rip all eight of your
feeble legs off one by one.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my legs!
Oh, God. I can't feel my legs.
Kill! Kill! Kill!
Cage!
Hello? Guys?
Will the guards please lock
the cage doors at this time?
This is some kind of mistake.
I didn't sign up for a cage match!
Hey! Unlock the thing!
Take the chain off!
Hey, freak show!
You're going nowhere.
I got you for three minutes.
Three minutes of playtime.
- What are you doing up there?
- Staying away from you.
That's a cute outfit.
Did your husband give it to you?
Finish him off!
Smash him!
Bone Saw! Bone Saw! Bone Saw!
- Hit him!
- Harder!
Kick his spider ass!
Hit him!
One, two, three!
That's it! That's it! Winner!
Ladies and gentlemen, give it up
for the new champion, Spider-Man!
Spider-Man! Spider-Man! Spider-Man!
Now get out of here.
A hundred bucks? The ad said 3000.
Well, check it again, webhead.
It said 3 grand for three minutes.
You pinned him in two.
For that, I give you 100.
And you're lucky to get that.
I need that money.
I missed the part where
that's my problem.
- Hey, what the hell...?
- Put the money in the bag.
Hurry up!
Hey! He stole the gate!
Stop that guy!
Stop him! He's got my money!
Thanks.
What the hell's the matter with you?
You let him go!
Cut him off in the lobby
and call the cops!
You could've taken that guy apart.
Now he'll get away with my money.
I missed the part where
that's my problem.
- Sir, you gotta get back.
- I can't see. What happened?
Old dude, man.
Come on, folks. Keep moving, please.
Keep moving. Let's go!
- What happened?
- Someone got hurt.
- How?
- What went down?
- Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Hey, stay back. Stay back.
- Hey. Stay back!
- That's my uncle!
- What happened?
- Carjacker. He's been shot.
We just called the paramedics.
They're on their way. Stay back.
Uncle Ben?
Uncle Ben.
Peter.
I'm here, Uncle Ben.
They got the shooter.
He's headed south on Fifth Avenue.
We got three cars in pursuit.
All right, folks. Come on, move back.
Hey, hey!
Get a unit to the rear!
I got the back!
Who's there?
Don't hurt me. Give me a chance.
Just give me a chance!
What about my uncle?
Did you give him a chance? Did you?
Answer me!
Stop that guy!
Thanks.
See you.
No...
Freeze! We've got the place
completely surrounded.
Oh, no. My God.
Oh, no. Oh, my God. No!
- Good evening.
- General. Good to see you.
Our exoskeleton's got real
firepower, General Slocum.
Well, if it does what you say it can,
I'll sign that contract tomorrow.
...17, 16...
- He's clear, let's go!
- You're confident about this test?
Absolutely. Captain Curtis is our top pilot.
Now, what about your
commitment to OSCORP?
Nothing would please me more than
to put Norman Osborn out of business.
...four, three...
- Preflight complete. Mark.
- ...two, one. Mark.
We are picking up an unidentified
object, closing fast.
- What the hell is that?
- Can you see anything?
Oh, my God!
- Say "chess."
- Chess!
Peter!
My darling, I'm so proud of you.
You looked so handsome up there.
Pete? Good news. Dad got the place
in New York, so we're all set this fall.
- That's great.
- You made it.
It's not the first time
I've been proven wrong.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks, Dad.
Peter, the science award.
That's terrific.
Yeah.
I know this has been
a difficult time for you...
...but I want you to try to enjoy this day.
Commencement:
The end of one thing,
the start of something new.
I don't want to be with you anymore.
Here's your ring.
You know what? Whatever.
Your loss.
You're like a brother to Harry.
That makes you family.
And if you ever need anything,
just give me a call.
Can I fix you something?
No, thanks.
I missed him a lot today.
I know.
I miss him too.
But he was there.
I can't help thinking about
the last thing I said to him.
He tried to tell me something important,
and I threw it in his face.
You loved him...
...and he loved you.
He never doubted the man you'd grow into.
How you were meant for great things.
You won't disappoint him.
With great power comes
great responsibility.
Remember that, Pete.
Remember that.
Hurry up!
He's not a man. My brother saw him
building a nest in Lincoln Center.
I think he's human, a man.
Could be a woman.
Bobby. Get a load of this!
He throws up his hands, ropes come out...
...and he climbs up them like a spider web.
I see the web, his signature,
and I know Spider-Man was here.
The guy protects us, you know,
he protects the people.
Some kind of freakyloo or something.
Wackadoo.
He stinks and I don't like him.
Don't move, lady!
Guy with eight hands. Sounds hot.
He has those tights
and that tight little...
♪ Dresses like a spider ♪
♪ He looks like a bug ♪
♪ But we should all just give him ♪
♪ One big hug ♪
♪ Look out ♪
♪ Here comes the Spider-Man ♪
"Who is Spider-Man?"
He's a criminal, that's who he is.
A vigilante, a public menace.
Why's he on my front page?
Mr. Jameson, your wife needs...
There's a Page 6 problem.
We have a Page 1 problem. Shut up.
- Well?
- He's news.
- The clients can't wait.
- They're about to.
- He pulled six people off a subway.
- From a wreck he probably caused.
Something goes wrong and he's there.
Look! He's fleeing the scene.
What's that tell you?
He's not fleeing, he's probably
going to save somebody else.
He's a hero!
Then why does he wear a mask?
What's he got to hide?
She needs to know if you want chintz
or chenille in the dining room.
- Whichever one's cheaper.
- Mr. Jameson, it's like this:
We double-booked Page 6.
So Macy's and Conway's both
have three quarters...
- We sold out four printings.
- Sold out?
Every copy.
Tomorrow, Spider-Man, Page 1,
with a decent picture.
- Conway to Page 7.
- That's a problem.
Page 8, give him 10 percent off.
Five percent.
- That can't be done.
- Get out of here!
We don't have a decent picture.
Eddie's been on it for weeks,
but we can barely see him.
What is he, shy?
If we can get a picture of Julia Roberts
in a thong, we can get this weirdo.
Put an ad on the front page:
"Cash for a picture of Spider-Man."
He doesn't wanna be famous?
I'll make him infamous!
Hey!
Buzz off.
- M.J., it's me, Peter. Hey.
- Hi!
- What are you doing around here?
- Begging for a job. How about you?
- I'm headed to an audition.
- An audition? So you're acting?
Yeah. I work steady.
In fact, I just got off a job.
That's great, M.J.
- You're doing it. Living your dream.
- Glamour girl!
Your drawer was short $6!
Next time that happens,
I'll take it out of your check.
Excuse me, Miss Watson?
I'm talking to you! Hey!
Yes, Enrique! Okay? I get you.
It better not happen no more.
Don't roll your eyes at me.
Some dream, huh?
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
- Don't tell Harry.
- Don't tell Harry?
Don't you guys live together?
We're going out. Didn't he tell you?
Oh, yeah. Right.
I think he'd hate the idea
of my waiting tables.
- He'd think it was low or something.
- It's not low. You have a job.
You know, Harry doesn't live
on a little place I like to call Earth.
No, I guess not.
Thanks, Pete.
We should catch up sometime.
Let's get some lunch some evening.
I'll come by and have some of your
Moondance coffee some day.
- And I won't tell Harry.
- No, don't tell Harry.
I won't.
I won't tell Harry.
Timing's perfect. Hey.
Five new contracts. It'll be great.
Storming Norman's making
his weekly inspection.
Spent half of it on the phone.
Look, man, I'm glad you're here.
I need your help. I'm really lost here.
Are you all right?
You look like you just got
second place in the science fair.
No, I...
I was late for work and
Dr. Connors fired me.
You were late again?
I don't get it.
Where do you go all the time?
Around.
Peter Parker.
- Maybe you'll tell me who she is.
- Who's that?
- This mystery girl Harry's been dating.
- Dad.
- When do I get to meet her?
Well, sorry. Harry hasn't mentioned her.
Hey, Pete, you're probably
looking for a job now, right?
Dad, maybe you can help him out.
- No, I appreciate it, but I'll be fine.
- It's no problem. I'll make a few calls.
No, I couldn't accept it, sir.
I like to earn what I get. I'll find work.
I respect that.
You want to make it on your own steam.
That's great.
What other skills do you have, Parker?
I was thinking about photography.
Hello.
Let's go! Move it!
Watch the street!
Cheese!
They're crap.
Crap, crap. Megacrap.
- I'll give you $200 for all of them.
- That seems a little low.
Take them somewhere else, then.
Your wife says the tile
for the foyer is out of stock.
Tell her we'll put a rug there.
Sit down. Give me that.
Give you 300.
That's the standard freelance fee.
- Tear up Page 1. Run that photo.
- Headline?
"Spider-Man, Hero or Menace?
Exclusive Daily Bugle Photos."
Menace? He was protecting that armored...
Tell you what, Atticus.
You take the pictures,
I'll make up the headlines. Okay?
- Yes, sir.
- Goody.
Give this to the girl up front.
She'll see you get paid.
- I'd like a job, sir.
- No jobs. Freelance.
Best thing for a kid your age.
You bring me more shots of that clown,
maybe I'll buy them.
But I never said you have a job. Meat.
I'll send you a nice box of Christmas meat.
Get out of here.
Bring me more photos.
- Hi.
Mr. Jameson told me to give that to you.
- Welcome to the Daily Bugle.
- Thank you.
I'm Peter Parker.
I'm a photographer.
Yes. I can see that.
As of today...
...OSCORP Industries has
surpassed Quest Aerospace...
...as the principal supplier
to the United States military.
In short, ladies and gentlemen
of the board...
...costs are down, revenues are up...
...and our stock has never been higher.
Wonderful news, Norman.
That's why we're selling the company.
What?
Quest is recapitalizing in the wake
of the bombing. Expanding.
They made a tender offer we can't ignore.
Why wasn't I told?
They don't want a power struggle
with entrenched management.
The deal is off if you come with it.
The board expects your
resignation in 30 days.
But you can't do this to me.
I started this company.
You know how much I sacrificed?!
- Oh, Max. Please.
- Norman, the board is unanimous.
We're announcing the sale
after the World Unity Festival.
I'm sorry.
You're out, Norman.
Am I?
Welcome to OSCORP Industries
Unity Day Festival.
Let's hear it for Macy Gray.
M.J., why didn't you wear the black dress?
Just, I wanted to impress my father.
He loves black.
Well, maybe he'll be impressed
no matter what. You think I'm pretty.
I think you're beautiful.
M.J., would you do me a favor?
I forgot my drink inside.
- Oh, hi, Mr. Fargas.
- Oh, Harry.
- Have you seen my father around?
- Well, I'm not sure if he's coming.
- What is that?
- Must be new this year.
- That's our glider!
What the hell was that?
Code 3!
- Oh, my God! Harry!
- M.J.!
Harry! Help me! Harry!
Out, am I?
- Mary Jane!
- Harry!
Hello, my dear.
It's Spider-Man!
- Come on, move, kid.
- Billy!
Somebody help him!
No!
Mommy!
- Hold it right there!
- I surrender.
- Oh, boy.
- Hold it right there!
Impressive.
- Mary Jane!
- Help! Someone please help me!
Hold on!
Watch out!
We'll meet again, Spider-Man!
Hold on, Mary Jane!
Well, beats taking the subway.
Don't mind us.
She just needs to use the elevator.
Wait.
Who are you?
- You know who I am.
- I do?
Your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man.
Incredible?
What do you mean he's incredible?
No. All right, wait. Stay there.
I'm gonna come over.
No, I'm gonna come...
All right. Fine.
Will you call me in the morning?
And we'll go and have breakfast, and...
...I wanna buy you something.
Because I want to.
It'll make you feel better.
Okay. And, like, what do
you mean, incredible?
All right. I'm sorry. Sleep tight.
Don't let the bedbugs...
She's all right.
She's just a little rattled.
Yeah.
Look, Pete, I should have
told you about us.
But you should know I'm crazy about her.
It's just, you know,
you never made a move.
You're right.
I didn't.
I'm gonna get some rest.
I'm gonna stay up for a while.
What was that thing?
I don't know.
Whatever it is, somebody has to stop it.
Somebody there?
Somebody.
Who said that?
Don't play the innocent with me.
You've known all along.
Where are you?
Follow the cold shiver
running down your spine.
I'm right here.
I don't understand.
Did you think it was coincidence?
So many good things,
all happening for you.
All for you. Norman.
What do you want?
To say what you won't.
To do what you can't.
To remove those in your way.
The board members.
You killed them.
We killed them.
We?
Remember?
Your little accident in the laboratory.
The performance enhancers.
Bingo. Me!
Your greatest creation.
Bringing you what you've always wanted:
Power beyond your wildest dreams.
And it's only the beginning.
There's only one who can stop us.
Or imagine if he joined us.
Spider-Man. And the Green Goblin.
The Green Goblin. You like that?
Made it up myself.
- These weirdos all gotta have a name.
- Mr. Jameson, Spider...
- Hoffman!
- Yeah?
Copyright the name "Green Goblin."
I want a quarter every time it's said.
How about "Green Meanie"?
Spider-Man wasn't attacking the city.
That's slander.
It is not. I resent that.
Slander is spoken. In print, it's libel.
You don't trust anybody.
That's your problem.
I trust my barber.
What are you, his lawyer? Get out.
Let him sue me, get rich
like a normal person.
That's what made this country...
Jameson, you slime.
Who's the photographer who takes
the pictures of Spider-Man?
I don't know. His stuff comes by mail.
- You're lying!
- I swear.
He's the one who can bring me to him.
- I don't know who he is.
- You are useless.
Set him down, tough guy.
- Speak of the devil.
- I knew you two were in this together!
Hey, kiddo, let Mom and Dad
talk for a minute, will you?
Sleep...
Wake up, little spider. Wake up.
No, you're not dead yet.
Just paralyzed...
...temporarily.
You're an amazing creature, Spider-Man.
You and I are not so different.
I'm not like you. You're a murderer.
Well, to each his own.
I chose my path,
you chose the way of the hero.
And they found you amusing
for a while, the people of this city.
But the one thing they love
more than a hero...
...is to see a hero fail, fall, die trying.
In spite of everything
you've done for them...
...eventually, they will hate you.
Why bother?
- Because it's right.
- Here's the real truth.
There are eight million people in this city.
And those teeming masses
exist for the sole purpose...
...of lifting the few exceptional
people onto their shoulders.
You, me...
...we're exceptional.
I could squash you like a bug right now.
But I'm offering you a choice. Join me.
Imagine what we could
accomplish together.
What we could create.
Or we could destroy.
Cause the deaths of countless
innocents in selfish battle...
...again and again and again
until we're both dead.
Is that what you want?
Think about it, hero!
In spite of everything you've done for them,
eventually, they will hate you.
Hey!
- It's me again.
- Hey!
How was your audition?
- How'd you know?
- The hot line. Your mom...
...told my aunt, told me.
So you just came by?
I was in the neighborhood.
Needed to see a friendly face.
I took two buses and a cab to get
in the neighborhood, but...
So how'd it go?
They said I needed acting lessons.
A soap opera told me
I needed acting lessons.
Let me buy you a cheeseburger.
The sky's the limit, up to $7.84.
I'd like a cheeseburger.
Oh, but I'm going out
to dinner with Harry.
Come with us.
No, thanks. How's it going with...?
Never mind.
That's none of my business.
It's not?
Why so interested?
I'm not.
You're not?
- Well, why would I be?
- I don't know.
Why would you be?
I... That's a...
I don't know.
Sorry you won't come with us.
I better run, tiger.
Hey, check it out, man.
Come on, man.
Hey, where you going, baby?
Come on!
Get off me!
Wait.
You have a knack for getting in trouble.
You have a knack for saving my life.
I think I have a superhero stalker.
I was in the neighborhood.
You are amazing.
Some people don't think so.
- But you are.
- Nice to have a fan.
Do I get to say thank you this time?
Wait.
Let me in! My baby's in there!
- Let me go!
- The roof's collapsing!
- Somebody save my baby!
- The roof's about to collapse!
Look! Up there!
Save my baby, please!
No!
- It's okay. Your baby's fine.
- Oh, my baby.
God bless you, Spider-Man.
Bless you.
There he is! Don't let him get away!
Hold it! You're under arrest.
I'm taking you in.
Oh, my God, there's
somebody still up there!
I'm going.
- I'll be here when you get back.
- Not coming back, chief.
Go! Go!
Where are you?
Where are you?!
I'm gonna get you out of here!
It's okay.
You're pathetically predictable.
Like a moth to the flame.
What about my generous proposal?
Are you in or are you out?
It's you who's out, Gobby.
Out of your mind.
Wrong answer.
Oh, great.
No one says no to me!
- M.J., will you stop goofing around?
- Harry, relax.
He's here.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
Aunt May. I'm sorry I'm late.
Work was murder.
I picked up a fruitcake.
Thank you.
We're so glad you could come.
- You look great.
- Thanks.
Who is this lovely young lady?
M.J., I'd like you to meet my father.
Dad, this is Mary Jane Watson.
I've been looking forward to meeting you.
- Happy Thanksgiving, sir.
- Now, where is Peter?
He'd better have remembered
that cranberry sauce.
Oh, that's weird.
I didn't know he was here.
Peter?
Is that you?
Pete?
How strange. There's nobody here.
- Bit of a slob, isn't he?
- All brilliant men are.
- Hey, everyone.
- Oh, Peter!
Sorry I'm late, it's a jungle out there.
I had to beat an old lady with a stick
to get these cranberries.
Thank you.
Now then, everybody sit down...
...and we can say grace.
Parker.
Here we go.
- There we are.
- It looks delicious.
Norman.
Will you do the honors?
Why, Peter, you're bleeding.
Oh, yeah...
I stepped off a curb and got clipped
by one of those bike messengers.
Well, let me see.
Oh, my goodness.
- Oh, that looks awful.
- No, it's nothing.
I'll get the first aid kit.
Then we'll say grace.
This is the boys' first Thanksgiving here,
and we'll do things properly.
How did you say that happened?
Bike messenger.
Knocked me down.
- If you'll excuse me, I've got to go.
- Why?
Something has come to my attention.
Are you all right?
I'm fine, just fine.
Thank you, Mrs. Parker. Everyone.
- Enjoy the fruitcake.
- Dad!
Dad! What are you doing?
I planned this so you'd meet M.J.,
now you have to leave?
I've got to go.
- This girl is important to me.
- Harry, please. Look at her.
Think she's sniffing around because
she likes your personality?
- What are you saying?
- Your mother was beautiful too.
They're all beautiful.
Until they're snarling after your trust
fund like a pack of ravening wolves.
You're wrong about her, Dad.
A word to the not-so-wise
about your little girlfriend:
Do what you need to with her,
then broom her fast.
Thanks for sticking up for me, Harry.
- You heard?
- Everyone heard that creep.
That creep is my father.
With luck, I'll be half of what he is.
Shut up about stuff you don't understand!
Harry Osborn!
I'm sorry, Aunt May.
Spider-Man is all but invincible.
But Parker, we can destroy him.
I can't.
Betrayal must not be countenanced.
Parker must be educated.
What do I do?
Instruct him in the matters
of loss and pain.
Make him suffer.
Make him wish he were dead.
Yes?
And then grant his wish.
But how?
The cunning warrior attacks
neither body nor mind.
Tell me how!
The heart, Osborn.
First, we attack his heart.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us...
Deliver us!
Finish it!
- Finish it!
- From evil!
Two milligrams IV.
Get the BP.
Aunt May. Is she gonna be okay?
- What happened?
- She'll be okay.
You have to leave.
- What happened?
- Those eyes!
Those horrible yellow eyes!
He knows who I am.
I'm sorry.
- Will she be okay?
- She's gonna be fine.
She's been sleeping all day.
- Thanks for coming.
- Of course.
How are you?
You okay about the other night?
Yeah, I'm fine. I just felt
bad about leaving Aunt May.
- Have you talked to Harry?
- He called me.
I haven't called him back.
The fact is...
- ...I'm in love with somebody else.
- You are?
At least I think I am.
- It's not the right time to talk about it.
- No, no. Go on.
Would I know his name, this guy?
You'll think I'm a stupid
little girl with a crush.
Trust me.
It's funny.
He's saved my life twice,
and I've never even seen his face.
- Him.
- You're laughing at me.
No, I understand.
He is extremely cool.
Do you think it's true, all the terrible
things they say about him?
No, no. Not Spider-Man,
not a chance in the world.
I know him a little bit.
I'm sort of his unofficial photographer.
- Has he mentioned me?
- Yeah.
What'd he say?
I said...
He asked me what I thought about you.
And what did you say?
I said, "Spider-Man."
I said, "The great thing about M.J...
...is...
...when you look in her eyes...
...and she's looking back in yours...
...everything feels...
...not quite normal.
Because you feel...
...stronger...
...and weaker at the same time.
You feel excited...
...and at the same time...
...terrified.
The truth is, you don't know
what you feel...
...except you know what kind of man
you want to be.
It's as if you've...
...reached the unreachable...
...and you weren't ready for it."
You said that?
Well, something like that.
Hey.
Dad?
Dad, is that you?
What is it?
Well, you were right about M.J.
You're right about everything.
She's in love with Peter.
- Parker?
- Yeah.
And how does he feel about her?
He's loved her since the 4th grade.
He pretends like he doesn't,
but there's no one Peter cares for more.
I'm so sorry.
I haven't always been
there for you, have I?
You're busy. You're an important man.
I understand.
That's no excuse.
I'm proud of you.
And I've lost sight of that somewhere.
But I'll make it up to you, Harry.
I'm going to rectify certain inequities.
Wake up, little spider.
Wake up.
Go home, dear.
You look awful.
- And you look beautiful.
- Well, thank you.
- I don't like to leave you here.
- But I'm safe here.
- Can I do anything for you?
- You do too much.
College, a job, all this time with me.
You're not Superman, you know.
A smile. Finally.
Haven't seen one of those on your
face since Mary Jane was here.
Hey. You were supposed to be asleep.
You know, you were about 6 years old
when M.J.'s family moved in next door.
And when she got out of the car
and you saw her for the first time...
...you grabbed me and said,
"Aunt May, Aunt May, is that an angel?"
- Gee, did I say that?
- You sure did.
Well, Harry's in love with her.
- She's still his girl.
- Well, isn't that up to her?
- She doesn't really know who I am.
- Because you won't let her.
You're so mysterious all the time.
Tell me, would it be so dangerous...
...to let Mary Jane know
how much you care?
Everybody else knows.
I'll be right back.
But...
Come on, pick up.
- Hey, M.J....
- Hi, it's me. Sing your song at the beep.
M.J., it's Peter. You there?
Hello? You there?
I'm just calling to check up on you.
Will you call me when you get in?
All right, well...
Don't...
Don't go up any dark alleys.
Hello?
Can Spider-Man come out to play?
Where is she?
- What is that?
- That's cool!
♪ The itsy-bitsy spider ♪
♪ Went up the water spout ♪
♪ Down came the goblin ♪
♪ And took the spider out ♪
Goblin, what have you done?
Spider-Man! This is why
only fools are heroes.
Because you never know...
...when some lunatic will come
along with a sadistic choice:
Let die the woman you love...
...or suffer the little children.
- Spider-Man!
- Save us!
Save us!
Make your choice, Spider-Man...
...and see how a hero is rewarded.
Don't do it, Goblin!
We are who we choose to be.
- Now, choose!
- No!
Everybody stay still!
Ahoy up there!
We're gonna bring the barge
right under you.
- He's coming back!
- Listen. I need you to climb down.
- I can't.
- Yes, you can!
M.J., you can do it. You have to.
Trust me.
Hold on tight and go quickly.
- Hurry!
- I can't. I can't do it.
Hang on, Mary Jane!
- He's not gonna make it.
- He's gonna make it!
It's time to die.
Come on up here, tough guy,
I got something for you!
We ought to kick your ass!
Leave Spider-Man alone!
You're gonna pick on a guy saving kids?
I got something for your ass!
Mess with Spidey, you mess with New York!
You mess with one of us,
you mess with all of us!
Yeah!
Spider-Man, watch out!
Misery, misery, misery.
That's what you've chosen.
I offered you friendship...
...and you spat in my face.
You've spun your last web, Spider-Man.
Had you not been so selfish,
your little girlfriend's death...
...would have been quick and painless.
But now that you've really pissed me off...
...I'm gonna finish her...
...nice and slow.
M.J. and I...
...we're gonna have a hell of a time.
Peter, stop!
Stop! It's me.
Mr. Osborn.
Peter, thank God for you.
You killed those people on that balcony.
The Goblin killed!
I had nothing to do with it!
Don't let him take me again.
I beg you. Protect me.
You tried to kill Aunt May.
You tried to kill Mary Jane.
But not you.
I tried to stop it.
But I couldn't stop it.
I would never hurt you.
I knew from the beginning...
...if anything ever happened to me...
...it was you that I could count on.
You, Peter Parker, would save me,
and so you have.
Thank God for you.
Give me your hand.
Believe in me as I believed in you.
I've been like a father to you.
Be a son to me now.
I have a father.
His name was Ben Parker.
Godspeed, Spider-Man.
Peter.
Don't tell Harry.
What have you done?
What have you done?!
Hey.
I'm so sorry, Harry.
I know what it's like to lose a father.
I didn't lose him.
He was stolen from me.
One day Spider-Man will pay.
I swear on my father's grave,
Spider-Man will pay.
Thank God for you, Peter.
You're the only family I have.
No matter what I do...
...no matter how hard I try...
...the ones I love will always
be the ones who pay.
You must miss him so much.
It's been so hard without him.
There's something I've been
wanting to tell you.
When I was up there...
...and I thought I was gonna die...
...there was only one person
who I was thinking of.
And it wasn't who I thought it'd be.
It was you, Pete.
I kept thinking:
"I hope I make it through this...
...so I could see Peter Parker's
face one more time."
Really?
There's only one man who's
always been there for me...
...who makes me feel...
...like I'm more than I ever
thought I could be.
That I'm just...
...me.
And that's okay.
The truth is...
...I love you.
I love you so much, Peter.
All I wanted was to tell her
how much I loved her.
I can't.
You can't what?
Tell you...
...everything. I mean,
there's so much to tell.
Yeah. There's so much to tell.
I want you to know...
...that I will always be there for you.
I will always be there
to take care of you.
I promise you that.
I will always be your friend.
Only a friend...
...Peter Parker?
That's all I have to give.
Whatever life holds in store for me...
...I will never forget these words:
"With great power comes
great responsibility."
This is my gift.
My curse.
Who am I?
I'm Spider-Man.