Wu.
You and your brothers
murdered three of our men.
He would have done the same.
Send three more
and I'll kill them too.
He already controls
the opium trade all across Asia.
May no one prosper but Ying Ko?
My poppy fields are tiny...
nothing compared to his.
Well, I, Li Peng, at least
I'm entitled to my little piece.
Ying Ko, if you kill me,
I promise my brothers
will come for you.
And I promise you...
I'll bury them beside you.
Kill him.
Let me go.
I only wish to leave.
I'll cut his throat.
Your men are not marksmen enough
to shoot around him.
You're right.
Wu, you are a wonderful friend.
Like a father to me.
Thank you, Ying Ko.
Shoot through him.
Uh!
Where are you taking me?
The Tulku wishes to see you
at his temple.
A holy man wants to see me?
You call that a temple?
No.
There.
Where did that come from?
The clouded mind sees nothing.
Who are you?
I am your teacher.
Do you have any idea
who you just kidnapped?
Cranston.
Lamont Cranston.
You know my real name?
Yes.
I also know that for as long
as you can remember,
you've struggled against your own
black heart and always lost.
You watched your spirit,
your very face change
as the beast claws
his way out within you.
You're in great pain,
aren't you?
You know what evil lurks
in the hearts of men,
for you have seen that evil
in your own heart.
Every man pays the price
for redemption.
- This is yours.
- I'm not lookin' for redemption.
You have no choice.
You will be redeemed
because I will teach you
to use your black shadow
to fight evil.
I wouldn't do that.
Phurba.
Phurba!
Am I in hell?
Not yet.
Get him, Johnny.
Maxie.
All right,
let's get this over with.
- Get out.
- No.
- Come on, come on!
- No, please.
- Eh, quit your whining.
- I didn't see anything.
Is it dry?
Perfect, Duke.
Bring him to the rail.
- Tip him.
- I won't tell anyone.
- I swear.
- Jeez.
I wish I could trust you,
sport, I really do.
I guess you just picked
the wrong alley to look down.
I have a family.
They'll get over it.
I won't talk.
I- I'm telling you.
Oh, I know you won't.
- Dump him.
- No!
- No, no!
- I hate heavy lifting.
No, no, no!
What the Christ was that?
Who's there?
Show yourself, fella.
You murdered a policeman, Duke.
Who said that?
Duke?
- Who said that?
- Shut up!
The weed of crime
bears bitter fruit.
I don't like this.
This stinks.
Let's get the hell outta here.
Shut your hole, Maxie!
Did you think
you'd get away with it?
Come on, Duke!
Did you think
I wouldn't know?
- Hah!
- Duke, I think you got him.
You're damn right I...
You committed murder, Duke.
Now you're going
to confess to it.
Like hell I will.
You will, Duke.
Because if you don't,
I'll be there.
I'll be there...
around every corner,
in every empty room.
As inevitable
as your guilty conscience.
You don't scare me!
You son of a...
You will go
to the 8th precinct house
on Second Avenue
and surrender yourself.
And you will do it now.
I confess, I confess,
I'll do it, I'll do it!
Oh, my God!
I'll confess, for God's sake,
I don't want to die!
Drive.
Thank you.
You fellas are probably busy.
You can just drop me off
anywhere along...
You're Doctor Roy Tam,
a professor in the science
department at NYU.
Yes.
I've saved your life, Roy Tam.
It now belongs to me.
It does?
You'll become one of my agents.
Like dozens of others
all over the world.
Could, I, uh, ask
my wife about this?
No!
Mr. Shrevnitz here,
will instruct you
in the way I will contact you
should I require your help.
When you hear one
of my agents say,
"The sun is shining,"
you will respond,
"But the ice is slippery."
This will identify you
to each other.
Do you understand?
Th-the sun is shining.
But the ice is slippery.
Uh, tell me one thing...
How did you know
what was happening to me?
How did you know who I am?
The shadow knows.
Thank you.
That's the shadow.
I mean, that's the shadow.
Hey, you're a pretty smart guy.
Well, I heard rumors
in the paper, on the radio,
but I thought it was just talk.
I didn't think he existed.
He doesn't.
Get it?
Don't ever take it off.
Wait a minute.
Who are you?
Somebody who owes him his life.
Somebody just like you.
Boss, you okay?
The Cobalt Club.
♪ You're some kind of mystery ♪
♪ Sweet kind of mystery ♪
♪ Gotta get you close to me ♪
♪ So I can figure out
what this mystery's about ♪
♪ You're some kind of heavenly ♪
♪ That's something
that gets to me I
♪ Gotta get you next to me A'
♪ So I can figure out
what this mystery's about a'
♪ You look into my eyes,
steal my heart, read my mind I'
♪ Help me I'm falling A'
♪ You cast your spell on me I'
♪ And here I am
surrendering my soul... ♪
Sorry I'm late,
Uncle Wainwright,
but there was a little, uh,
accident on the bridge.
Well, I didn't think
you wanted me to wait.
Incidentally, try the, uh, prime rib.
It's excellent.
- You're usual, Mr. Cranston.
- Oh, yes.
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
You know, Lamont, I'm...
I'm very upset with you.
What is it this time?
What is it every time?
You ask me to dinner
and show up an hour late.
There's simply no excuse
for that kind of behavior.
Uncle Wainwright,
I'm sorry, I, uh...
I got caught up.
With what, for God sake?
You don't do anything.
A man your age is unseemly.
At least pick
a hobby or something.
Why am I talking
to the back of your neck?
Lamont?
Lamont!
I'm sorry,
what were we talking about?
You know, I've never meddled
in your affairs.
Going back to the time that
after the war,
when you disappeared
for some seven years.
I never asked any questions then.
I'm not asking any questions now.
Excuse me,
Police Commissioner Barth.
- Urgent message for you, sir.
- Thank you.
What's the matter, cops and robbers
business slowing down?
Mm-mm.
It's a report of that damn
Shadow character again.
I thought you said
he was only a rumor.
I'm sick of the Shadow business...
his meddling in police affairs.
This time tomorrow...
I'll put a task force on him.
You're not going
to appoint a task force.
No, hell with him.
I'm not going
to appoint a task force.
You're not going to pay any attention
to these reports of the Shadow.
Ignore them entirely.
There is no Shadow.
No, there is no Shadow.
If there were,
I'd be Eleanor Roosevelt.
Mm, where was I?
You were about
to tell me who she is.
That's Margo Lane.
Her father's a scientist working
for the War Department.
What the hell do you see in her?
Uncle Wainwright, are you sure
you're not dead?
Not by a long shot.
Do yourself a favor...
stay away from her.
She's strange.
She hears voices.
That's what they say.
Really?
Yes, I would like a glass
of the Mouton...
Rothschild 1928.
Yes.
- From the gentleman.
- Gentleman?
Lamont Cranston.
May I sit?
You know...
it's the strangest thing,
but I have this sudden craving
for Peking duck.
That's so odd.
I was thinking
the exact same thing.
Care to join me?
You speak Chinese.
Only Mandarin.
Well, aren't you full
of surprises.
Thank you.
I'm glad you like it.
Oh, I had it made,
uh, at Adrian's.
Why did you just tell me that?
Well, you just complemented
me on my dress just now.
- Didn't you?
- No, I didn't.
But I was thinking it.
Oh, now that hasn't happened
to me in a long, long time.
Since I was a little girl
with my cousin Harry,
I could hear
what he was thinking.
Just pick the thoughts right out
of his head before he said a word.
It was the strangest thing
and I never was able...
ls-is something bothering you?
Oh' no' no' no'.
- Not at all.
- Oh.
Well, thank you.
I had a wonderful time.
I'm not sure I can recall
an evening as... stimulating.
Good night Miss Lane.
Good night, Mr. Cranston.
I like her, boss.
She's different than
your usual dames.
More than even she knows.
How's that?
She has ability she's
completely unaware of.
No kidding?
You going to see her again?
No, it's much too dangerous.
Dangerous for who?
For me, Moe.
For me.
Someone's coming.
Well, what is it?
That's just it, sir,
I don't know.
Why, I would have labeled it a mummy
case, coming from Tibet like it did.
Mummy cases come
from Egypt, Berger.
Well, that's right, exactly.
Besides, the thing is metal, which made
me think it was a sarcophagus.
No, Tibetan sarcophagi
were of stone.
Uh, what happened to the truckman
who dropped it off?
Gone.
Well, it's obviously
an incorrect shipment.
Call our, uh,
customs broker and...
My God.
This is beautiful.
That is solid silver.
Nelson, help us take
the sides off.
What does it say?
It's Latin.
Kha Khan,
dei potestas, in Terra.
"The power of God on Earth,
the seal
of the Emperor of Mankind."
Oh, my God.
Temujin.
This is the silver coffin
of Temujin.
Who's Temujin?
The man who very nearly conquered
the globe eight centuries ago.
Well, how come
I never heard of him?
Temujin was the birth name...
of Genghis Khan.
What was the shipper's address?
It didn't say.
Label just had
the country of origin.
Let me make a telephone call.
Let me help you.
Nelson, whatever you do,
don't open it.
No, sir.
♪ Come on along and listen to ♪
♪ The lullaby... ♪
♪ Oi... r
♪ Broadway. ♪
Uh...
We-we're closed
Join me or die.
Excuse me?
This is...
this is private property.
Your mind is weak.
Don't come any closer.
Fall to your knees.
Put your gun to your temple.
Sacrifice yourself... to me.
Yes, my Khan.
Oh, my God.
I can't believe it.
We were only gone for a moment.
You didn't hear me, did you?
I'm through
with the beryllium sphere.
I'm just doing some underwater
tests to check pressure.
Farley, I have told you a dozen times
we are doing energy research.
I'm not interested in any military
application of the project.
Oh, yeah?
So, why do you let the War Department
pay all the bills?
'Cause you talked me into it.
I just wanted
enough money to finish.
Dr. Lane, you don't think big.
If you'd only listen to me,
the world could be our oyster.
Oysters?
I get a rash from oysters.
Oh, Margo.
What a beautiful dress.
And such a clever neckline.
Uh, excuse me, Mr. Claymore,
I'd like to see my father.
So...
When are you going to come down
and see my beryllium sphere?
I'm not interested
in your spheres, Mr. Claymore.
Margo, you don't return
my calls anymore.
Well, that's not true.
I never did return your calls.
I know.
I can't imagine why.
It's because I don't like you.
What a fascinating woman.
Uh! Dad, I don't know how
you can work with that man.
Margo, what a nice surprise.
Hm?
Hi.
Hey, have you had your dinner?
Hm?
- Yes, dad, it's two a.m.
- Mm, mm.
Dad, where did you
get this shirt?
Mm, well, you said
I look good in green, hm?
No, this is green, that's red.
Mm, red, green, mm.
Well, to me
it's just a clean shirt.
' Dad?
Hm?
Do you believe in telepathy?
Mm-hm.
I mean, do you believe that it can
exist between certain people?
You mean mind reading?
Well, of course I don't, dear.
I'm a scientist.
So strange.
I've always had this feeling
that there was this...
indescribable connection
out there
just waiting for me.
And suddenly tonight
there it was.
Well, that's nice, dear.
What was it?
It was a man.
And I'm probably never
gonna see him again.
But why not?
I just know.
It was as though I could sense
what he was feeling.
And now I'm completely
and utterly depressed.
Well, that's nice, dear.
Okay, that'll be four forty-five.
What are you doing?
Writin' down a drop-off point.
You're making a record
of my destination?
Taxi commission's rules.
All right, Reilly, back her up.
That's it.
You need fuel.
Jeez, I need gas.
Cut left, that's it.
Hey, thanks.
Look out!
This must be my lucky...
Well, what's going on?
Inspector Cardona's
in charge, sir.
He's, uh, over there.
Mm.
Well, I don't know
what to think.
Hey, what are you, crazy?
- Out.
- Thank you.
To The Sanctum.
Go, go.
Come on, lady,
there's no parking there... come on.
Hey, Louie,
save that cab for me!
Report.
Our agent in 26th precinct reports
police investigation of murder
at the Museum
of Natural History.
Murder?
Agent advises inquiry.
Understood.
I saw you as taller.
Who are you?
Shiwan Khan, last descendent
of Genghis Khan.
You are naturally
deeply honored.
Don't feel obligated
to introduce yourself.
I already know who you are.
Not this temporary version
of yourself.
I know who you really are...
Ying Ko.
I'm a great admirer.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Please.
It is no more difficult for me
to invade your mind
than it was this room.
May I sit?
You are hurting
my feelings, Ying Ko.
I should have thought
you would enjoy to meet another
with the unique ability
to cloud men's minds.
You were a student
of the The Tulku?
Yes, he spoke of you constantly.
But I'm afraid he wasn't able
to turn me quite as easily.
Hey, would you happen to have
some American Bourbon?
I have a bit of a taste for it.
Hey, I'm happy to pay,
of course.
No, no, not at all.
Say, you didn't happen,
by any chance,
to, uh...
pay a visit to the Museum
last night, did you?
Mm, a wonderful collection
of Tibetan tapestries.
Ah!
Oh, Ying Ko, grown men
still shiver at your name.
You are, I have to confess,
my idol.
Your raid on the Village of Barga...
I studied it.
How nice, you remember it.
It rings a bell.
It was a master stroke.
Swift, vicious, and sudden!
What genius.
Uh-huh.
So, uh, what brings you
to the Big Apple?
My destiny.
Genghis Khan conquer half
of the world in his lifetime.
I intend to finish the job.
And, uh, how do you plan
to do that?
If I told you,
it wouldn't be a surprise.
I travelled to this country
in Genghis Khan's holy crypt
to absorb his power.
In three days
the entire world will hear my roar
and willingly fall subject
to the lost empire of Sianking.
That is a lovely tie,
by the way.
- May I ask where you acquire it?
- Brooks Brothers.
Is that Midtown?
Forty-fifth and Madison.
You are a barbarian.
Thank you.
We both are.
I know that inside you
beats a heart of darkness.
You dip into it every time
you put on that hat and cloak.
Join me.
You are Ying Ko,
the Butcher of Lhasa.
You and only you deserve
to be by my side.
Together, we'll pit armies against
one another like a chess game.
We'll collect our due of pain
and we'll wash our hands in blood.
Your mouth still waters
at real power.
I am offering you a chance
to take it back.
Be my partner, Ying Ko.
- That's not my name anymore.
- But it is!
Nevertheless, still who you are.
Isn't it?
For the bourbon.
We will meet again, soon.
The day of the Mongol warrior
is once again at hand.
Soon, with wings outstretched,
we fly to our destiny!
Good morning,
Mr. and Mrs. America.
Flash... Manhattan reels from yet
another report of the elusive Shadow.
You know, I think they just
made up the Shadow
so people would listen
to the radio more.
What do you think, Roy?
Some say
this Shadow is a foe...
Hm?
Oh, well, it...
I'll... I'll get it.
Yes.
The sun is shining.
But the ice is slippery.
You're an agent of the Shadow.
Who?
Oh, oh yeah, right.
Gotcha.
Wh... what do you need?
I need a metal analysis of this.
Bronzium.
The metal is bronzium.
I didn't think it existed,
but, my God, here it is.
The ancient Chinese believed
this was the very stuff
the universe was formed of.
Where did it come from?
I'm told it came from Sianking.
If you believed in legends,
it had to be Sianking.
They called it the birthplace
of the world.
Could bronzium conceivably be used
to make some sort of a weapon?
Theoretically, yes.
How?
Well, supposedly, it's very unstable
on the molecular level,
constantly given to expansion.
Only the cell bonds
hold it in check.
But if the bonds were
ever breached...
By explosion?
It wouldn't do it.
But if the power of the cell
were to turn on itself in an implosion,
the molecular imbalance
will be released.
And then you'll have
your explosion all right.
HOW big?
No man can say.
The breakdown
would spread to all levels
of the cells'
atomic construction.
Fashioned into a bomb,
it would be catastrophic.
I guess you'd call it
an implosive-explosive
submolecular device.
Or an atomic bomb.
Hey, that's catchy.
But it would have to have a beryllium
sphere to contain the apparatus.
No other metal would
enhance a blast.
In any case, it's all moot.
None of this would be possible.
Unless some genius figures out
how to design and make it.
An implosive device.
It would have
to be put in a shell
with tiny implosive charges
regularly spread over the surface.
Something like this.
Fortunately,
such a device doesn't exist.
Reinhardt Lane.
Yes, my Khan.
You know something, Lamont,
that puzzles me?
How a man like yourself
who has absolutely nothing to do
can be late
for every little engagement.
Practice, Uncle Wainwright.
Lots and lots of practice.
- Waiter?
- Mm.
Get me some more chives,
would you please and, uh...
Oh, my God, here comes
that Lane woman.
Oh, please,
I don't need her anymore, I, oh...
Hi, Miss Lane, how are you?
All right, you can drop the act,
Commissioner.
What have you done
about my father?
My secretary made it very clear.
There's nothing we can do unless...
Unless what?
He blows himself up?
Margo Lane,
my nephew Lamont Cranston.
Yes, we've met.
Would you, uh, care to join us?
Miss Lane, the fact that
your father is acting strangely,
I don't think really calls
for a police investigation.
Look, I just want to see him.
The War Department says he's suddenly
decided to take no visitors,
not even his own daughter.
Well, chances are he's working
on some top secret.
It is a government project,
you know.
No, his project is harmless.
Energy research...
some kind of implosive device.
Look, I know something's wrong.
I spoke to him on the phone.
He was distant,
confused, babbling.
He spoke to me in Chinese.
- Uh, wai... waiter.
- He doesn't even speak Chinese!
I'm sorry, please.
Tomorrow, I'll, uh, send a policeman
over to the Federal Building.
You'll see your father
and everything'll be fine, all right?
What's your opinion, Mr. Cra...
Excuse me.
Mm?
Thanks.
Lamont!
Wait a second, Lamont.
I wanted to ask you
about my father.
I have to go.
Ying Ko.
Who's Ying Ko?
Uh!
You will forget about me.
Why would I do that?
You will give me
no further thought.
Are you drunk?
Look, Mr. Cranston, I don't know
what kind of woman
you're used to dealing with, but I
certainly don't appreciate being...
Hey!
Taxi, taxi!
The Federal Building.
You got it, boss.
Pizza?
Yechh.
Well, I'm not going
to eat a burger again.
I'm not asking you
to eat a burger.
You like fish?
How about a burger?
Uh!
Next time you get to be on top.
Where is Khan?
I will not tell you.
What are you doing?
Hold on or you'll die.
Yes, to serve my Khan.
I sense somebody's coming.
- Uh.
- Wooh!
Drive.
Hello?
- Hello, Margo.
- Oh, Dad.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine, dear.
I need to see you right away.
At the lab.
Are you there now?
Hurry.
Oh no, no, no.
Oh, God.
Dad!
Dad, where are you?
Oh, God, no.
Margo Lane.
I have a mission for you,
my dear.
Margo Lane.
What are you doing here?
You're in my home.
I am?
Your home?
- What are you doing here?
- I don't know.
- Who sent you?
There was a voice
over and over in my head.
It said I had
to kill the Shadow.
I want you to leave right now.
I had to kill the Shadow
and I came here.
I said I want you
to leave right now.
And there was only you.
Get out.
Let me see into your eyes.
You want to see into my eyes?
- I think I know something...
- Go ahead.
- I didn't before.
- Look at them.
- There's something strange about you.
- I could feel it.
- But I've got to warn you,
- you won't like what you see.
Static in my head
whenever I was near you.
I knew it.
You're the Shadow.
My father's disappeared.
You're the only one
who can help me find him.
Just be gone when I get back.
How do you know I won't tell
anyone who you really are?
I know.
To The Sanctum.
Nice tie.
Thank you.
By the way, you sent
Margo Lane to kill me.
Kill you?
If I wanted you dead, Ying Ko,
I would have your liver on pole by now.
I sent a girl to be killed.
Tell me, how did you kill her?
She's alive.
And she's a danger to you.
She now knows
exactly who you are.
How long will you let her live?
How long before
your pure instincts take over?
I'm onto your plan, Khan.
You still don't have
the beryllium sphere.
And without it,
you can't complete the bomb.
Besides, you know
I'm going to stop you.
You American are so arrogant.
You think your meaningless,
decadent country
is the new cradle
of civilization.
- But let me tell you something.
- Hey.
That's the US of A
you're talking about, pal.
I am talking
about ruling the world.
I'd like to give you a name.
Leonard Levinski,
brilliant psychiatrist.
- You'll talk, he'll listen.
- You are boring me!
Oh, that knife.
Recognize it.
I took it from The Tulku.
No, no, no, I correct myself.
I took it out of The Tulku
after I ran it through his heart.
When will you learn to listen
to your instincts?
Instincts?
I'll show you my instincts.
Never did master
the Phurba, did you?
Still expect it
to respond to brute force.
My Mongol warrior
aren't terribly bright.
But they are loyal.
Accept the truth.
There is no light
without shadow.
And you and I are their shadow.
I would sooner destroy
a Rembrandt than kill you.
For the last time,
will you join me?
You cannot fool me.
You cannot defeat me.
Your mind is an open book to me.
Then learn how to read.
Uh!
Weakling.
Ka Khan!
Tail 'em, Moe.
He's disappeared, boss.
Stop the car.
It's just an empty lot, boss.
I can't help that I know
what I know about you.
And I can't forget it either.
It's late.
Sleep here if you like.
There are guest rooms.
But in the morning
you should go.
I'm not afraid of you.
But I am.
Lamont.
Oh, my God.
Good morning.
Oh, God, I dreamed.
So did I.
What did you dream?
I was lying naked on the beach
in the South Seas.
And the tide was
coming up over my toes.
The sun was beating down.
My skin was...
hot and cool at the same time.
It was wonderful.
What was yours?
I dreamed I tore
all the skin off my face
and was somebody else
underneath.
You have problems.
I'm aware of that.
I'll wait for you outside
while you get dressed.
Oh, that's okay.
You can stay.
Oh, these are all rumpled.
Uh, well, there might be some things
in here that you could use.
Uh, yeah.
- This belonged to, uh, my Aunt Rose.
- Oh, really.
Very fashionable gal, that Rose.
- Mm-mm, kept her figure too.
- Ah, yeah.
Well, I've gotta run.
I've got a, uh...
Taxi waiting downstairs?
Excuse me?
Oh, I just sensed that's what
you were going to say.
It is, isn't it?
- Yes.
- Huh!
Say this is getting easier
the more I'm around you.
You're like reading a book.
Well, thank you very much, Lamont,
but I won't be needing that taxi.
Whoa, yes, you do.
I have a very important...
Oh, great, I'll come with you.
- Uh, no, last night we agreed...
- Uh, no, I didn't agree to anything.
Do you mind if I just get
one tiny little sentence out here?
Thank you very much.
Last night we both agreed that
you were going to leave this morning.
No, you agreed
I was going to leave.
I agreed to no such thing.
We need each other.
- No we don't.
- We have a connection.
No we don't.
Then how do you explain that
I can read your thoughts?
- My thoughts are hard to miss.
- And why is that?
Psychically,
I'm very well endowed.
I'll bet you are.
Okay, so you don't need me,
but I need you, Lamont,
to help me find my father.
And I am coming with you.
Okay.
Empire State Building pennants.
Get your Empire State
Building pennants.
From there to there.
That is just the explosion.
The destruction
will be incalculable.
Good.
Ahh, what a beautiful day.
Nice dress, toots.
- Come on along and listen to...
- Get me down!
Hey, Bobby, what the hell
are you doing?
- I have no idea.
- No, don't do it.
Get me down.
Get me down from here.
The lullaby of Broadway.
Get me down.
Get me down!
It's all falling
into place for me now.
Shiwan Khan needs a beryllium sphere
to complete the bomb.
I wonder where
he intends to find one.
Beryllium sphere?
- Farley Claymore.
- What's that?
Farley Claymore,
my father's assistant.
He was working on a beryllium sphere,
I'm sure of it.
- In your father's lab?
- No, no, he was working on his own.
- Uh, Maritech Labs down on Southside.
- Good, very good.
Do your sleeping at home, will ya?
Get out of the way!
Hey, I got something else
I want you to do for me.
Of course, what?
I was trailing Khan when
I suddenly lost him
on the corner of Second Avenue
and Houston Street.
There's something very strange
about that corner.
It's a vacant lot now, but I want
you to find out what used to be there.
Second and Houston.
What about Farley Claymore?
Mr. Claymore's gonna
receive a little visit
from the Shadow.
Farley Claymore.
Who's that?
Where is the beryllium sphere,
Claymore?
sphere?
What sphere?
Claymore, you idiot!
You're being manipulated.
Your mind is being controlled
by hypnosis.
My mind?
Controlled?
Claymore, what have you done
with the sphere?
It's too late.
I loaded it on a truck.
Take me to it now!
Who do you think you're gonna shoot
with that, Claymore?
Uh!
No one controls my mind, Shadow!
There's a new
world order coming.
And I'm gonna be a king.
A king!
Margo.
Margo, I need you.
You called?
Lamont?
You are not supposed to be here.
Lamont.
You were dreaming.
You saw.
Do you have any idea
what it's like
to have done things
you can never
forgive yourself for?
Lamont...
whoever you were,
whatever you did...
it's in the past.
Not for me, Margo.
Never for me.
We are victorious.
And as victors, we will collect
the spoils of war.
I will remember each of you.
Particularly my special servant.
The only American
with genius enough
to join me of his own free will.
Khan.
Who saw himself
a king in my kingdom.
King?
Did Is ay king?
Maybe not the best
choice of words.
No, it wasn't.
Because actually
I was thinking prince, tops.
Not even necessarily.
Uh, duke, baron?
You're choice, of course.
Your choice.
Get Dr. Lane.
Assemble the bomb!
Of course.
In the name of the new Kha Khan.
The power of God on Earth.
The Emperor of Mankind.
Extra, extra, read all about it.
Madman threatens
to blow the city sky-high.
Residents of New York City were
thrown into a virtual panic today.
Police were still trying to determine
if, in fact, the threat was real
or merely an incredible hoax.
Either way,
surely the work of a madman.
Morning, Russell.
He's demanded works of art,
famous jewels, even gold.
Find Khan and you'll find
the bomb, I bet.
What did you find out
about that vacant lot?
Not much, I'm afraid.
It was the site
of the old Hotel Monolith.
It was finished nearly ten years ago,
but it never opened.
The Monolith.
I vaguely remember that.
Seems that's the only way
anybody remembers it.
Before the hotel was completed,
the developer went bankrupt
and committed suicide.
Ah.
The, uh, last record is a sale
to a Far Eastern buyer
six years ago.
When was it torn down?
It doesn't say.
I made some calls this morning
to newspapers and such.
All anybody can remember is
up to the time it was sold.
Everyone seems
to know that it was torn down,
but they can't remember
when or by whom.
Or if.
I can't believe he did it.
Did what?
Lamont?
My God.
It's beautiful.
What is?
Hey, hey, fella.
That building right there,
what's the name of that building?
Lunatic.
Shiwan Khan has
hypnotized the entire city!
They don't see it.
None of them see it.
But I see it.
You and Shrevnitz
will receive your instructions.
I want you
to follow them exactly.
Lamont.
Bet you wish you'd been a little nicer
to me now, huh, don't ya?
Bet you wish you'd listened
to my ideas?
Bet you didn't count
on me being friends
with a conqueror,
huh, did ya, did ya?
Hey, that's enough.
Activate the bomb.
Set the timer for two hours.
You are certain
you could duplicate
this bomb's design
any time I require?
Absolutely, no problem.
That makes Dr. Lane obsolete.
Secure him in a room.
He'll die at the hands
of his own invention.
Yes, my Khan.
Listen, I know
you must have this covered,
but shouldn't we be
getting out of here too?
There's an aeroplane waiting
to take us all to safety.
We leave in one hour.
What is it, Moe?
Is it another one of those things
from the bowling league?
Mm-hm.
" Uh!
Ying Ko.
The Shadow.
Where?
Not here, you idiot.
In the building.
Can you tell if he's mad at me?
We had a little
misunderstanding yesterday
and there might
still be hard feelings.
Find him and kill him!
Kill him?
- Me?
- All of you!
Couldn't I just stay here
and help you?
Go!
You guys go that way.
Did you think you'd
never see me again, Claymore?
I'm right here.
All around you.
Everywhere around you.
Coward!
Chicken, sissy!
Come out here
and fight like a man!
You're a fool, Claymore.
Get out of my sight!
There's your exit, Claymore.
You know what I love
about this job?
The excitement.
Ah, Ying Ko, I surrender.
You're finished, Khan.
Uh!
Phurba.
You are losing
your concentration.
Your mind is too weak.
You are beginning
to lose your power.
Look at you.
Can't even control yourself.
How can you hope
to control Phurba?
Stop!
My God.
That's what he saw.
Mm.
Where am I?
Ka Khan!
Khan!
- Dad.
- Margo.
- Oh, are you all right?
- Where am I?
What is going on here?
- Well, there's this guy...
- Mm-hm.
I'll tell you later.
- Moe, go call the police.
- Okay.
Look, there it is.
Oh, my God!
Oh, this is impressive work.
Who did this?
You did.
We only have an hour left.
Disconnect it.
Hm, cut this off.
Oh.
Dad, the timer...
You gotta stop it.
Oh dear.
Hah!
Two minutes left.
Oh, my God, hurry.
Hurry, Dad.
This way.
Oh, my God, it's upstairs.
Oh, no, the elevator!
Be careful.
Which wire?
I don't remember.
I just don't remember.
Pick one!
Oh, well, what the hell,
it's usually green.
No, green!
This is green.
That's red.
I've gotta try to remember that.
Oh.
What are you doing?
Where the hell
did that come from?
What is this?
Where am I, huh?
You, come here.
Look at me.
Look into my eyes.
Yes.
Release me at once.
No, we won't have
any of that, Mr. Khan.
Let's just have a look
at those stitches, shall we?
Stitches.
What... what have you done?
Saved your life, that's what.
Of course, we had to remove
a little section of your frontal lobe.
But you'll never miss it,
believe me.
It's a part nobody ever uses.
But... huh?
Unless you believe
in telepathy.
Wait!
Come back here!
You, come here!
I am Shiwan Khan, the last
descendant of Genghis Khan!
Listen to me!
I'm Houdini!
I am Theodore Roosevelt.
I am Napoleon.
I'm Josephine.
I'm Babe Ruth.
I'll see you later.
Hey, how will you know
where I am?
I'll know.