You join us
live outside the state prison...
to witness the arrival
of Nathan and Erin Randall,
the father and sister
of the murdered Lauren Randall.
The impending state execution of
Alex Corvis may provide the Randalls,
and what seems the majority of this
crowd, with some form of justice.
- Why are there so many?
-Just hold on to me.
Back, back.
Mr. Randall, sir, do
you think this execution...
will bring you a sense of closure
for you and your daughter?
Erin, your sister has been
gone for three years now.
Can you tell us anything?
A difficult time
for everyone involved.
Interesting fact: It will take
about 21 cents of electricity...
to execute Alex Corvis tonight,
on this, his 21st birthday.
He didn't order that.
We found the man
with the scar.
Go ahead,
make a wish.
Get it out of here.
Oh, yes, I've come to a lot
of these over the years,
but this one has, well,
many unique aspects.
The youth of the condemned.
Now, that's unusual.
And 53 stab wounds!
Hmph! Kind of a record.
- And Corvis still
maintaining his innocence?
- Oh, they all say that.
I saw those two fighting that day.
Facing the chair,
you do what you gotta do.
You okay?
What's been
holding me together...
is the hope that maybe
you do go someplace.
I'll be seein' her
again soon, you know.
Only what can I say?
That I was too stupid
to find the guy that killed her?
That he's down here laughin'?
Tell her...
we'll get him.
"We" won't.
Someday he'll surface,
and I'll get him for both of you.
I promise.
I'll find the guy with the scar.
This mystery man with the scar,
the zigzag, whatever?
We couldn't find him.
Obviously the jury didn't buy it.
-Some people here seem to.
- Look.
People here are protesting
execution of a kid turned 21 .
A kid who had a tough life.
No parents, no dough,
always had to fight for everything.
It's a tragedy.
It really is.
If I was facing the hot seat,
I'd want my attorney...
banging down the door to the Supreme
Court, not playing some board game.
But maybe that's just me.
Your move.
No. It's time.
I don't want you to watch.
I don't want to give 'em
the pleasure.
Come on now.
"The Lord
is my shepherd, I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
He leadeth me
beside the still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the paths
of righteousness for His name's sake.
Yea, though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death...
I will fear no evil...
for Thou art with me.
Thy rod and Thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table
before me...
in the presence
of mine enemies.
Thou anointest my head
with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy...
shall follow me...
all the days of my life...
and I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever."
Alexander Frederick Corvis,
do you have any last words?
I loved Lauren.
I still do.
I'm innocent.
Murderer!
Look at that.
Goddamn helmet
melted his skin off.
That's what I call
a deterrent.
Oops.
Why do they bother
autopsying these guys?
I mean, the cause of death
is pretty fucking obvious.
Go on to the car,
honey. Go on.
Mr. Randall, we all wish this
would have ended better, sir.
We've got unauthorized
movement on B-5.
I repeat. Unauthorized movement, B-4,
B-2, all of section " B" and section "C."
We have an escape in progress.
I repeat, an escape in progress.
- Mercer, are you down there?
- This is Mercer. I'm on it.
They're heading
for the roof.
All prisoners present and accounted for.
Then who's fucking Houdini?
- What? Police? Evidence?
There's nothing
under "Crow."
" Execution"?
- Lauren!
What are you trying
to say here?
I'm all yours.
His knife!
- Corvis.
-  You lie!
You lie!
Thomas Leonard.
Shit.
I thought
I'd be with you now.
I'm not dead.
And I'm not alive.
And I'm remembering.
And it hurts.
Your Shaolin style
is no match for my kung fu.
Your flying crane style...
is no match for
my drunken tiger kick.
Aww.
Your mad monkey love...
is no match--
I can't be alive.
Not without you.
I want to be with you
forever.
- I want to be with you forever.
- Only forever?
It's okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Don't come near me!
- I was a friend of your sister's.
- I know her friends.
That locket
you're holding.
- You have one just like it.
- No kidding.
Your father gave them
to both of you.
He's right over there
by the way.
What did you do
to your face?
- Someone else did it.
- You're a friend of the guy
who killed Lauren, aren't you?
- You almost sound like him.
- He didn't kill her.
- How do you know?
- I know everything about your sister.
I'll prove it to you.
Stay away from me!
Dad!
- Dad.
- Are you all right?
There's this guy.
He said he was a friend of Lauren's.
He had paint all over his face.
He was here!
He was right here!
Marcy!
She's resting, Thomas.
Where the fuck
did you come from?
Big bang, primordial ooze?
Divine hand
ofa benevolent creator?
All possibilities. Although,
recent events have given me doubts...
about the
benevolent creator.
- You lied at my trial, Thomas.
- I don't even know you, man.
Capital case 99-C1 1 5.
Alex Corvis!
Exhibit "A."
Hey, I said what I saw.
Two kids arguing. A guy and a girl.
No, you said you saw me
with this.
I never held it
until today.
What's your damage, man? Corvis hacked
up that girl like a motherfucker!
One chance to tell
the truth, Tommy.
Who is the man
with the scar?
He planted this
in my car.
There's no scar.
Corvis made it up.
Wrong answer!
They showed me pictures,
what he did to her.
Evidence.
Said all I had to do was
stand up there and nod my head "yes."
What did they give you?
Ajob!
Construction.
Twelve an hour.
Write their names down.
You've already got 'em all
right here.
These cops said they needed
an eyewitness or Corvis would walk.
Oh.
Is there a problem?
Let's hope not.
- License and registration, please.
- Yeah.
What's with
your friend there?
She's sick.
- Actually, she never had
Mai Tais before.
- But you've had 'em.
Oh, not tonight.
Honest.
If you had a license,
I bet I'd have seen it by now.
How old are you?
What?
Fifteen?
Look, I'll tell you the truth.
Jannie drove us and
was supposed to drive us back.
She has a license, but--
I mean, look at her.
Jannie, get up.
Come on, get up!
Getup!
Why don't you get out?
Want me to walk
a straight line?
- I want you to bend over.
- Can I just call a cab?
What'd I say?
Very nice.
Maybe I'll just ask
your friend here.
I want you to bend over,
Officer Dutton.
What the fuck did you--
Get out of the car. Now!
Hey, punk!
- Get your hands on the car.
- These hands?
You're dead, ditch weed.
Oh, my God!
- You're up!
Ladies, drive carefully.
You might want to call 9-1 -1 .
Report an officer down.
That was a fucking
hollow point!
Guess it's true.
Guns don't kill people.
Think, uh,
like maybe knives do?
Keep that thing
away from me.
Phillip, this is not
just some "thing."
It's "AC-005."
You're the skell that broke into
the evidence room.
Fuck!
What do you want?
A scar
on the arm...
of the man who planted this
in Alex Corvis's car.
There was no scar, you freak.
The Corvis kid made it up.
He was innocent.
You killed him!
You and Erlich
and Roberts and Toomey.
What do you think,
Officer Dutton, huh?
An eye for an eye?
- Get her!
You were there?
All four of you?
You killed her!
I saw it!
Bitch killed herself
when she shot a cop in the foot.
If she had just shut up and acted like
a girl, nothing would have happened.
So you're right, spooky.
You happy?
I'm working on it.
- Police!
- Fuck! What the fuck?
Don't do that, man.
That's fuckin' really cool.
Thank you.
So, how'd the month
end up?
- Fantastic.
- Yeah.
- Never been better.
Where's Dutton?
Probably parked in front of
some high school with a hard-on.
The fuck never showed up.
- You know why Dutton's not here?
- No.
Rigor mortis.
Dead!
One shot to the head.
Then 53 stab wounds
with a six-inch blade.
This cause any kind of deja vu
for you guys?
Rumors multiply as police
refuse to confirm or deny reports
of multiple, multiple stab wounds.
- Dad, come in here.
- Yeah, what is it, honey?
- That cop who found
the knife in Corvis's car.
-  They're moving him now.
Body covered. It would appear
that 37-year-old Phillip Dutton
is dead in the line of duty.
Let's go.
Watch her. What are you doing?
Get back behind the line.
Get back there right now.
It's shocking,
even for these mean streets.
The word "Daisy"
carved into his forehead
by the perpetrator still at large.
A name?
Perhaps a message.
What's the matter, honey?
Lauren used to call me that
when we were little.
Daisy.
Nobody knew but us.
Honey, it doesn't mean anything.
It's not a message.
No, that guy at the cemetery said
he knew everything about Lauren.
It still doesn't
mean anything.
He said he'd prove it.
Come on,
you're hiding something!
I don't know anything
about any knife.
- I'm tryin' to forget that case.
- Well, someone isn't.
They killed Dutton.
- It wasn't me.
- No shit.
You couldn't get close to him.
But I am betting...
that you know who did.
You're the only one who gave a flying
fuck about him when he was alive.
- Lauren Randall did.
- Yeah, well, bitches are crazy.
The richer they are,
the crazier they get.
Yeah? Maybe if you hadn't
fried an innocent kid--
Who is it?
Maybe it's the real killer.
Did you ever think of that? Huh?
If you're covering up for someone,
that's jail time.
I've got my eye on you.
Queen to bishop five.
"Check."
Don't move.
Fuck me.
I heard you were looking
for this.
You're the guy
who killed Dutton.
The way I see it,
I want you to think of me
as the guy who killed you.
I'm a police officer, man!
Yeah? What happened
to your leg there, Officer?
Is that like
a hunting accident, huh?
Lauren Randall shot you
trying to get free.
The 53 stab wounds
she died of came from you!
Am I right?
Ballpark?
What the fuck do you want?
I want Lauren! I want my life back!
I wanna know why!
It's all money, man!
The girl just got in the way.
The scar.
Which of you has it?
Nobody. It's just a bullshit fucking
story the loser boyfriend made up.
Are you out of your fuckin' mind?
We're gonna die!
How can you die
if you're already dead?
You're him... Corvis.
Go, go!
C'mon!
Here, here, take it.
Fuck!
Daisy.
How did you know?
I told you.
I knew her.
You killed that cop,
Dutton.
And another one.
Erlich.
Took a wrong turn.
I know who you are.
That's why
you paint your face.
To hide.
I'm not hiding.
I'm right here.
You killed Lauren!
You killed her!
Not me! Dirty cops killed her.
Dutton and Erlich!
My dad was right.
He said you'd ruin her life.
No!
Listen to me!
Lauren found out something
they didn't want her to know. This!
Look at it.
Because you need
to understand.
You need to be careful.
I'm sorry.
Your father...
wasn't right.
All right, all right!
Listen up!
Yo!
We've got a cop killer
out there.
Till we get some I.D.,
treat everyone like a suspect.
He knows. I saw him.
He's got a fucking zombie mask.
- Calm down.
- No, you calm down!
Whose name's next on the fucking list,
huh? It's not yours.
You didn't testify.
You're not on the list.
- Scary guy.
- Yeah, scary.
He survives that crash,
takes time out for art?
Madden, the old man's requested
the pleasure of your company.
All right, boys and girls, to quote John
Wilkes Booth, "Just watch your backs."
- Glad I'm not you.
- Right back at ya.
Sit down.
I thought we had
an understanding.
I thought we understood
that discretion is paramount.
- Yeah, we do.
- Shut up!
Erlich gimping around in his
goddamn hot rod is not discreet.
I've got reporters
asking me how much he made.
I've got the entire force
looking at this case now.
- I know.
- You know.
I know... the guy,
he leaves a sign.
No shit he leaves a sign!
He's goddamn Picasso.
What else do you know?
You know this?
Tommy Leonard.
The eyewitness in the Corvis case.
Some hooker phoned it in. There was
a riot at his apartment yesterday.
- Guy dressed for Halloween?
- Good for you. You do know something.
Don't... say.
Just do.
Before this whole thing
comes tumbling down.
- Idiots.
What are you doing?
Um, I dropped
an earring.
Well, it looks like
you've got them both on.
Alex Corvis
didn't kill Lauren.
Cops did,
didn't they?
You're in with them.
- It isn't what you think.
- You killed her!
No! Erin!
It wasn't supposed to happen!
- Stay away from me!
- Erin, please.
It wasn't supposed to happen.
- She found out.
- About you?
About them. You have to
leave this alone, sweetheart.
Don't call me that!
Don't call me anything!
I would never do anything
to hurt Lauren or you.
- You have to believe me.
- I don't believe you.
- Please.
- They killed Alex because of you, Dad.
Now you killed
both of them.
- Please, leave him alone.
- Get your hands off me.
Calm down!
Put your hand down!
- I'm not makin' this up.
He had a crow with him.
- That's what you're tellin' me.
He said I lied at his trial.
It's Alex Corvis.
So now we're talkin'
about a ghost...
with a fuckin' pet bird,
is that right?
- Turn that--
Turn that fuckin' baby down!
- I wanna show you somethin'.
See this? See this here?
Come here. I wanna show you something,
all right? See that?
My name's next on his list.
It's fuckin' next.
I want you to tell me
who it is, Tommy.
- It's Corvis. It's Alex--
- Take your time.
I want you to think about it.
'Cause you gotta give me something other
than this bullshit you been spewin'.
He said the whole trial
was a setup.
He said I caused an innocent kid
to die. Is that true?
Is that true?
Come on.
Check... and mate.
Dream on.
Oh, my God.
That really is you under there.
Two down.
Two to go.
Down?
Wait, don't tell me.
The cops...
at my trial.
They killed Lauren.
The whole thing was fixed.
You think I'm crazy.
I'm thinking...
it explains a lot.
Lauren's father
is involved.
He bought these cops
fancy cars.
And I don't know
what else.
It's a company
called D-E-R-T.
I think Lauren
found out.
What-- What do they do
that they had to kill her?
I was hoping
you'd find out.
I sure will.
What's with this bird?
Keeps hangin' around.
This is where
it happened.
Yeah, I know.
Are you okay?
When Lauren was missing,
the cops came
to our house.
They said they were looking
for her, right?
But now I know
they had her.
And the reason
they brought her here,
and they knew they could blame it
on you, is that I sent them here!
I told them she came here sometimes
with her dirtball boyfriend!
That's exactly what I said!
Erin, it's not your fault.
Oh, God, I wish I were dead.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
There were four of them!
- Get her out of the car.
- C'mon, baby.
- No! No! No!
- Hold on. C'mon, baby!
- No! No!
Be nice, would ya?
You wanna see a little somethin'?
Four large men, and still
she grabbed one of their guns.
And she ran.
She ran for her life!
I don't wanna know!
She ran, them breathing
down her neck...
all the way
from the road...
to here.
Here's where it happened.
She turned and faced them
and went down,
kicking, and punching...
and tearing at them
as they stabbed her.
Fifty-three times.
She fought
for her life...
because life
is worth living.
Think about that.
And you tell me how much
you wish you were dead.
- Why wasn't this incident reported?
- Nothing to report.
All the prisoners
were present and accounted for.
- So you pretended nothing happened?
- Hey, Corvis fried.
I don't see how
it could've been him.
No, I wouldn't
expect you to.
Be forewarned. Nature takes its toll.
Bon appetit.
Okay, you lost him.
Now clear out.
- They botched the execution.
- Yeah, you could say that.
Christ! It was Corvis.
Tommy Leonard was right.
Hey, babe?
Fuckin' crow.
Sign of the dead
come back to life.
How about sign of
a big black bird?
The dead can return
given sufficient motivation.
And Corvis has that.
I've studied this phenomenon before.
He's looking for something.
Won't stop
till he finds it.
Sometimes, the best way
to get rid of someone is...
to let them have what they want.
The man with the scar.
Give him the man with
the scar, then he'll lose his powers.
The man with the scar...
took everything
I ever cared about.
Left me with nothing.
So you're going
to kill him?
I have to find him first.
You know what Lauren and I
were fighting about that night?
She had a secret.
Wouldn't tell me.
My father.
All I knew was
she was pulling away.
It made me crazy.
I used to be
so proud of him.
My big-deal daddy.
And now...
he's just a crook.
Worse even.
And the weird thing is...
I wish I could hate him,
but I can't.
He said he'd never hurt
either of us.
And I know it's true.
And I'm going back.
It's what Lauren
would do.
I wanna forget.
Forget everything.
Keep it.
It connects you to Lauren.
And it connects you to me.
No matter what happens,
I'll make sure everyone knows
that you're innocent.
That you loved her.
If you need me,
you know where to find me.
- You know it doesn't work this way.
- I'm out of this, John.
Partner ships
don't end like that.
Friendships don't.
Our friendship...
ended when Lauren died.
Do you believe in ghosts, Nathan?
- Because there's a ghost
threatening us.
- You mean Alex.
I mean Lauren.
Because you never accepted that
what happened to her was an accident.
Your men
killed my daughter.
- An accident, Nathan.
- She was 1 8 years old.
There were four of them.
They stabbed her 53 times.
Where's the accident, John?
Where's the fucking accident?
I watched her grow up,
just like you.
I know how her mind worked.
She was snooping around
because she was worried about you,
about what you'd
gotten yourself into.
So stop blaming me...
and blame yourself.
I do... every day.
Erin knows,
doesn't she?
Don't bother.
You never were a good liar.
Look at this.
Everything we've worked for.
Now, you tell me.
What are we going to do?
Dad? You home?
D-E-R-T is owned
by Westwind Builders,
Nathan Randall's company.
But DERT, in turn, owns
a dozen other corporations.
That's a big mess to wade through,
so I checked out Tommy Leonard.
Leonard, Dutton, Erlich.
They don't matter.
You understand?
I want the king.
We're getting there because,
in his so-called construction job,
Tommy makes a daily delivery
to a place called The Key Club.
- The strip joint?
- I believe they call it
a connoisseur's club.
Owned by DERT.
Places like this,
they're about unreported cash,
processing money from drugs,
prostitution.
So I took a chance.
I called over there,
asking for Roberts and Toomey,
the two other cops.
Whoever answered said, "They're not
here. This is the front office."
They killed my dad.
I can't take it.
Erin?
Erin? Who?
I don't know.
I found him lying there.
Where is it, this place?
- I think we should get some support.
- What, call the police?
What is this?
Where are you going?
1 31 5 Berkeley Street.
Hey, you have some I.D., pal?
Circus in town, or what?
How old are you?
You have one chance
to value your life.
Take it.
We'll be safe in my car.
Nobody will recognize it.
We'll put yours in back.
You followed me here.
No.
Erin, I put a bulletin out
on your car because...
there's bad news, and I thought
you should hear it from me.
Your father got involved
with some bad cops on my force.
So I take responsibility.
He killed himself.
How?
How'd he kill himself?
With a gun.
With a gun, right? When there wasn't
one anywhere near where you found him!
- You killed him.
- Erin, don't.
- Back the fuck off now!
- He left this.
There's names, addresses.
There's a note to you.
These people he got involved with,
they killed Lauren.
He couldn't bear it anymore.
Oh, my God, he's right.
It's all here.
The note.
Show it to me.
Not you!
It's right here.
Look, under here.
Look.
You need help?
Finish him.
Lauren?
You were here?
Hey. Hey, c'mon. Wake up. Wake up.
Hey. Come on, Sampson,
wake up. Come on.
You awake, Sampson?
You awake?
Not anymore.
Shit. That's Randall's daughter.
She saw us.
Go, go, go!
Get her!
Gentlemen.
Cheers.
Find him!
Go.
Toomey!
Spark, gas.
Bad combination.
And it's not this leak here that's
the least of your worries, ya know?
You're him.
Jesus, you're Corvis!
We fried your ass!
You're a dead man!
- Good thing, in a situation like this.
- You're a fuckin' zombie.
Son of a bitch.
- The scar!
- There is no scar!
It's over.
I'm losing you.
Come on, Alex.
Lauren?
What'd you do that for?
He's bleeding.
I don't--
I don't bleed.
Erin?
The king.
I hate that picture.
Where is she?
Can I get you something?
Glass of water?
Transfusion?
Last chance.
Where's Erin?
Or what? You'll bleed
all over my carpet?
You know,
crime was actually down
before you showed up.
Or, uh,
stuck around, or whatever the hell
you're doing here.
What are you doing here?
I'm looking for my friend.
See, I heard you were looking
for some guy with a scar.
How's that going?
Did you find him?
Yes? No?
You're like the guest
who would not leave.
And, judging by your condition,
maybe you've overstayed your welcome.
It's not a criticism,
it's just an observation.
Oh.
I don't think you're gonna use it.
That's Lauren's knife.
You come in here so full of righteous
indignation. What have you got to be...
so righteous about,
huh?
How many innocent people
did you leave dead back there?
I had no choice.
You sent them.
Bullshit! You're a killer,
that's all you are.
Just a clown with a bird
and a rising death toll.
You think the world
did you wrong? Huh?
You did the world wrong.
You and Lauren had a fight,
and you couldn't let it go.
- What is your problem?
- Why won't you tell me?
- I can't tell you!
I just--
I just can't. I--
- Come back here! Come here!
- No! Stop!
It was bad enough her dad
rejected you, but when she did...
-you lost it.
- You're wrong.
Yeah? Well, I see doubt
oozing out all over you.
Where do people go
who kill their girlfriends?
- Screwed-up kid.
-
He stabbed her 53 times.
Where will he end up?
Take a look, you sick fuck!
That's who you are.
Are you looking?
Every loser name anybody
ever called you is true.
- Are you looking?
I never meant to hurt her.
You see it?
Alexander Frederick Corvis,
do you have any last words?
I loved Lauren.
I never meant
to hurt her.
Did you see it?
Yeah, I think
you fuckin' saw it.
Lucky, huh? I guess
he found the arm you planted.
A fake picture's worth
a thousand words, huh?
Just don't believe
everything you see.
Doubt is a motherfucker.
Give me a hand
with this sack of shit.
Oh, he's cute!
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Was cute.
All but the face.
Well, makeup
can work for you...
or against you,
right?
All done.
Very nice.
- You're such a good listener.
-  Clear the table.
I've read about this,
but I never thought I'd see it.
So, was he alive
or dead?
I've seen birds stuffed
and mounted so lifelike...
you'd swear
you saw them breathing.
Yeah, maybe we've got a case
of that here. Get me my kit.
The two of you are majorly demented.
You know that?
He should've gone home when he found the
scar we planted. He came to save her.
Caring for the living.
Not part of his job description.
- Fifty-three?
- In all the excitement,
I guess I lost count.
Think I'll mount him
with his head up his ass.
- Grab it!
And it connects you to me.
No matter what happens,
I'll make sure
everyone knows...
that you're innocent.
I promise.
Everything you ever showed me,
all lies.
- I'll kill her.
- No!
Oh, I'd love to hurt ya!
- Got you!
That bird!
Kill it!
You brought him back.
Good.
He owes you.
Where did they go?
- I know you too well. You won't do it.
- You don't know me at all.
Aah! God!
There's only one in the chamber.
That's all you get.
Holy mother of God!
The devil himself.
What the fuck?
The jolt,
eight amps
at 2,000 to 3,000 volts.
It lasts a few seconds.
The current surges
and is turned off.
Then they check to see
if the heart is still beating.
If it is... ba-boom!
Another jolt is applied.
Experts say
unconsciousness...
occurs before pain
has time to register.
They agree
that electrocution...
does not hurt.
But it does.
Unimaginably...
believe me.
I... don't expect a call
from the governor.
Any last words...
Captain?
Yeah.
Fuck you!
Was that it?
I'm not dying for your goddamn
illusions! You got that?
You think you and your girl friend
had some rosy future taken
from you? Bullshit!
She was already bored. Why do
you think she was lookin' around?
You're nothing, Corvis.
Less than nothing!
You can't do this to me,
you little fucks!
You hear me?
You understand?
I'll be back!
Just like you! A big,
fucking, shit-spewing bird!
And guess which little bitch
I'm taking out first!
You are so dead.
Erin?
I'll always be with you,
and so will Lauren.
Alex, look.
In that moment, when
Alex went, I knew I was making a choice.
To be alive in the world.
I'm thinking of them...
hoping that sometimes
they're thinking of me.