Mutants. Since the discovery
of their existence,
they have been regarded
with fear, suspicion, often hatred.
Across the planet debate rages.
Are mutants the next link
in the evolutionary chain?
Or simply a new species of humanity,
fighting for their share of the world?
Either way, it is an historical fact
sharing the world has never been
humanity's defining attribute.
"We are not enemies, but friends.
We must not be enemies."
"Though passion may have strained, it
must not break the bonds of our affection."
Lincoln said that in his first inaugural
address as our nation's 16th president.
It's one of my favourites.
If you'll please have your tickets ready,
we can begin the tour.
Jackie, clear my schedule.
I'm having dinner with my son.
Yes, Mr President.
Excuse me, sir. Are you lost?
Perimeter breach at visitors' checkpoint.
Multiple subjects.
Mr President, security breach.
Jackie, leave. Get him to the car.
Exits not clear. Unknown how many.
Both sides secure.
- Something's in the corridor.
- To the shelter.
Not clear.
- It's outside the Oval Office.
- Lock this place down.
Don't shoot!
My God.
Neanderthals. We once believed that
they were wiped out by years of conflict
with the much more advanced branch
of humanity called Cro-Magnon man,
but recent research into our DNA suggests
that these two species may have interbred,
evolving into modern humans.
In other words, into what?
- Us.
- That's right.
Artie.
Not here.
Come on. Pay attention.
...makes me insane when she does this...
What are you looking at? Sick...
To the shelter.
They're gonna kill him.
Jean? You OK?
Yeah, I'm fine.
It's just a headache.
It's not just a headache, is it?
I wasn't sure how to say this,
but since Liberty Island you've been...
- Scott.
- You've been different.
My telepathy's been off lately.
I can't focus. I hear everything.
Jean, it's not just your telepathy.
A month ago you had to concentrate
just to levitate a book.
Now when you have a nightmare
the entire bedroom shakes.
My dreams are getting worse.
I keep feeling
something terrible's about to happen.
I would never let anything happen to you.
Have you guys seen Bobby and Rogue?
Something's happening in the food court.
- It's a simple question.
- Why are you being a dick?
Yeah, why are you being such a dick?
Because I can.
Can I have a light?
- Sorry. Can't help you out, pal.
- John, knock it off.
- Why don't you stop showing off?
- For her?
- I can't help it if your girl's getting excited.
- She isn't.
- We're trying to have a good time.
- You're the only one having a good time.
That's real cute, man.
What are you gonna do?
Suddenly you're not so tough.
Bobby, what did you do?
I didn't do this.
No. I did.
And the next time
you feel like showing off, don't.
- Breaking news.
- We're live from Washington,
where there's been an attack
in the Oval Office of the White House.
We have been informed that the president
and vice president were not harmed.
Sources say the attack involved
one or more mutants...
- I think it's time to leave, Professor.
- I think you're right.
- In my opinion, Magneto's behind this.
- I don't think so, Scott.
While Eric could organise
something like this from prison,
it would be irrational
and only hurt his goal of mutant prosperity.
- You mean superiority.
- You're right, if Eric had his way.
And, of course, the government
will reintroduce the Registration Act.
Or worse.
The president could declare a state of
emergency, place every mutant under arrest.
- Do you think the assassin worked alone?
- We'll only know that if we find him first.
I've been trying to track him using Cerebro,
but his movements are inexplicably erratic.
When I have exact coordinates, Storm, Jean,
I'll need you to take the jet and pick him up.
It was close, wasn't it?
Closer than anyone's admitted.
- What do you need, William?
- Your authorisation for a special operation.
No, thank you, Mr President.
I thought you were here
to talk about school reform.
Funny you should say that, Mr President.
- Senator.
- Mr President. Thank you for having me.
- Senator Kelly, Colonel William Stryker.
- How do you do?
His department has been dealing with the
mutant phenomenon since before my time.
You were a staunch supporter
of the Registration Act,
but it seems your ideas on
the mutant problem have changed.
For the best, I hope.
So what are you proposing, Mr Stryker?
May I, Mr President?
We've managed to gather evidence
of a mutant training facility
in the Salem region of upstate New York.
Where did you get this information?
Interrogation of one of the mutant terrorists
from the Liberty Island incident.
Eric Lehnsherr?
- You have access to him?
- Magneto, yes.
We developed the technology
that built his plastic prison.
- This facility is a school.
- Sure it is.
- What the hell is that?
- A jet.
- What kind of jet?
- We don't know.
But it comes up out of the basketball court.
If we'd been allowed to do our jobs
before this incident...
All right, listen.
William, you enter, you detain,
you question,
but the last thing we need to see is the body
of a mutant kid on the six o'clock news.
- Mr Stryker?
- Senator Kelly.
This is Yuriko, my personal assistant.
- Quite a handshake.
- What can I do for you?
Eric Lehnsherr's prison.
I'd like to arrange a visit.
It isn't a petting zoo, Senator.
In this conflict he is the enemy, you're just
a spectator, so why not sit this one out?
Conflict? Mr Stryker, do you really
want to turn this into some kind of war?
I was piloting black ops missions
in North Vietnam
while you were sucking
on your mama's tit at Woodstock.
Don't lecture me about war.
This already is a war.
- You're dead. You're so dead.
- You're dead.
I don't wanna hurt you.
I'm not afraid.
Logan.
You miss me, kid?
Not really.
- How are you doing?
- I'm OK. How are you?
- Who's this?
- This is Bobby. He's my...
I'm her boyfriend.
Call me Iceman.
Right.
Boyfriend? So how do you guys...?
We're still working on that.
Look who's come back. Just in time.
For what?
- We need a baby-sitter.
- Baby-sitter?
Nice to see you again, Logan.
Hi, Logan.
Hi, Jean.
I should go and get the jet ready.
Well, it was good to meet you.
- Come on, let's go.
- Bye, Logan. I'll see you later.
Storm and I are heading to Boston.
We won't be gone long.
The professor wants us to find
a mutant who attacked the president.
So it was a mutant.
You'll be here when we get back,
unless you plan on running off again.
I could probably think of
a few reasons to stick around.
Find what you were looking for, Logan?
More or less.
I'll see you boys later.
- Be safe, OK?
- You too. Bye.
See ya.
Aren't you gonna welcome me home?
Your bike needs gas.
Then fill her up.
Mr Laurio, how long can we keep this up?
- How long is your sentence?
- Forever.
Not necessarily forever, Mr Lehnsherr.
Just until I've got all that I need.
Mr Stryker, how kind of you to visit.
Have you come back to ensure
the taxpayers' dollars
are keeping me comfortable?
Done. You can go.
Now...
Mr Lehnsherr.
I'd like to have one final talk
about the house that Xavier built
and the machine called Cerebro.
My tolerance for your smoking
in the mansion notwithstanding,
smoke that in here
and you'll spend the rest of your days
under the belief you are a six-year-old girl.
- Can you do that?
- I'd have Jean braid your hair.
Welcome back.
- You want me to leave?
- No. Just don't move.
These lights represent
every living person on the planet.
The white lights are humans.
And these are the mutants.
Through Cerebro I'm connected to them,
and they to me.
You see, Logan?
We're not as alone as you think.
I found the base at Alkali Lake.
There was nothing there.
The broken line represents the path
of the mutant who attacked the president.
I've been finding it difficult
to get a lock on it.
Can't you just concentrate harder?
If I wanted to kill him, yes.
There.
Looks like he's finally stopped running.
I need you to read my mind again.
- The results will be the same as before.
- We had a deal.
The mind is not a box that can be simply
unlocked. It's a beehive with a million...
Spare me the lecture.
I've no doubt your amnesia,
your adamantium skeleton,
the claws are all connected, but...
Logan, sometimes the mind
needs to discover things for itself.
I promise you we'll talk again when I return.
If you would be kind enough
to watch over the children tonight.
Scott and I are going to visit an old friend.
I'm sending the coordinates
of where the mutant's settled.
As soon as you find him,
bring him back to the mansion.
- Let's hope he cooperates.
- Yes, for his sake. Good luck.
Stryker, William.
What are you doing in here?
Garbage.
These are the coordinates.
He's a teleporter. Must be why
the professor had trouble locating him.
We're not here to hurt you.
We just wanna talk.
- Are you bored yet?
- Oh, yeah.
Sure you don't wanna come down?
- You have him?
- He's not going anywhere.
Are you?
Please don't kill me.
I didn't mean to harm anyone.
Why would people
have gotten that impression?
- What's your name?
- Wagner. Kurt Wagner.
There was so much shooting, such fear.
And then there was only pain.
I could see it all happening,
but I couldn't stop myself.
It was like a bad dream.
Perhaps he is testing me.
And before you were in the White House,
what do you remember?
Nothing.
I was here.
- I'd rather get him back to the professor.
- The professor?
Did you do these yourself?
And what about this?
- I need you to read my mind again.
- The results will be the same as before.
- You'll be indestructible.
- No memory.
Sometimes the mind needs
to discover things for itself.
Wolverine.
No memory. You'll have no memory.
Can't sleep?
How can you tell?
Cos you're awake.
Right. How about you?
I don't sleep.
- Doesn't anybody sleep around here?
- Apparently not.
- Got any beer?
- This is a school.
- So that's a no?
- Yeah, that's a no.
Is there anything other than chocolate milk?
There's soda in that cupboard.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
I'll take him from here.
It's all right, Scott.
- Nice shades.
- Thanks.
Charles Xavier.
Have you come to rescue me?
Sorry, Eric, not today.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
The assassination attempt.
What do you know about it?
Nothing.
Only what I read in the papers.
You really shouldn't have to ask.
What's happened to you?
I've had frequent visits
from William Stryker.
You remember him, don't you?
His son, Jason, was once
a student of yours, wasn't he?
Yes. Years ago.
Unfortunately, I wasn't able to help him.
At least, not in the way his father wanted.
And now you think taking in Wolverine will
make up for your failure with Stryker's son?
- How long you been here?
- A couple of years.
And your parents just sent you off
to mutant school?
Actually, my parents think
this is a prep school.
I see. Well, I suppose lots of prep schools
have their own dorms, campuses...
Jets.
So you and Rogue.
It's not what you think.
I'd like it to be, but it's just...
It's just that it's not easy when you
wanna be closer to someone, but you can't.
I've seen how you look at Dr Grey.
Excuse me?
Nothin'.
You haven't told him of his past, have you?
I've put him on the path.
Logan's mind is still fragile.
Is it?
Or are you afraid of losing
one of your precious X-Men, old friend?
Eric, what have you done?
I'm sorry, Charles.
I couldn't help it.
What have you told Stryker?
Everything.
The war has begun.
Scott!
You should have killed me
when you had the chance.
But now and then
every mother needs to get away.
Without her, the babies are helpless...
Hi.
What is it?
You picked the wrong house.
You all right?
Stay here.
- This way.
- Let's go.
John! Where's Rogue?
- I don't know.
- I gotta find her.
- Open it.
- Here, take her.
Go on, get in. Let's go. Come on.
Take him. He's stunned.
- I can help you.
- Help them.
- Rogue!
- Bobby!
This way.
Come on. Everybody, follow me up here.
Move.
Come on.
Let's go.
Come on, this way.
This is it.
Logan.
- You wanna shoot me, shoot me.
- Don't shoot him.
Not yet.
Wolverine?
I must admit this is certainly
the last place I'd expect to find you.
How long has it been? 15 years?
You haven't changed one bit.
Me, on the other hand...
Nature.
Wait. We've gotta do something.
They'll kill him.
- He can handle himself. Let's go.
- Bobby.
Please.
I didn't realise Xavier was taking in animals,
even animals as unique as you.
Who are you?
Don't you remember?
No!
Logan, come on. Let's go.
- Go. I'll be fine.
- But we won't.
Go. Keep going.
- Right, get in.
- I'm driving.
Maybe next time.
This is Cyclops's car.
Oh, yeah?
What the hell was that back there?
Stryker.
His name is Stryker.
- Who is he?
- I can't remember.
Here.
This is yours.
- I hate uncomfortable silences.
- What are you doing?
I don't think that's his CD player.
- Sit back.
- Where are we going?
Storm and Jean are in Boston.
We'll head that way.
- My parents live in Boston.
- Good.
Sergeant?
Most of the mutants
escaped through a series of tunnels.
- We have some in custody.
- How many?
Six, sir.
Welcome, Professor.
Take what we need, gentlemen.
This protest underscores a growing concern
among most Americans.
Mutant registration...
Why stop there? It'd be easier
to round up mutants by the truckload.
- Or maybe you'd like an all-out war?
- Oh, please.
- Turn that shit off, Lou.
- A lot on your mind?
Mr Laurio?
I'm Grace.
You want another beer?
Of course you do.
- You're really aggressive.
- Yes, I am.
I've never hooked up with
a girl like you before.
I know.
- It's kind of dirty in here, don't you think?
- That's the idea.
Velcro?
Nice.
- Bottoms up.
- I certainly hope so.
Bottoms up.
- William...
- Please, Xavier, don't get up.
I call it the neural inhibitor.
It keeps you outta here.
- What have you done with Scott?
- Don't worry.
I'm just giving him a little re-education.
Of course, you know
all about that, don't you?
You wanted me to cure your son,
but mutation is not a disease.
You're lying.
You were more frightened of him
than I was.
Just one year after Jason returned
from your school, my wife...
You see, he resented us.
He blamed us for his condition,
so he would toy with our minds,
projecting visions and scenarios
into our brains.
My wife, in the end,
she took a power drill to her left temple
in an attempt to bore the images out.
My boy - the great illusionist.
For someone who hates mutants,
you certainly keep some strange company.
They serve their purpose,
as long as they can be controlled.
You arranged the attack on the president.
You didn't even have to read my mind.
I've been working with mutants
as long as you have, Xavier,
but the most frustrating thing I've learned is
nobody really knows how many even exist
or how to find them.
Except you.
Unfortunately, this little potion
won't work on you, will it?
You're much too powerful for that.
Instead, we'll go right to the source.
Allow me to introduce mutant 143.
The fluid secreted by his brain
acts as a mind-controlling agent.
But that's only where it begins.
Jason?
My God, William. This is your son.
- What have you done to him?
- No, Charles.
My son is dead.
Just like the rest of you.
Mom? Dad?
Ronny? Is anybody home?
I'll try and find you some clothes.
Don't burn anything.
I found some of my mom's old clothes.
I think they're from before I was born.
Groovy.
Hello?
Jean. Where are you?
These are my grandmother's.
Thanks.
You won't hurt me.
Wow.
I'm sorry.
It's OK.
Ronny, next time you...
Who the hell are you?
- Aren't you supposed to be at school?
- Bobby, who is this guy?
This is Professor Logan.
There's something I need to tell you.
You're clear.
Have a nice sleep, Lehnsherr?
- There's something different about you.
- Yeah. I was having a good day.
It's not that.
Sit down.
- Sit your ass down.
- What could it be?
What are you doin'?
There it is.
Too much iron in your blood.
Mr Laurie, never trust a beautiful woman,
especially one who's interested in you.
When did you first know you were a...
A mutant?
Would you cut that out?
You have to understand. We thought
Bobby was going to a school for the gifted.
- Bobby is gifted.
- We know. We just didn't realise...
We still love you, Bobby.
It's just this mutant problem is a little...
What mutant problem?
...complicated.
- What exactly are you a professor of?
- Art.
You should see what Bobby can do.
I can do a lot more than that.
This is all my fault.
Actually, it's males that carry the mutant
gene and pass it on, so it's his fault.
911. Please state your emergency.
I need the police. There are people
in our house. They won't let us leave.
It's believed a manhunt for several fugitives
from the facility is now under way.
Nobody's responding. I can't get a signal.
Why don't you take a break? I'll keep trying.
What are they?
They're angelic symbols passed on
to mankind by the archangel Gabriel.
They're beautiful.
How many do you have?
One for every sin.
So quite a few.
You and Miss Grey are schoolteachers?
Yes. At a school for people like us,
where we can be safe.
Safe from what?
Everyone else.
Outside of the circus
most people were afraid of me.
But I didn't hate them. I pitied them.
Do you know why?
Most people will never know anything
beyond what they see with their own eyes.
I gave up on pity a long time ago.
Someone so beautiful
should not be so angry.
Sometimes anger can help you survive.
So can faith.
- Storm, I found an active com device.
- Where?
Oh, God. It's for me.
Have you tried not being a mutant?
No one's left, Jean. Soldiers came.
What about the children?
I saw them escape.
Not sure about the rest.
We can't reach the professor
or Scott either.
- Where are you?
- Boston, with Bobby Drake's family.
- OK. We're on our way.
- And, Storm, make it fast.
- We have to go now.
- Why? Logan, what's wrong?
Drop the knives
and put your hands in the air.
What's going on here?
- Ronny.
- I said drop the knives.
- Open the door.
- Break it.
Turn around. Up against the wall.
- This is just a misunderstanding.
- Put the knives down.
I can't.
Look.
The rest of you, on the ground now.
Kid, I said on the ground.
We don't wanna hurt you, kid.
You know all those dangerous mutants
you hear about on the news?
I'm the worst one.
Get down.
- Who the hell is this?
- Kurt Wagner.
In the circus I was known as
"The Incredible Nightcrawler".
- Save it. Storm.
- We're outta here.
Jason, stop it.
It's all right. You can come out.
Have they gone?
- Where are all the other students?
- I don't know.
We'll have to find them, won't we?
We'll use Cerebro.
Come on.
How far are we?
We're actually coming up
on the mansion now.
I've got two signals approaching.
Coming in fast.
Unidentified aircraft,
you are ordered to descend to 20,000ft.
Return with our escort to Hanscom Air Force
Base. You have ten seconds to comply.
- Wow. Somebody's angry.
- I wonder why.
We are coming up alongside you
to escort you to Hanscom Air Force Base.
Lower your altitude now.
Repeat: lower your altitude to 20,000ft.
This is your last warning.
They're falling back.
They're marking us.
They're gonna fire. Hang on.
I gotta shake 'em.
- Please don't do that again.
- I agree.
Don't we have any weapons in this heap?
Warning.
Everybody OK back there?
My God. There's two of 'em.
There's one more.
Jean?
Oh, God.
- Rogue!
- No!
- Jean?
- It's not me.
When will these people learn how to fly?
Thank you.
- Can you hear what they're saying?
- I could take a closer look.
His name is Colonel William Stryker, and
he invaded your mansion for one purpose.
He wanted Cerebro.
Or enough of it to build one of his own.
That doesn't make sense. Stryker
would need the professor to operate it.
Which I think is the only reason
my old friend's still alive.
My God.
What are you all so afraid of?
While Cerebro is working, Charles's mind
is connected to every person on the planet.
If he were forced to concentrate
hard enough on a particular group -
mutants, for example -
he could kill us all.
Wait. How would Stryker even know
where to find Cerebro in the first place?
Because I told him.
I helped Charles build it, remember?
Mr Stryker has powerful methods
of persuasion,
even against a mutant as strong as Charles.
- So who is this Stryker anyway?
- He's a military scientist.
He spent his whole life
trying to solve the mutant problem.
If you want a more intimate perspective,
why don't you ask Wolverine?
You don't remember, do you?
William Stryker - the only other man I know
who can manipulate adamantium.
The metal on your bones -
it carries his signature.
- But the professor...
- He trusted you
to discover this on your own.
He gives you more credit than I do.
Why do you need us?
Mystique has discovered plans of a base
that Stryker's been operating
out of for decades.
We know it's where he's building
the second Cerebro,
but we don't know where the base is.
And I believe one of you might.
The professor already tried.
Once again, you think it's all about you.
Hello.
I didn't mean to snoop.
Just try and relax.
I'm sorry.
- Stryker's at Alkali Lake.
- That's where the professor sent me.
- There's nothing left.
- Nothing left on the surface.
The base is underground.
You OK?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
How we doin'?
Not good. It looks like four or five hours
before I can get it off the ground.
That's not what I meant.
- I'm just worried about Scott.
- I'm worried about you.
That was some display of power up there.
- Obviously it wasn't enough.
- Come on.
I love him.
Do you?
Girls flirt with the dangerous guy, Logan.
They don't take him home.
They marry the good guy.
I could be the good guy.
Logan, the good guy sticks around.
Please.
- Don't make me do this.
- Do what?
This.
Excuse me.
They say you can imitate anybody,
even their voice.
Even their voice.
Then why not stay in disguise all the time?
Look like everyone else?
Cos we shouldn't have to.
Look...
- No one's ever left a scar quite like you.
- What do you want, an apology?
You know what I want.
But what do you want?
What do you really want?
I want you to get out.
Jesus.
Why don't we get uniforms?
They're on order.
Should arrive in a few years.
We love what you've done with your hair.
Come on, let's go.
They say you're the bad guy.
Is that what they say?
It's a dorky-looking helmet.
What's it for?
This dorky-looking helmet is the only thing
that'll protect me from the real bad guys.
What's your name?
John.
What's your real name, John?
Pyro.
Quite a talent you have there, Pyro.
I can only manipulate the fire.
I can't create it.
You are a god among insects.
Never let anyone tell you different.
Sir, the machine has been completed
to all specifications.
Good.
If I may ask, sir,
why are we keeping the children here?
I'm a scientist, Sergeant Lyman.
When I build a machine,
I wanna make sure that it's working.
All right, this is a topographic map
of the dam. This is the spillway.
See these density changes in the terrain?
They're tire tracks.
That's the entrance.
And this shows the depth of the ice
covering the ground.
- This is recent water activity.
- If we go in, Stryker could flood the spillway.
Can you teleport inside?
I have to be able to see where I'm going,
otherwise I could wind up inside a wall.
I'll go.
I've a hunch he'll want me alive.
Whoever goes into the dam needs to be
able to operate the spillway mechanism.
What do you intend to do?
Scratch it with your claws?
- I'll take my chances.
- But I won't.
Sir, there's someone
coming down the spillway.
- I'm flooding it.
- Wait.
Stryker!
Look who's come home.
Move, and you're dead.
The one thing I know better than anyone
is my own work. Seal the room. Shoot it.
Seal the room. Step away.
We have a metamorph loose.
Could be anybody.
- Can you override the spillway mechanism?
- Only from that room.
- That's why the doors are so thick.
- Really?
Get some charges. Blow the doors open.
Take out these cameras.
I'm in.
- She's good.
- You have no idea.
Fire in the hole.
Move.
She's opened the spillway doors.
More mutants have entered.
- How many?
- We've lost coms - electrical interference.
Sergeant Lyman, gather your men
and meet me outside Cerebro.
You, carry on. When I come back
I want this door open all the way.
Welcome, Professor.
Don't leave me alone. Please?
You can come inside.
Found it?
A large portion of energy from the dam
has been diverted to this chamber.
- Cerebro.
- There it is.
Can you shut it down from here?
- Come. There's little time.
- Not without us.
My God. The children.
Kurt, will you come with me?
- Where are they?
- In a cell one level down.
We'll get the children
and meet you at Cerebro.
I'll try to find Scott and the professor.
- Will you be all right without us?
- I'll be fine.
Where's Logan?
He's gone.
You. Set up a perimeter.
Jason.
It's time.
Time to find our friends.
Is it time to find our friends?
All of them.
All of the mutants.
Everywhere.
- Everywhere.
- That's right.
- Every one of them?
- Yes.
Good.
It's time to bring it to an end.
Make me proud.
Just don't move.
Kill anyone who approaches.
Even if it's me.
Go! I'll take care of him.
This is one lovers' quarrel
we cannot get involved in, my dear.
Scott!
- Help us, anybody!
- Listen.
- Help!
- Get us out of here.
- Jubilee?
- Storm.
We're coming.
Scott, don't do this.
Jean, no, it's OK. It's me.
I'm so sorry.
- I thought I'd lost you.
- Oh, God.
I'm so sorry. I could see you,
but I couldn't stop myself. I tried.
- I love you so much.
- I love you.
- My leg.
- Easy.
Something's wrong.
My God.
Have you found the mutants yet?
Have you found all of them?
I'm trying. There are so many of them.
Then concentrate.
There's a tricky thing about adamantium.
If you ever manage
to process its raw, liquid form,
you gotta keep it that way.
Keep it hot.
Because once the metal cools,
it's indestructible.
But you already know that.
I used to think you were
one of a kind, Wolverine.
I was wrong.
Holy shit.
That's it.
- Where do you think you're going?
- I'm sick of this. I'm going in.
John, they told us to stay here.
You always do as you're told?
Find all the mutants.
All of them. Find them.
Everywhere. Each one. All of them.
Good. Kill them.
Concentrate. Concentrate harder.
Now find them all. Find all the mutants.
Concentrate harder. Each and every one.
Find all the mutants.
Kill them all. Find them all. Kill them.
Cerebro...
We're too late.
Eric, hurry.
That's strange.
How does it look from there, Charles?
Still fighting the good fight?
From here, it doesn't look like
they're playing by your rules.
Maybe it's time to play by theirs.
There's been a change of plan.
Goodbye, Charles.
There's been a change of plans.
Now find them. Focus. Find them all.
The humans. Find all of them.
Every one.
How does it feel, bub?
- Why did you come back?
- You cut me open. You took my life.
You make it sound as if
I stole something from you.
As I recall, it was you
who volunteered for the procedure.
Who am I?
You are just a failed experiment.
If you really knew about your past -
what kind of person you were,
the work we did together...
People don't change, Wolverine.
You were an animal then.
You're an animal now.
I just gave you claws.
What the hell is that?
- What is it?
- The dam's ruptured.
It's gonna flood water into the spillway.
It's trying to relieve the pressure.
It's too late. In a few minutes
we'll all be underwater.
Come with me,
and I'll tell you all you wanna know.
You can't help your friends.
They're as good as dead, Wolverine.
You're a survivor.
Always have been.
I thought I was just an animal with claws.
If we die, you die.
There are no answers that way, Wolverine.
Find all the humans. Each and every one.
Find them. Find all the humans. Kill them.
- What is this?
- Cerebro.
- Jean, are you OK?
- I'm fine.
What's happening?
Professor's still in there,
with another mutant.
He's trapped in some kind of illusion.
Oh, my God. Magneto's reversed Cerebro.
It's not targeting mutants any more.
- Who is it targeting?
- Everyone else.
Impossible.
- Stand back.
- No. His mind is connected to Cerebro.
Opening it could kill him
and everyone his mind is linked to.
Wait. Kurt, I need you to take me inside.
Who is this guy? Who are you?
My name is Kurt Wagner,
but in the circus...
He's a teleporter.
I told you. If I can't see where I'm going...
I have faith in you.
Don't believe anything you see in there.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on Earth...
as it is in heaven.
Hello.
What are you looking for?
Professor, can you hear me?
You've got to stop Cerebro now.
Who are you talking to?
Don't move.
But she's just a little girl.
No, she's not.
I've got my eyes on you.
Mr Stryker.
Funny we keep running into each other.
Mark my words, it'll never happen again.
Kurt, it's about to get very cold in here.
I'm not going anywhere.
What are you doing?
Find all the humans.
Kill them. Every single one of them.
Focus. Find all the humans.
Stop it!
Jason.
He's gonna be so angry at me.
Logan, where are you?
We have to go through the spillway.
You don't wanna go that way. Trust me.
There's another way out of here.
The helicopter was right here.
I will take him.
It's OK, Rogue. You can let go, honey.
- Go. I'll be fine.
- You sure?
Who has the answers, Wolverine?
Those people?
That creature in your arms?
I'll take my chances with him.
One day someone will finish
what I've started, Wolverine.
One day!
We've got to get to Washington.
I fear this has gone beyond Alkali Lake.
I got him.
You OK?
I am now.
- What's wrong?
- Thrusters off line.
- So fix it.
- Has anyone seen John?
Pyro? Where the hell is he?
He's with Magneto.
Come on.
Oh, no. We've lost the power.
There's power in the fuel cells...
- Storm, we need some external power.
- Jean?
Where's Jean?
She's outside.
We're not leaving. Lower the ramp.
Storm, lower it.
I can't.
She's controlling the jet.
- You, get her, now.
- She's not letting me.
Dammit.
I know what I'm doing.
- This is...
- ...the only way.
Jean...
Listen to me.
Don't do this.
Goodbye.
She's gone.
Don't say that. We gotta go back.
- She's gone.
- No!
She's gone.
"The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want."
"He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures."
"Yea, though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of the death,
"I will fear no evil,
"for thou art with me."
"Today I can shed light
on recent occurrences
"from the attack that ended in this office..."
Morning. "...to the phenomenon
that swept the Earth,
"nearly annihilating our way of life."
Do we like this word "annihilating"?
Good morning.
- Good morning, Mr President.
- Thank you.
Mr President, we're live in five,
four, three, two...
My fellow Americans, in this time of
adversity we are being offered a moment.
A moment to recognise
a growing threat in our own population
and take a unique role
in the shape of human events.
Did we just lose the feed? Are we still live?
Good morning, Mr President.
Please, don't be alarmed.
We're not going to harm anyone.
Who are you people?
We're mutants.
My name is Charles Xavier.
- Please, sit down.
- I'd rather stand.
Rogue.
These files were taken from
the private offices of William Stryker.
How did you get this?
Let's just say I know a little girl
who can walk through walls.
- I've never seen this.
- I know.
So you also know
I don't respond to threats.
This is not a threat. This is an opportunity.
There are forces in this world, mutant and
human alike, who believe a war is coming.
You will see from those files
that some have already tried to start one.
And there have been casualties,
losses on both sides.
Mr President.
What you are about to tell the world is true.
This is a moment.
A moment to repeat the mistakes of the
past, or to work together for a better future.
We're here to stay, Mr President.
The next move is yours.
We'll be watching.
Mr President?
You know, even when Jean was a student,
she was always hesitant about her powers.
Always looking to others.
Feeling that in some way
she was left behind.
Could we have done more to save her?
In the past, she may have let us.
There had to be another way.
Why did she leave the plane?
Because she made a choice.
Yes, come on in.
Listen.
She did make a choice.
It was you.
Professor?
Is everything all right?
Yes, I think it will be.
Tell me, have any of you read a book
by an English novelist named TH White
called The Once and Future King?
Mutation: it is the key to our evolution.
It is how we have evolved
from a single-celled organism
into the dominant species on the planet.
This process is slow, normally taking
thousands and thousands of years.
But every few hundred millennia
evolution leaps forward.