Mama!
Mother. What are you...
I thought you were a burglar.
I didn't mean to scare you, darling.
I was just getting a snack.
Go back to bed.
What's the matter?
Go on, back to bed.
I'll make you a hot chocolate.
Who are you?
And what have you done with my mother?
My mother has never set foot
in this kitchen in her life.
And she certainly never
made me a hot chocolate.
Unless you count ordering
the maid to do it.
You're not scared of me?
I always believed I couldn't be
the only one in the world.
The only person who was
different.
And here you are.
Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You're hungry and alone.
Take whatever you want.
We've got lots of food.
You don't have to steal.
In fact,
you never have to steal again.
Understand this, Erik...
These Nazis, I'm not like them.
Genes are the key, yes?
But their goals?
Blue eyes? Blond Hair? Pathetic.
Eat the chocolate.
It's good.
Want some?
I want to see my mama.
Genes are the key that unlocks
the door to a new age, Erik.
A new future for mankind.
Evolution.
You know what I'm talking about?
It's a simple thing I ask of you.
A little coin is nothing
compared to a big gate.
Is it?
Ja.
I tried, Herr Doctor.
I can't... I don't...
It's impossible.
The one thing I can say for the Nazis
is their methods seem to produce results.
I'm sorry, Erik.
Mama!
My darling.
How are you?
Here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to count to three...
...and you're going to move the coin.
You don't move the coin,
I pull the trigger.
Understand?
One
Mama.
You can do it.
Two
Everything is all right.
Three.
Yes. Wonderful.
Excellent.
Nein!
Outstanding, Erik.
So we unlock your gift with anger.
Anger and pain.
You and me...
...we're going to have a lot of fun together.
Heterochromia.
A gentleman would at least
offer to buy me a drink first.
Norman, a pint of bitter for me
and a brandy for the lady, please.
- How did you know that?
- Lucky guess.
My name is Xavier. Charles Xavier.
- How do you do?
- Amy.
Heterochromia was
in reference to your eyes,
which I have to say are stunning.
One green, one blue.
It's a mutation.
It's a very groovy mutation.
I've got news for you, Amy.
You are a mutant.
First you proposition a girl,
and then you call her deformed.
How is that seduction
technique working for you?
I'll tell you in the morning.
No, seriously, though,
you mustn't knock it.
Mutation took us from
single-celled organisms
to being the dominant form
of reproductive life on this planet.
Infinite forms of variation
with each generation,
all through mutation.
Then let's reclaim that word.
- Mutant and proud.
- Chin-chin. Hey.
- I guess I have to buy my own drink.
- I'm sorry. One cola.
Charles here was just telling me
that I'm like one of the first
sea creatures that grew legs.
A tiny bit sexier.
I'm sorry. This is my sister, Raven.
- Hi.
- Amy.
- And what do you study?
- Waitressing.
Oh, look, you have heterochromia, too.
- Sorry, what?
- Look at her eye.
Right. Raven, get your coat, please.
Don't talk to me. You did that on purpose.
- I did not! Why would I do it on purpose?
- Yes, you did!
You know I can't control it
sometimes if I'm stressed or tired.
You seem to be doing a perfectly
good job right now.
- "Mutant and proud."
- What?
Or is it only with pretty mutations,
or invisible ones like yours?
But if you're a freak, you better hide.
You're being ridiculous.
I don't mean to sound like an old fart.
- Which you are.
- Sometimes.
But we've talked about this, Raven.
A small slip-up is one thing.
A big one does not bear thinking about.
"Mutant and proud."
"Mutant and proud"?
If only.
- Would you date me?
- Of course I would.
Any young man would be lucky
to have you. You are stunning.
Looking like this?
Like... What?
Blue?
- You're my oldest friend.
- I'm your only friend.
- Thank you for that.
- Well?
I'm incapable of thinking of you that way.
I feel responsible for you.
Anything else would just feel wrong.
- But what if you didn't know me?
- Unfortunately, I do know you.
I don't know what's gotten into you lately.
You're awfully concerned with your looks.
I'm sleepy. Will you read to me?
I can't. I have my thesis coming up.
I have to study.
Fine, read that.
Your thesis always sends me right off.
"To Homo neanderthalensis,
his mutant cousin, Homo sapiens,
"was an aberration.
"Peaceful cohabitation,
if ever it existed, was short-lived.
"Records show, without exception,
"that the arrival of the mutated
human species in any region
"was followed by the immediate extinction
"of their less-evolved kin."
Possession of that gold is illegal.
I should inform the police.
Let's not play this game.
Where did you get it?
A friend.
He recommended your bank most highly.
I see.
Do you know our terms, sir?
Yes.
And you should know mine.
This gold is what remains of my people.
Melted from their possessions.
Torn from their teeth.
This is blood money.
And you're going to help me find
the bastards responsible for it.
Don't touch that alarm.
I want Schmidt. Klaus Schmidt.
Where is he?
Our clients don't provide addresses.
We're not...
Not that sort of bank?
Metal fillings, eh?
Not gold.
Worried someone might steal them?
Argentina! Schmidt is in Argentina!
Villa Gesell! Please!
Thank you.
I would love to kill you.
So mark my words.
If you warn anyone I'm coming...
I will find you.
Another day at the office.
Is that Colonel Hendry?
The NATO guy?
Yeah.
Yes, it is.
Because that's three mob bosses,
the Italian ambassador
and the CEO of Lockheed.
They can't all be Communists.
This Hellfire Club,
it's got to be something else.
Do you see that?
Hello, girls.
Wow! Very nice.
What are you doing?
Using some equipment the CIA
didn't give me. Stay put.
- Colonel Hendry?
- Yes, ma'am.
Emma Frost. Sebastian Shaw's associate.
And where is Mr. Shaw?
We're having a party,
and here's the entertainment.
Come with me.
Hello, beautiful. How are you?
Hey, baby. You want to find a quiet place?
I am so sorry.
I've been booked by Colonel Hendry.
Excuse me.
You sure we can't get you a refill, Bob?
No.
So, I hear you blocked the proposal
to position Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
I expect you'll reconsider.
We've had this conversation.
You put our nukes in Turkey
or anywhere that close to Russia,
and you're looking at war.
Nuclear war.
I don't ask for favors, Colonel.
I express my expectations.
So, let me say it again.
I expect you'll reconsider.
The only thing I will reconsider
is having another glass
of that delicious champagne.
What the hell did you put in my drink?
You're thinking of running. Hiding.
We'd find you, Hendry.
There's not a fortress in the world
that could keep us out.
Magnificent. Isn't she, Bob?
Genetic mutation.
The evolution of the human genome.
Where's Azazel?
We don't want the Colonel to be late.
Comrade.
Missiles in Turkey send
a very clear message.
If we ever decide to fire them,
the Russian early-warning system
won't even have time to kick in.
This better be important, MacTaggert.
Whoa, slow down.
Are you smoking them funny cigarettes?
People don't disappear.
Colonel Hendry was there.
He was there, McCone, in the Hellfire Club.
Colonel Hendry?
I agree with you, General.
I've reconsidered my position
and I now believe we should put
Jupiter missiles in Turkey.
Colonel Hendry is here.
So unless he magically traveled
3,000 miles in the last 10 minutes,
listen to me, I suggest
that you stop wasting my time.
Looks like Hendry wants
to start World War III.
I got bigger things to deal with
right now, MacTaggert.
Sir, I...
- God!
- Have you lost your mind?
So, now what?
We find an expert on genetic mutation.
Professor of Genetics,
Charles Francis Xavier.
So, how does it feel to be a professor?
Don't call me that.
You don't get to be called a professor
until you actually have a teaching position.
I know, but it suits you.
Don't say that. Do say,
"Let's go have a drink."
- Let's go have a drink.
- Wonderful.
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Hot out there.
Beer, please.
- German beer.
- Of course.
Yes, it's Bitburger. You like it?
The best.
What brings you to Argentina?
The climate. I'm a pig farmer.
Tailor. Since I was a boy.
My father made the finest
suits in Dusseldorf.
My parents were from Dusseldorf.
What was their name?
They didn't have a name.
It was taken away from them...
by pig farmers...
...and tailors.
Blood and Honor.
Which would you care to shed first?
We were under orders...
Blood then.
Freeze, asshole.
Come on, shoot.
Who... what are you?
Let's just say I'm Frankenstein's monster.
And I'm looking for my creator.
Drink! Drink! Drink!
Yeah!
- I'm so proud of you.
- Thank you.
I need another drink.
And you need another cola.
- Congratulations, Professor.
- Thank you very much.
It's much harder than it looks, actually.
No, on your presentation.
You were at my presentation?
How nice of you. Thank you very much.
Moira MacTaggert.
- Charles Xavier.
- Do you have a minute?
For a pretty little bean
with a mutated MCR1 gene?
I have five.
I say "MCR1," you would say "Auburn hair."
It's a mutation.
It's a very groovy mutation.
Mutation, right,
took us from single-celled
organisms to the dominant form...
You know what? This routine may
go over great with the co-eds,
- but I'm here on business.
- What?
- I really need your help.
- All right.
The kind of mutations that you
were talking about in your thesis.
I need to know if they may
have already happened.
In people alive today.
Professor?
I think we should just
talk when you're sober.
Do you have any time tomorrow?
Something tells me you already
know the answer to your question.
This is very important to me, and if
I can help you, I will do my utmost.
Thank you.
Still drinking champagne, Bob?
I will pass.
Okay, well, so much for the pleasantries.
I was wondering who you told
about our little arrangement.
No one.
- He's telling the truth.
- Good.
Well, I guess we're done here.
Let's wrap things up, shall we?
I knew better than to trust you.
Now, you let me walk out
of here with my money,
or I will pull this pin, and we all die.
Go ahead. Pull it.
I'll do it, I swear to God.
No, you won't.
But I will.
You're one of them?
Very astute of you, Colonel Hendry.
You want to guess what I can do?
I've got the power to absorb energy.
It keeps me young.
But that's the boring part.
The fun stuff is what I can do
with it once I've got it.
The advent of the nuclear age may have
accelerated the mutation process.
Individuals with extraordinary
abilities may already be among us.
Thank you very much.
MacTaggert, you really think
that some crackpot scientist
is going to make me believe
in sparkly dames and vanishing men?
You just bought yourself a one-way
ticket back to the typing pool.
This meeting is over.
Please sit down, Agent MacTaggert.
I didn't really expect you to believe me,
given that all you could think about
during my presentation was
what sort of pie they were
serving in the commissary.
It's apple pecan.
I haven't been entirely honest
with you, love. I'm sorry.
You see, one of the many spectacular things
my mutation allows me to do
is that I can read your mind.
I've seen this before in a magic show.
Are you going to ask us to think
of a number between one and 10 now?
No, Agent Stryker. Although,
I could ask you about your son, William,
who you were thinking about,
which is very nice.
But I think I'd rather ask you
about the Jupiter missiles
America are currently placing in Turkey.
He's a goddamn spy.
You brought a goddamned
spy into this facility!
How's that for a magic trick?
Best I've ever seen.
I want them out of here.
And locked down until I can
figure out what to do.
My facility is off-site.
I'll take them.
I can't believe this.
You'd think the director of the CIA
would have a little more composure.
We should be going after Shaw right now.
But instead, he's out there worrying
about the wrong mutants.
What are we going to do, Levene?
Levene? Levene, what's wrong with you?
Absolutely nothing.
I've just frozen him for a moment
because I'd like to talk to you.
It's good, isn't it?
I'm as interested in this
Sebastian Shaw as you are.
If you still want my help, meet me
on the third floor of the parking garage.
I've always known that there
were people like you out there.
I've been the laughing stock of this
agency for years, but I knew it!
You are going to love my facility.
- That's going to have to wait.
- Why?
Agent MacTaggert has
a lead on Sebastian Shaw,
and if we don't move now,
apparently, we're going to lose him.
- What?
- Not only can he read minds,
he can communicate with them as well.
Moira and I have just had
a lovely conversation.
Yes, we did.
That is incredible!
But I cannot take you anywhere else
without permission from upstairs.
- Like to see one more magic trick?
- Okay.
- Get in the car.
- Good idea.
Herr Doktor.
Little Erik Lensherr.
He's here to kill you.
What kind of a greeting is that...
...after all these years?
Emma.
We don't harm our own kind.
Now it's a party.
This is the US Coast Guard.
Do not attempt to move your vessel.
Stay where you are.
They have a telepath.
I've lost Shaw. I've lost Shaw.
There's something blocking me.
This has never happened to me before.
I think there's someone like me
on that ship.
- Like you?
- I'm sorry, a telepath.
This is incredible. I could actually feel
her inside my mind. I'm very sorry,
but I don't think I'm gonna be much
help tonight. You're on your own.
- Oh, my God!
- Jesus!
Get inside.
Stop, stop, stop.
Charles! Are you okay?
There's someone else out there.
There.
Time to go.
Let go!
You have to let it go!
You've got to put someone
in the water to help him.
Let it go! You have to let it go!
You can't. You'll drown.
You have to let go.
I know what this means to you,
but you're going to die.
Please, Erik, calm your mind.
Get off me! Get off!
Calm down! Just breathe. We're here!
- Who are you?
- My name is Charles Xavier.
You were in my head.
How did you do that?
You have your tricks, I have mine.
I'm like you. Just calm your mind.
I thought I was alone.
You're not alone.
Erik, you're not alone.
Welcome to my facility.
My mission has been to investigate
the application of paranormal
powers in military defense.
Or offense.
This guy Shaw, Schmidt,
whatever you want to call him,
he's working with the Russians.
- We might need your help to stop him.
- Marvelous.
So we're to be the CIA's
new mutant division, yes?
Something like that.
It's a supersonic.
The most advanced plane ever built.
You should see it in real life. It's incredible.
Hank, these are the special new
recruits I was telling you about.
This is Hank McCoy, one of our
most talented young researchers.
How wonderful.
Another mutant, already here.
Why didn't you say?
Say what?
Because you don't know.
I am so, so terribly sorry.
- Hank?
- You didn't ask, so I didn't tell.
So, your mutation is what?
- You're super-smart?
- I'll say.
Hank here graduated
Harvard at the age of 15.
I wish that's all it was.
You're among friends now, Hank.
You can show off.
Splendid.
I'm sorry.
Ta-da!
You're amazing.
Really?
"The presence of US missiles in Turkey
"represents an unprecedented threat
to the people of the Soviet Union,"
warned Russian Foreign Minister
Gromyko earlier today.
But he was quick to insist
the Russians would not be the first
to initiate any military action.
Yeah, we'll fix that as soon
as we get to Russia.
Unless the CIA find us first.
I'll take care of them, too.
If that telepath gets inside your head,
he won't be as much fun as I am.
Already in hand, my love.
The Russians
made me this.
So, what am I thinking?
I don't know.
I was thinking that you are
the most exquisite thing
I have ever seen in my life.
And that this needs ice.
Fetch me some.
There's a good girl.
I promised myself I'd find a cure
ever since I was a little boy.
You have no idea what I'd give to feel
- normal.
- Normal.
Charles has never understood.
He's different, but he's never had to hide.
Hank, this serum that you're making,
it doesn't affect abilities, right?
Just appearance. It normalizes it.
Yeah.
Do you think it would work on me?
I can look into it, if you'd like.
It's the least I can do
after asking you to come down here
with such a weird request.
I have to admit, usually when guys
ask me out, they're not after my blood.
Sorry. I didn't intend to be forward.
I was just...
I was excited.
You know, the nature of your mutation.
If any genes hold the key
to changing appearance, it's yours.
Hank, you weren't being forward.
That's kind of what I meant.
No.
But I'm just sorry if you thought I was.
And I'm sorry that you weren't.
Go ahead. Take the blood.
Sorry. Did I hurt you?
Kinky.
By the way, if I looked like you,
I wouldn't change a thing.
From what I know about you,
I'm surprised you've managed
to stay this long.
What do you know about me?
Everything.
Then you know to stay out of my head.
I'm sorry, Erik, but I've seen
what Shaw did to you.
I've felt your agony.
I can help you.
I don't need your help.
Don't kid yourself.
You needed my help last night.
It's not just me you're walking away from.
Here you have the chance to be part
of something much bigger than yourself.
I won't stop you leaving. I could.
But I won't.
Shaw has got friends.
You could do with some.
Hank turned that radar
installation into a transmitter.
It's designed to amplify brainwaves
so it could enhance your telepathic powers,
help us find other mutants for our division.
What if they don't want to be found by you?
Erik.
You decided to stay.
If a new species is being discovered,
it should be by its own kind.
Charles and I find the mutants. No suits.
First of all, that's my machine out there.
Second of all, and much more
importantly, this is Charles' decision.
Charles is fine with the CIA being involved.
Isn't that right?
No. I'm sorry, but I'm with Erik.
We'll find them alone.
What if I say no?
Then good luck using your installation
without me.
I call it Cerebro.
- As in the Spanish for "brain."
- Yes.
Okay, so, the electrodes connect Charles
to the transmitter on the roof.
When he picks up a mutant,
his brain sends a signal through a relay
and then the co-ordinates
of their location are printed out here.
- You designed this?
- Yeah.
What an adorable lab rat you make, Charles.
Don't spoil this for me, Erik.
I've been a lab rat.
I know one when I see one.
Okay, great.
Are you sure we can't shave your head?
- Don't touch my hair.
- Okay.
It's working!
For that, daddy-o, you get a private dance.
You cats know it's double for both, right?
No, that won't be necessary.
Although, I'm sure it'd be magical.
We were thinking more, we'll show you ours
if you show us yours.
Baby, that is not the way
it works around here.
More tea, vicar?
Don't mind if I do.
My turn.
How would you like a job where
you get to keep your clothes on?
- Where to, fellas?
- Richmond, Virginia, please.
Right, so, you want the airport?
The station? What?
No, we were rather hoping you
would take us all the way.
That's a six-hour drive.
That will give us plenty of time to talk.
What does the government want
with a guy like Alex Summers?
I hope you're not planning
on putting him with others.
First guy I've ever met who actually
prefers solitary confinement.
Crazy, huh?
What?
You like fish. I like fish, too.
Maybe we should get a bite
sometime, talk about it?
I'd rather go out with the fish.
These fish?
- Excuse me, I'm Erik Lensherr.
- Charles Xavier.
Go fuck yourself.
- There's nothing on radar?
- Nothing.
- Sonar?
- Nyet.
Then we have a problem.
Beautiful, isn't it?
The reason we exist.
We are the children of the atom, my love.
We have a situation.
The telepath.
I shouldn't be able to feel
him at this distance.
It's like his reach is
amplified.
They're recruiting.
You go on to Russia. I'll handle them.
I can't stop thinking about
the others out there.
All those minds that I touched.
I could feel them.
Their isolation, their hopes,
their ambitions.
I tell you, we are at the start
of something incredible, Erik.
We can help them.
Can we?
Identification, that's how it starts.
And ends with being rounded up,
experimented on, eliminated.
Not this time.
We have common enemies.
Shaw, the Russians.
They need us.
For now.
We should think of code names.
We're government agents now,
we should have secret code names.
I want to be called Mystique.
Damn! I wanted to be called Mystique.
Well, tough. I called it.
And I'm way more mysterious than you.
Darwin, what about you?
Well, "Darwin" is already a nickname,
and, you know, it sort of fits.
Adapt to survive and all.
Check this out.
- That was incredible.
- Thank you.
- What about you?
- I'm going to be
Banshee.
Why do you want to be named
after a wailing spirit?
You might want to cover your ears.
- Your turn.
- My stage name is Angel.
- It kind of fits.
- You can fly?
And...
What's your name?
How about Big Foot?
You know what they say
about guys with big feet.
And yours are kind of small.
Okay, now.
Alex, what is your gift?
What can you do?
It's not...
I just can't do it.
I can't do it in here.
- Can you do it out there?
- Why don't you just do it out there?
- Come on!
- Alex! Alex! Alex!
That's the spirit!
Get down when I tell you.
"Get down when I tell you."
Get back.
Get back!
Whatever.
We have intel that Shaw is meeting
with the Russian Defense Chief in Moscow.
So go ahead. Say it.
I'm not here to say "I told you so."
You know why I'm here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Clearance to bring along your mutants.
Fight fire with fire. It makes sense.
Wait! You're okay with this?
Sending in a bunch of untrained,
unauthorized freaks?
These freaks are dedicated,
hardworking people.
Plane leaves for Russia in an hour.
I'm telling you, these kids
are not ready for Shaw.
I think they're gonna surprise you.
They're an exceptional
bunch of young people.
What the hell?
Come on! You can go harder than that.
Harder!
What are you doing?
Who destroyed the statue?
It was Alex.
No, Havok.
We have to call him Havok.
That's his name now.
And we were thinking,
you should be Professor X
and you should be Magneto.
Exceptional.
I expect more from you.
- We got a problem.
- What?
I'm so sorry. This wasn't on the map.
No matter what happens, act normally.
I'll take care of this, all right?
Now, listen to me...
- Where are you going?
- To our farm.
Open the back.
As you wish.
Easy, easy. Take it easy, chaps.
- Anything back there?
- Nothing. It's empty.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
- Where is Shaw?
- I don't know.
But if she's a telepath and I read her,
she'll know we're here.
Let me try something else.
Shaw sends his apologies
but he's indisposed.
He asked me to come in his place.
And between you and I, honey,
I'm a lot better company.
Please, come in.
He's not coming.
So, what now, boss?
Now, nothing. We're here for Shaw.
Mission aborted.
- The hell it is.
- Erik.
She's his right-hand woman.
That's good enough for me.
The CIA invading the home of a senior
Soviet official. Are you crazy?
I'm not CIA.
Erik!
Your health.
So, you must be busy
planning your next move.
What with the Americans refusing
to remove their missiles from Turkey.
You know I can't talk about
those things, Miss Frost.
Emma.
And don't worry.
You don't have to say a word.
He's gonna start
World War III single-handed.
- We have to do something.
- Like what?
- We're moving out.
- You can't!
I'm sorry. I can't leave him.
For God's sake, Erik! Be calm.
Be calm.
Forget my face.
You are beautiful, so beautiful! Yes!
Pathetic.
Yes!
Nice trick.
Who are you?
Go to sleep.
You can stop trying to read my mind, sugar.
You're never going to get anything
from me while I'm like this.
So, then, you can just tell us.
Where is Shaw?
Erik.
Erik, that's enough.
Erik, that's enough!
All yours.
She won't be shifting
into diamond form again.
And if she does, just give her a gentle tap.
We are the children of the atom.
What will kill the humans
will only make us stronger.
Beautiful, isn't it?
This is worse than we previously imagined.
We're taking you with us.
CIA will want to question you themselves.
Oh, I doubt it.
They have bigger things
to worry about right now.
- Whoa!
- All right, all right.
Jesus, man, you are killing me.
Don't beat yourself up.
I've had a lot of spare time.
I didn't know the circus was in town.
Hey, come on, honey. Give us a little...
No? Come on, let's see the foot.
There it is. Come on, Big Foot, let's go.
Hey. Hey, come on. Hey.
They're just guys being stupid.
Guys being stupid, I can handle. Okay?
I've handled that my whole life.
But I'd rather a bunch of guys
stare at me with my clothes off
than the way these ones stare at me.
At us.
What was that?
I don't know. Something doesn't feel right.
No news of Shaw?
- Not a peep.
- Not even through that back channel?
What is that?
- We have an intruder in the main atrium.
- Where are the mutants?
If you take another step,
I'm gonna put you down.
Of course you will. But where do
I find the more evolved people?
Send back-up now!
Get back! Do not leave that room.
We're under attack!
Shoot! Shoot!
Where are the mutants?
Put that man down or we will open fire!
Stay here, my ass! Let's go!
- Get back!
- We can help! We can help!
Wait!
You want the mutants?
They're right through that door.
Just let us normal people go.
We're no threat...
- Where is the telepath?
- Not here.
Too bad.
Well, at least I can take
this silly thing off.
Good evening.
My name is Sebastian Shaw.
And I am not here to hurt you.
Freeze!
Azazel.
My friends, there is a revolution coming.
When mankind discovers
who we are, what we can do,
each of us will face a choice.
Be enslaved
or rise up to rule.
Choose freely, but know
that if you are not with us,
then, by definition, you are
against us.
So, you can stay
and fight for the people
who hate and fear you,
or you can join me and live like kings.
And queens.
- Angel.
- Are you kidding me?
Come on.
We don't belong here.
And that's nothing to be ashamed of.
We have to do something.
Stop. I'm coming with you.
Good choice.
So, tell me about your mutation.
Well, I adapt to survive.
So, I guess I'm coming with you.
I like that.
- Alex!
- Get out!
Do it!
Protecting your fellow mutants?
That's a noble gesture.
Feels good.
Adapt to this.
Hello.
Once again, my sympathies for your
treatment at the hands of the CIA.
These Americans are ruthless.
Now they have their missiles
placed in Turkey...
...I expect you'll be planning
new missile sites of your own.
Somewhere you know the American
early-warning system won't help.
I hear Cuba is lovely this time of year.
And so close to Florida.
Missiles in Cuba?
You're serious?
We may as well declare war.
Maybe I wasn't clear enough.
You will make this happen.
Okay.
Let's see what KGB think about this.
Hello? General Armivolkoff.
It's nothing.
Raven?
We've made arrangements for you
to be taken home immediately.
- We're not going home.
- What?
He's not going back to prison.
He killed Darwin.
All the more reason for you to leave.
This is over.
Darwin's dead, Charles.
And we can't even bury him.
We can avenge him.
Erik, a word, please.
- They're just kids.
- No. They were kids.
Shaw has his army, we need ours.
We'll have to train.
All of us.
- Yes?
- Yeah.
Well, we can't stay here.
Even if they reopen
the department, it's not safe.
We've got nowhere to go.
Yes, we do.
The law says we've got to turn her over.
The law applies to human beings.
The same laws don't apply to mutants.
They're too dangerous.
In times like this, security is
more important than liberty.
- There is a war coming, John.
- Yes,
but a war with who?
Excellent question.
Though I wouldn't call it a war, exactly.
That suggests both sides stand
an equal chance of winning.
Captain, no sign of any American ships.
Maintain course, full ahead.
The Russians have sent
their warheads to Cuba.
We have a week before
the ship hits the coast.
Our fleet can be on this line when
the Russian missile ship arrives.
If that ship crosses the line,
they will have declared war
against the United States.
And we will have no choice but to retaliate
with a full nuclear response.
Do we agree?
Dispatch the 7th fleet.
This is yours?
No, it's ours.
Honestly, Charles. I don't know how
you survived, living in such hardship.
Well, it was a hardship softened by me.
Come on. Time for the tour.
Dear comrades...
The United States have
dispatched warships for Cuba.
This leaves us with no choice.
Comrade First Secretary...
We must send in our fleet.
Dispatch the fleet!
President Kennedy has signed
a formal proclamation
setting up a blockade
of all missiles bound for Cuba.
The Soviet Union reacted by terming it
"A step along the road to unleashing
a thermo-nuclear war."
You're sure?
I'm sure.
All right.
No. No, I can't. I'm sorry.
I can't shoot anybody point blank,
let alone my friend.
Oh, come on. You know I can deflect it.
You're always telling me
I should push myself.
If you know you can deflect it,
then you're not challenging yourself.
Whatever happened to the man
who was trying to raise a submarine?
I can't. Something that big?
I need the situation, the anger...
No, the anger is not enough.
It's gotten the job done all this time.
It's nearly gotten you killed all this time.
Come here.
Let's try something
a little more challenging.
My stepfather took the possibility
of nuclear war quite seriously. This way.
That is why he had this
bunker built down here.
I thought we could use it
as a practice range of sorts.
You don't think I'm going
to blow through the walls?
He had this place built
to withstand a nuclear bomb.
I think it can handle you, Alex.
You know, when I do this,
bad things tend to happen.
That's because you can't control it.
It controls you.
That's why we're here, Alex.
It's why we're training.
What you're doing is incredible.
You're hitting a pitch with sound waves
that have the same resonant frequency
as the glass. That's why it shatters.
But this, it's like any other
muscle in the body.
You can control it.
"In each of us, two natures are at war."
Robert Louis Stevenson, Jekyll and Hyde.
Top marks.
The story wasn't really about
good and evil though, was it?
It was about man's animal nature and
his struggle to control it, to conform.
And it's that struggle
which is holding you back.
No, Jekyll was afraid of what
he could be capable of.
And you are, too.
If you're serious about me doing this,
you might want to get back.
All right.
- Shall I shut the door?
- Yeah.
Whenever you're ready.
Oh, my God!
I will teach you to control this, Alex.
And you're sure that this will work?
Anything is possible. I based the design...
Hank, stop talking. Come on.
Now, remember.
Scream as hard as you can.
You need the sound waves
to be supersonic.
Catch them at the right angle
and they should carry you.
They should carry me.
- That's reassuring.
- Good luck.
And don't forget to scream.
Now, if you want to beat me this time,
you have to set the beast free.
On your marks,
get set,
go!
Congratulations, my friend.
Robert Louis Stevenson
would have been proud.
Impressive, Hank.
With feet like those,
all you need is a red nose.
Right, Bozo?
- I'm done here.
- Thank you, Alex.
Come on, Hank.
If you're using half your
concentration to look normal,
then you're only half paying attention
to whatever else you're doing.
Just pointing out something
that could save your life.
You want society to accept you,
but you can't even accept yourself.
Sexy!
Well, this is just the prototype.
The real one will look considerably better.
It will be a whole suit. See, these
sensors measure your energy output.
This panel focuses it and
the excess is absorbed.
Try hitting the one in the middle.
Just the one in the middle, mind.
Good luck.
You got to see this. Your genes
are extraordinary, you know that?
Your cells age at half the rate
of a normal human.
When you're 40, you'll still have
the leukocytes of a teenager.
You have the most incredible
cellular structure I've ever seen.
And you truly believe I'll fly this time?
Unreservedly.
- I trust you.
- I'm touched.
- I don't trust him.
- Say nothing.
I'm gonna die!
Look, we're not going to make you
do anything you don't feel...
Here, let me help.
Erik!
What?
You know you were thinking the same.
Wonderful work, Hank.
Thank you very much.
All right, Alex, I want you to hit the "X".
And try not to hit me.
There's a good chap.
- You're serious?
- I'm very serious.
I have complete and utter faith in you.
Am I still a bozo?
Yes, Hank, you're still a bozo.
But nice job.
See that?
Try turning it to face us.
You know, I believe that true focus lies
somewhere between rage and serenity.
Would you mind if I...
What did you just do to me?
I accessed the brightest corner
of your memory system.
It's a very beautiful memory, Erik.
Thank you.
I didn't know I still had that.
There is so much more
to you than you know.
Not just pain and anger.
There is good, too. I felt it.
When you can access all of that,
you'll possess a power no one can match.
Not even me.
So, come on. Try again.
- Hey!
- Well done.
The President is about to make his address.
It shall be the policy of this nation
to regard any nuclear missile
crossing the embargo line
that surrounds Cuba
as an attack by the Soviet Union
on the United States
requiring a full retaliatory
response upon the Soviet Union...
- That's where we're going to find Shaw.
- How do you know?
Two superpowers facing off and
he wants to start World War III.
He won't leave anything to chance.
So much for diplomacy.
I suggest you all get a good night's sleep.
...ultimately leads to war.
Tensions mount as the Soviet
missile ship nears Cuba.
All diplomatic efforts to avert
nuclear war have thus far failed.
As the American people ready themselves
for the likelihood of an atomic attack,
there are widespread
reports of panic-buying,
supermarkets cleared, as shelters
unused since the Second World War
are stocked for what may lie ahead.
In all its history, America has
never faced a greater threat.
The world is primed for war
and there's no one to stop me.
Come in.
Hey.
I have a surprise for you.
I isolated the right marker
in your DNA sample.
The serum works like an antibiotic,
attacking the cells that cause
our physical mutation.
It won't affect our abilities,
just our appearance.
Do you still want to do this?
Should we have to hide?
Well, you already do.
You're hiding right now,
like I have my whole life.
I don't want to feel like a freak
all the time. I just want to look...
- Normal.
- Yeah.
Hank, don't!
You're beautiful, Hank.
Everything you are, you are perfect.
Look at all of us. Look at all
we've achieved this week.
All we will achieve.
We are different.
But we shouldn't be trying
to fit into society.
Society should aspire to be more like us.
Mutant and proud.
It behooves me to tell you
that even if we save the world tomorrow,
and mutants are accepted into society,
my feet and your natural blue form
will never be deemed beautiful.
You look beautiful now.
We need this cure.
Cuba.
Russia, America.
It makes no difference.
Shaw has declared war
on mankind, on all of us.
He has to be stopped.
I'm not going to stop Shaw.
I'm going to kill him.
Do you have it in you to allow that?
You've known all along why
I was here, Charles.
But things have changed.
What started as a covert mission,
tomorrow, mankind will know
that mutants exist.
Shaw, us, they won't differentiate.
They'll fear us.
And that fear will turn to hatred.
Not if we stop a war.
Not if we can prevent Shaw.
Not if we risk our lives doing so.
- Would they do the same for us?
- We have it in us to be the better men.
We already are.
We're the next stage of human evolution.
- You said it yourself!
- No...
Are you really so naive
as to think that they won't
battle their own extinction?
- Or is it arrogance?
- I'm sorry?
After tomorrow,
they're going to turn on us.
But you're blind to it, because you
believe they're all like Moira.
And you believe they're all like Shaw.
Listen to me very carefully, my friend.
Killing Shaw will not bring you peace.
Peace was never an option.
No.
No, no. No.
Well,
this is a surprise.
The nice kind?
Get out, Raven.
I want to go to bed.
Maybe in a few years.
How about now?
I prefer the real Raven.
I said the real Raven.
Perfection.
Could you pass me my robe?
You don't have to hide.
Have you ever looked at a tiger
and thought you ought to cover it up?
No, but...
You're an exquisite creature, Raven.
All your life, the world
has tried to tame you.
It's time for you to be free.
You know, sometimes I wonder
what my life would have been like
if you hadn't found me here that night.
Sorry, what? You...
For God's sake, Raven!
Where are your clothes?
Put some clothes on.
That's not what you said
when you first saw me.
But I guess pets are always cuter
when they're little, right?
Raven, I don't know
what's gotten into you lately.
I thought you'd be in a good mood.
Hank, he tells me that he's found
the answer to your cosmetic problem.
Are you gonna tell me what's the matter
or do I have to read your mind?
You promised me you would never do that.
Until recently,
I never had to use my power to know
what you were thinking, Raven.
Charles, I used to think it was going
to be you and me against the world.
But no matter how bad the world gets,
you don't want to be against it, do you?
You want to be a part of it.
What the hell happened here?
Hank has been busy.
Do we really have to wear these?
As none of us mutated
to endure extreme g-force
or being riddled by bullets,
I suggest we suit up.
Where is Hank?
I'm here.
Hank?
It didn't attack the cells.
It enhanced them.
It didn't work.
Yes, it did, Hank. Don't you see?
This is who you were meant to be.
This is you.
No more hiding.
- You never looked better, man.
- Hank!
Don't mock me!
Hank, put him down immediately, please.
Hank! Hank!
I wasn't.
Even I got to admit you
look pretty badass.
I think I got a new name for you.
Beast.
You're sure you can fly this thing?
Of course I can. I designed it.
Status of the cargo ship.
Bearing 1 -8-0 at 12 knots.
Three minutes to the embargo line, sir.
God help them if they cross it.
God help us all.
- Sound general quarters.
- General quarters, general quarters!
- All hands, man battle stations!
- Aye, sir.
Set condition Zebra!
General quarters, battle stations.
Captain, we already have our orders.
Why so eager for new ones?
I lived through one war, comrade.
I'd prefer not to start another.
Battle stations! NOW!
Gun Boss, target cargo ship bearing 1 -8-0.
Fleet reports all weapons ready.
From the Kremlin, sir.
New orders. As of 1025 hours, the cargo
vessel Aral Sea is hereby ordered to...
...reverse course
and return to port in Odessa.
Aral Sea, come in.
They are not responding.
She's not turning around.
Aral Sea, you are ordered to turn around.
Do not cross the line.
Target ready to be fired upon, sir.
- Stand by to fire.
- Standing by, sir.
It looks pretty messy out there.
Aral Sea you are ordered to turn around.
The crew of the Aral Sea are all dead.
Shaw's been there.
He's still here, somewhere.
He set the ship on course
for the embargo line.
If that ship crosses the line,
our boys are going to blow it up.
And the war begins.
Unless they're not our boys.
USS Independence, this is Alexander Nevsky.
We have lost control of our cargo ship.
She has been instructed to stop.
Do not fire! Repeat, do not fire!
They have signaled the cargo
ship to turn around, sir.
It's a ruse. Pay no attention!
- Stand by to fire.
- Standing by to fire, sir.
On my count. Five,
four...
Hold on!
Nyet.
- What was that?
- The Russians.
They have fired on their own ship.
A little warning next time, Professor.
- Sorry about that. You all right?
- Yeah.
Son of a...
Give me CINCLANT on the horn.
I want a new set of orders.
Congratulations, comrade.
You just averted nuclear war!
What?
Take him to the brig.
What? What just happened?
They say the comrade lost his mind.
The Americans are applauding.
They're here. That telepath is powerful.
We're moving to a back-up plan.
That was inspired, Charles.
Thank you very much,
but I still can't locate Shaw.
He's down there. We need to find him now.
Hank?
Is there anything unusual
on the radar or scanners?
No. Nothing.
Well, then he must be underwater.
And obviously, we don't have sonar.
- Yes, we do.
They are ready for war.
We just need to strike another
match to light the fuse.
And we still have the most
powerful weapon of all.
Me.
Turn the nuclear reactor to 100% output
and make sure I'm not disturbed.
Hank, level the bloody plane!
Whoa! You back right off.
Beast, open the bomb bay doors!
Remember! This is a muscle.
You control it!
You'll be in here the entire time!
We'll see you soon!
On my mark! Three! Two!
One! Go!
Alert the fleet, they may
want to take their cans off.
Banshee has got a location on Shaw.
- Are you ready for this?
- Let's find out.
Remember, the point between rage
and serenity.
Erik, take my hand!
Hold on, guys. It's gonna get bumpy.
Moira? Moira, are you all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I read the teleporter's mind.
Shaw is drawing all the power
out of his sub.
He's turning himself into
some kind of nuclear bomb.
We got no time.
The Geiger count is going out of control.
Moira, this is what we're gonna do.
Get on the radio and tell them
to clear both fleets out immediately.
- I'm going in.
- Beast, Havok, back him up.
Erik, I can guide you through
once you're in,
but I need you to shut down
whatever it is that's blocking me,
then we just hope to God it's not
too late for me to stop him.
- Got it.
- Good luck!
- Raven, stop!
- I'm going to help them.
We don't have time for this.
If anything comes in that entrance,
- you're taking care of it, yes?
- Fine.
Beast!
If we go, you go!
We believe Shaw is trying
to detonate some kind of bomb.
Erik, make for the middle of the vessel.
That's the point my mind can't penetrate.
We have to assume
that that's where Shaw is.
Gangway! Gangway! Gangway!
That's the nuclear reactor. Disable it.
Stop! Don't move!
Get down!
Erik, you're there.
You've reached the void.
He's not here, Charles. Shaw's not here!
He's left the sub!
What? He's got to be there. He has to be!
There's nowhere else he can be.
Keep looking.
And I'm telling you he's not.
There's no one here, God damn it!
Erik.
What a pleasant surprise.
Erik? Erik.
So good to see you again.
May I ask you something?
Why are you on their side?
- He's gone.
- What?
He's gone into the void!
I can't communicate with him there.
Why fight for a doomed race
who will hunt us down
as soon as they realize their
reign is coming to an end?
Yeah! Yes!
I'm sorry for what happened in the camps.
I truly am.
He's back! Erik, whatever
you're doing, keep doing it.
It's starting to work.
But everything I did, I did for you.
To unlock your power,
to make you embrace it.
It's working!
I'm starting to see him,
but I can't yet touch his mind.
You've come a long way from bending gates.
I'm so proud of you.
And you're just starting
to scratch the surface.
Think how much further we could go
together.
Look out!
Stop! Azazel.
I don't want to hurt you, Erik. I never did.
I want to help you.
This is our time.
Our age.
We are the future of the human race.
You and me, son.
This world could be ours.
Everything you did made me stronger.
It made me the weapon I am today.
It's the truth.
I've known it all along.
You are my creator.
Now, Charles!
- Are you okay?
- Moira, be quiet.
I can only control this man for so long.
- Sorry, Charles.
- Erik, please.
- Be the better man.
- It's not that I don't trust you.
Erik, there will be no turning back!
No!
- Charles!
- Don't do this, Erik!
If you're in there,
I'd like you to know that I agree
with every word you said.
We are the future.
But,
unfortunately,
you killed my mother.
This is what we're going to do.
No. Please, Erik, no.
I'm going to count to three and
I'm going to move the coin.
One.
Please, Erik.
Two.
Three.
The Russians share our concerns
and will join a strike on all the mutants.
We can end this threat for good.
We'll never have another
opportunity like this.
We have an agent on that beach.
One agent.
She's a good agent.
She's collateral damage.
Today, our fighting stops!
Take off your blinders,
brothers and sisters.
The real enemy is out there.
I feel their guns moving in the water,
their metal targeting us.
Americans, Soviets,
humans.
United in their fear of the unknown.
The Neanderthal is running scared,
my fellow mutants!
Go ahead, Charles.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Fleet Commander, this is X-Ray Bravo 7-0.
Respond. Over.
The beach is secure. Call off the attack.
The beach is targeted
and ready to be fired upon, sir.
- Stand by.
- Standing by, sir.
New orders. Fire on the beach.
Hello?
Hello!
Fire!
Erik, you said yourself,
we're the better men.
This is the time to prove it.
There are thousands of men
on those ships.
Good, honest, innocent men!
They're just following orders.
I've been at the mercy of men
just following orders.
Never again.
Erik, release them!
No!
I don't want to hurt you. Don't make me!
Stand back!
Charles, that's enough!
Erik, stop!
Gentlemen, it's been an honor
serving with you.
Comrades, thank you for your service.
I'm so sorry.
I said back off!
You. You did this.
Erik. Please.
She didn't do this, Erik.
You did.
Us turning on each other,
it's what they want.
I tried to warn you, Charles.
I want you by my side.
We're brothers, you and I.
All of us together, protecting each other.
We want the same thing.
My friend.
I'm sorry, but we do not.
Charles! I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
It's all right. It's all right.
This society won't accept us.
We form our own.
The humans have played their hand.
Now we get ready to play ours.
Who's with me?
No more hiding.
You should go with him.
It's what you want.
You promised me you would
never read my mind.
I know.
I promised you a great
many things, I'm afraid.
I'm sorry.
Take care of him.
And, Beast, never forget.
Mutant and proud.
Help me out, come on.
I'm gonna get you to a hospital.
Wait, Charles.
Charles, don't move, okay?
I won't.
Actually...
I can't feel my legs.
- What?
- I can't feel my legs.
I can't feel my legs.
In this week of Thanksgiving
there is much for which we can be grateful
as we look back to where
we stood only four weeks ago.
The unity of this hemisphere,
the support of our allies
and the calm determination
of the American people.
These qualities may be tested
many more times in this decade.
So, how many students do
you think you'll have here
once you get the academy up and running?
As many as I can manage.
Possibly more.
You know,
one day the government is going to realize
how lucky they were to have
Professor X on their side.
I suppose I am
a real professor now, aren't I?
Next thing you know, I'll be going bald.
We're still on the government's side, Moira.
We're still G-men. Just without the "G".
No. You're your own team now.
It's better.
You're X-Men.
Yes, I like the sound of that.
Moira?
For us, anonymity will be
the first line of defense.
I know.
They can threaten me
all they want, Charles.
I'll never tell them where you are.
Ever.
I know you won't.
I know.
I remember the attack on HQ,
leaving to go somewhere else.
And then this morning,
I woke up at home.
That's it.
All that time, wiped clean from your mind.
Just gone.
He can do that?
You don't remember anything?
Sometimes I get fragments.
Like
trees,
sunlight.
- A kiss.
- Oh, Jesus.
Gentlemen, this is why the CIA
is no place for a woman.
What the hell was that?
I know we've had our differences.
Where's your telepath friend?
Gone.
Left a bit of a gap in my life,
if I'm to be honest.
I was rather hoping you would fill it.
Join us.
Erik, I believe.
I prefer
Magneto.